<akomaNtoso>
  <debate>
    <meta>
      <references>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Philip Epps" id="Philip Epps" showAs="Philip Epps">
        </TLCPerson>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <debateBody>
      <debateSection>
        <heading>2017-04-17 Philip Epps visit</heading>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Are we on record like the camera, or...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, no. I’ll just turn on the audio on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Audio.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You’ll get a transcript to edit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Oh cool. Thank you. Very nice. It’s my first time in this building. It’s pretty interesting.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I had to show you a photograph because I didn’t know your Chinese names. I showed you what could be your photograph. Oh yeah, you didn’t tell me that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m sorry.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You saw my email. I’m a producer. I’m also a wannabe technie, but not a programmer. I’ve done some PR and marketing for two companies in China and Hong Kong here. I’m not the millennial age that you normally see. Obviously, I’m 59. But I have a lot of ideas and I’ve been around a bit. I read a lot. I assimilate stuff.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>When I saw that you had gotten your position I thought...I hadn’t heard of you before but I was like, &quot;Oh, yeah. That’s the symbol of the new Taiwan or the global ethic that’s going on.&quot; Smart. Hacker. Transgender. Minister without portfolio.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I thought, &quot;What a great story.&quot; That was my first take on that. Then I thought, &quot;Well, I should present some of my ideas.&quot; So here we are, to make a long story short. How is your effort to make Taiwan transparent?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is Silicon Valley. That first thing is...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What is your priority?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...is saying that we are not making Taiwan an Asia Silicon Valley. One of my first moves was to redefine the Asian Silicon Valley plan into the Asia dot Silicon Valley plan, meaning that we’re connecting to the rest of Asia, and then we’re connecting to Silicon Valley, but we are not aiming to be the Silicon Valley of Asia.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There were some...there was a message aspect...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There was a lot of messages, especially during the campaign.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I know, but especially Silicon Island.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly right, which I think is all very silly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’d love to hear your take on it’s the connections rather than...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We have the ASVDA, which is our website. As you can see, it is Asia Silicon Valley. It’s not &quot;Asian&quot; Silicon Valley, meaning that we’re linking with Asia...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Or &quot;Asia’s,&quot; right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly, so it’s linking with Asia and linking with Silicon Valley.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>The links already exist, so what’s the challenge for you?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Two main challenges for the ASVDA. The first challenge is that there is a lot of IoT innovation going on in Taiwan for R&amp;D and everything, but it’s mostly centered around lower levels such as the sensors, such as the protocol level, the computational level, and...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Small devices and hardware.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly, but then for the business intelligences, for the analytics, for the application layer things, there is very little integration between the Taiwanese people making this kind of software versus the Taiwanese people doing the sensors and everything.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s normally a very disjointed ecosystem. We have the suppliers who supply to brands overseas, and we have some app people working on analytics...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>But there’s no real glue...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...all together.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There’s no real glue. There’s no glue to, and so that’s the first challenge.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Are you the glue?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not exactly. I’m mostly just pointing out directions. ASVDA is actually an independent agency, and we hire people who are seasoned veteran Silicon Valley people to be the C‑level people, because these...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>How is it going, the recruiting?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s all done. Yeah, linking Asia, connecting to Valley...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Aside from the visuals, what does it really mean on the ground?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>On the ground, it means there’s a technology officer to do the research environment thing. There’s the human resource, for lack of better term, officer, that does the IoT gluing, as we just said.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There’s a CFO that makes the investments, both on a national level, to the more promising sectors, and also linking Silicon Valley VCs for Taiwanese companies. It’s bi‑directional. There’s also the deregulation and policies to identify exactly what the regulations need to change in response to such startups and IoT people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Finally, there’s also a media marketing part, because as you can see, this is actually a very marketing Taiwan kind of move.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Right, because it’s an export economy...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is, so...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You’ve got to put a good face to the products, or...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. We hired these people already. I’m head of supervising committee. I just set an overall direction. It’s not mostly me, actually. Mostly it’s the minister of NDC, who is himself a minister without portfolio also, and then working with the economy and scientific knowledge administers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The CEO is his deputy minister, the deputy minister of NDC commission, who runs the day‑to‑day program. This is the structure. I mostly just set our direction.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What is NDC?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The National Development Council.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Are you a bureaucrat now? Is that sort of how you see yourself, just sort of shepherding the ideas, or are you more of an activist? I saw you, my first hit was you’re an activist.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I don’t see how this should be naturally exclusive.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There’s not a difference. No.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Mostly I see myself as a channel that takes the activist circles, ideas, collective intelligence, and whatever, and try to synthesize it and translate it somehow into bureaucratic language, and then also trying to reform the bureaucracy.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>So that people there also learn to internally collaborate and have this kind of organizational structure instead of the purely tree‑like structure. As you can see, this is very cross‑functional.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Right. I’m very interested in this part, the media and marketing, because you have to get the word out. I’m asking silly questions, but is that the public face to any kind of change or adaptation to of hardware to software, or global tech more?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s mostly that the two core elements. One, it’s not about moving from hardware to software. We have pretty strong hardware, pretty strong software. It’s just that they were not linked together. They were not glued together as a set.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The core message is about to create a comprehensive ecosystem and diversified aspects for services. It’s not about focusing more on software. It’s about getting software people to work with hardware people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The next part is a startup entrepreneurship ecosystem, which we need to increase our supply chain and related laws and regulations, and building an innovative environment. Then again, this is not about young people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This is about bridging the young people’s talents and entrepreneurship with the more seasoned industry veteran’s resources, and so on. This is intergenerational glue, but the force here at play is always on the gluing. It’s not on promoting any particular sector.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>How’s this site going? The first part of your briefing was this part, right? Now we’re...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Is this more challenging, or...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think so far, so good. We have an innovation and entrepreneurship plan going on, also managed by the NDC. I’m overseeing only one small part of it. It’s about social enterprises. That’s about companies whose solve social problems while doing their business.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Or you can see it as a social mission that happens to earn some money to be sustainable, or you can view it any which way. That’s my purview, but there’s other part as well. There’s the green energy, sustainable development part.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Which is one part of the entrepreneurship also, because of our changed electricity laws that promotes renewable resources. That will be Minister Wu’s work. It is not my work. There’s also many other plans around startup entrepreneurship, but I’m mostly about social enterprises.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Attracting young talent, Silicon Valley or globally?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s kind of what the end result is, the end product? You need that...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, and then the end product, like this week, we’re having this foreign talent act, which encourages people from all sort of diverse backgrounds.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Not just coders, but...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not just coders.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...people and...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, there’s an act for recruitment and employment form. Right, so you did.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s a streamlining that’s allowing people easy access to visas and things like that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right, and also having their spouses and children to easily enjoy health care here and so on. It’s about improving the overall life quality of foreign people and talent.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Because you know the digital nomad isn’t really looking for long‑term visas. They’re not really...It’s hard. I’ve looked at the entrepreneur visa for myself. I’m on a 90‑day entry visa, a landing visa.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It looks great until you get to the line that says, &quot;You need two million NC to show the bank,&quot; and that stops...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, that’s a big problem, but this is something else. This, you just need a local company to vouch for you or whatever.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Sponsor?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sponsor...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s the same thing as getting an ARC.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not exactly, but, yeah. I know there’s still some threshold going here, which is what we get from this public consultation. We’ve got a lot of foreign people saying that keeping to the APRC is too strict, or a minimum of 183 days per year in Taiwan is not encouraging, and so on. We...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s livable, but I think it’s the money you have to put up front, even if it’s just showing it at the bank for a couple of days. I think the young people are put off by that, a little bit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right. The Ministry of Labor, actually, adjusted this a lot in response to the public’s...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I know there’s a lot of change happening.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, lots of change happening. You can see, there’s a lot of, huge amount of feedback that we got here. The adjusted version will probably get to the executive meeting maybe this Thursday or next Thursday, and then we will have this public announcement.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, the legislation still has to pass it, but at least it will be for a wider circulation. So, yeah, that’s what...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>When is it going to be easier for someone? Basically, I’ve been doing a bit of research, and there’s a lot of this, global movement in young people. Not necessarily coders, but people who are doing online stuff, and they’re kind of flopping around.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They’re looking for travel and nice places to go, and friendly people. Taiwan offers that, obviously. I think they enjoy Asia, a lot of Americans, but also Europeans and such. It seems like there are some hot spots now. Bali is one.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Chiang Mai is another.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Thailand is attractive, because you get ‑‑ at least Americans ‑‑ you get a six‑month landing visa with no problem. They’re looking for what? Fast Internet, decent accommodation. They’re kind of making money on their own online.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s an issue. It’s like what if you’ve got online businesses ‑‑ several ‑‑ which I kind of do, and yet, you’re not really officially paying taxes if you’re on a visitor visa. You don’t want to do anything illegal. You like where you are. It’s obviously pretty alternative compared to the structure that this is set up.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you’re online company is targeting Taiwan or the vicinity as a primary user base...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Targeting the world. That’s what...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There’s a billion people online...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, so...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...e‑commerce...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>All we ask is to just pay this five percent tax, the VAT tax, which starts this May, I think.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s for purchasing, though. It’s not...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That does for purchasing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What if you’re actually making income?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You’re making an income...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yeah. It’s illegal.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Wait a second. You’re saying that you have a US business.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m saying there’s a whole population of young people out there, digital nomads, and this is a growing phenomena, which I know you are aware of that. They’re super smart, hungry, educated, and they’re doing all kinds of stuff, whether it’s online editing, online education, this, this, this, Web development, software, whatever.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They’ve got clients everywhere, and they’re always hustling for new clients. This is the new economic order, part of it anyway. It’s not the future of all of us, doing...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...but it’s significant, and if you want to bring young talent here...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If their bank is not in Taiwan, their customers are not in Taiwan, it just so happens they work from Taiwan, I don’t think our tax agency has anything to say...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I don’t know. You’re working in a place you don’t have official work status.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right, so it’s just a visitor. Basically, you’re on a vacation. That’s the working...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>But you’re still working.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I don’t know. I’m...OK.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s a working vacation, but...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’ll be interesting to see what they...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, but if you start working for a Taiwan company, then the line, you know...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What if you wanted to be established here? What if you wanted to stay longer‑term, or at least have some flexibility with that, and want health care and things like that? What if you wanted to pay into taxes? What if you wanted to be part of that system? It’s not that easy. You have to have that Taiwan...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s not. It’s not. You need to, exactly, but this is part of it, because if you qualify for a special professional, your so‑called go cart, then actually, it makes it much easier. We’re mostly talking about, it’s not quite O‑3 or O‑1 visa, like in US, which requires a much higher...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m not sure what that is, like H‑1B or something?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, no. A O‑1 or O‑3 is not quite Nobel prize level, but if there’s someone that’s very...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Oh, I see.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...respected.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...patents, or papers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, exactly. The special professional, our draft definition is that you’re in the top quarter of salaries, so professional, currently, in Taiwan, that is to say average of about this number NDD per month. If your previous job, not necessarily in Taiwan, pay you this much, then we actually want you here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Sure. That’s pretty standard. Most countries attract...Anybody who’s got that certain level...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...Nobel prize.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. But it’s not just the payment. You can also get...And this is what I mean by vouching. The Academia Sinica or the ITRI doesn’t have to hire you. They just have to write a recommendation letter that says you are this kind of professional, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Finally, if you work one part of the focal industry ‑‑ high tech, e‑commerce, green energy, technology management ‑‑ then it’s up to these ministries to recognize your contribution to that area, and then you also automatically qualify, even not meeting the salary definition.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think if you’re talking about digital nomads, then it’s mostly about the digital economy, which will be the purview of the Ministry of Economy Affairs to make such a recognition. If you fit the definition, then you automatically qualify for the special professional, not necessarily a professional worker. This is one part that will probably make your life easier.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m actually thinking about this global community, because you want to attract global talent, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I think there’s separation. The digital nomad is not the Silicon Valley professional, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They’re not software engineers, necessarily.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>But they work in the, broadly speaking, digital economy, which means their work transmits over online channels, basically. They produce digital goods.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yes, right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They’re welcome here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...commission...Right, so they will get, if this act gets passed, a three‑year stay, and with more or less the same benefits as a permanent...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You get health care, and you get...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. That’s the basic idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It sounds good.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think it’s a pretty good compromise.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>How will they know about this, though? They’re working in Chiang Mai, and they’re sort of bopping around. Obviously, they’re well‑read, and they’re online, and they’ve done a lot of stuff, but, &quot;Oh, let’s go to Taiwan.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>&quot;What’s the laws like?&quot; &quot;Oh, you can get your landing visa, the 90‑day landing visa.&quot; They may not ask the next question. &quot;Well, what if I...&quot; I guess that would...&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>&quot;...and I could be here for a while.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>One of the reason for circulating this online consultation is just to raise awareness of the expat communities and so on so that people know this is coming. We did see this circulating on Facebook and Twitter, and other parts, so it’s not as if there were a warrant, all right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The other thing is that once is sent to legislation, we imagine the ruling party, the DPP ‑‑ because that’s one of the DPP’s main presidential promises during the campaign. Their PR machine...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Kind of streamlined...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right. Their PR machine will make it very visible.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I see. As a producer, to me, you put together a visual, a media campaign or such, whether it’s a documentary or a commercial, things like that. I’m not sure if it’s just that bump up to the level of actually raising money for it and things like that, because the higher the quality, the higher the costs.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’ve estimated with my director one to three million for a 10‑minute documentary about this very subject.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>We think it could be very colorful, including surfing in Wi‑Ho, or all the other benefits of a cool place to stop.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That sounds good.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s in the works, so how would I apply for...I don’t think the government’s just going to hand over money of that kind to a project like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If it’s DPP’s PR team, then it’s actually not the administration’s business. It would be the party or the president’s office, perhaps.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>This is the idea, &quot;Taiwan Trending.&quot; Fast‑moving, music, skateboarding.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This sounds good.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What we’re saying is that we’re produced as policies, of laws, and so on. Most of the promotional work goes to the legislators, their parties, and sometimes the presidential office handles promotion.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Why is it sort of broken out like that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Because it’s their job to pass this act. Technically, we just produce a draft for the legislators to deliberate and to pass. Once they pass it, the credit goes to the legislator who countersigns or...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It was your idea, but they get the credit for it. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure. That’s our working relationship. In the US, administration can’t propose acts like this, but it has to be...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>No, they propose all the time, but they don’t...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They have to hand it to one of the assembly people, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, all the credit goes to the assembly people?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I guess...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s the same system here, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yeah, but if they’re president of the United States, it doesn’t really matter, right? They don’t need to extra credit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In any case.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yeah. I would like to let you take a look at that. There’s other information I’d like to talk about. One is...You saw this, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, sure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>This is so cool, that they’re opting out of Hong Kong, and the fact that a lot of Hong Kong people are immigrating here to get away from the oppression of the Mainland. I’m not anti‑China, but I think Taiwan is a special place for its tolerance and freedoms.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, I was just profiled on &quot;Time,&quot; that talks about rumors and whatever, but they also put a lot of...Yeah, this is a coverage...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Was this a new article?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is pretty new, April 7th. The Time person interviewed me, and then talk about things, and it has a lot of information related to the thing that we talk about. The other thing is that it also highlighted on Reporters Without Borders, because the freedom of speech is kind of the core value...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They’re under attack in Hong Kong, where there was supposed to be 50 years of freedom. It’s not. They’re lying.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>This is the imagery of this sort of startup. This is all familiar stuff to you. I just wanted to say Berlin, London. This is London and Silicon Valley. There’s so much activity out there, these hubs, and I don’t really see it happening here. I know...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We don’t have the highlights...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...startup stadium, but they’re sort of individual and separated.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s exactly right. Previously, we had a startup center in the Taiwan Air Force. Have you been there?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’ve only seen the sign.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s now being made into a more...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>TAF, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, the TAF. There’s plenty of very good visuals around the TAF.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What’s happening to it now?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s turning into a more culturally‑oriented kind of cultural park of sorts. We’re still looking for a highlights place just like this. We have several candidates. We don’t have a finalized destination yet.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>TAF is becoming more like a museum?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not exactly. The Ministry of Culture is designing so that it is still hip, and innovative in Taiwan, but it’s about the...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Showcasing, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly, showcasing Taiwanese films, Taiwanese products, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>But not purely the innovation sector?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s still innovation, but it’s mostly around so‑called cultural startups or cultural innovation.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>This is sort of the second half of my presentation, which is something you may or may not have heard about. It’s called Building 21. It was a pretty ramshackle office space that entrepreneurs could go in and move walls and do all kinds of experimentation in the ’50s. It’s been torn down now, but it’s on the MIT campus.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I had this idea of why don’t you or we start something like that, Building 21, and sort of emulate what they did at MIT. The whole idea is...I’ve seen that the ITrI has something in Hsinchu. There’s a very expensive big building, all this great architecture. I’m not sure what the name of that is...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>...but it’s gorgeous. It’s stunning. This is where people could go in and engage and even camp. It’s much more on the kind of grass‑roots level. Getting into the ITRI building, it just seems like there would be a wall of paperwork and red tape.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I think that that’s what is sort of like Steve Jobs’ garage, but before that. I like the story here. There was a lot of science and a lot of brains, and I know that there’s abandoned buildings in Taiwan that are just kind of sitting there.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I think the connection to the hub that I believe that Taiwan needs for that software, that digital nomads that land to hear about, word of mouth, to say, &quot;Oh, I think Taiwan is the place to go. It’s cool. There’s people there.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>&quot;There’s a lot of things to see and do. The food is great, and the government allows me to work on my stuff without any kind of threat of deportation and things like that.&quot; It doesn’t have to be in Taipei. It can be in Yilan, where I live, or outside, less expensive.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This is the thing you were talking about? That’s the Hsinchu site.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s incredible. It’s a billion US dollars, right, to build that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, and there is a corresponding center at Sunnyvale, so yeah. I’m aware of this plan, and they have pretty good Web copies for the communications they’re putting through and so on. This is mostly, I think, a minister of science technology’s work, even though the site is ITRI.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What your proposing is a much smaller thing?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s, I guess, the idea would be it’s a live‑work space. The graffiti is welcome. It’s alternative San Francisco kind of bohemia ethic. That’s going to scare people away, because, &quot;Oh no way. I don’t have my PhD or my...I’m not capable to do that.&quot; But something like this, if there was some PR, word of mouth...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>A little bit like Freemont before it got gentrified? There was this town, where...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You worked in Silicon Valley, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I know Freemont. It’s kind of near San Francisco.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right. It was like that, graffiti were coming and so on, and there would be people that set up home there, and then they all left it and so on, but then...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Kind of a squat, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, but like a gentrified, like really quickly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s Freemont, though, with the houses prices and...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, but the thing is that we see this happening in Taiwan all the time. If you don’t have a status of a heritage site, that prevents housing speculation. Any bustling center of graffiti very quickly get gentrified with skyrocketing housing prices and so on. This is...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Outside of Taipei?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Even outside of Taipei. You see that around the major cities. Of course, on a county, I think this is much better, because they don’t speculate as much in those corners.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>On the other hand, the transportation and the link to the PR tems that each of the mayors has is considerably smaller. They are still working very hard on that. I’m aware of that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Where would there be an attractive place...? There’s some mayors wanting that. They want to bring it in, but they’re against it. They want...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah. All the mayors want it, but they were informed by many different forces. There’s forces from, for example...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Mostly entrepreneurial, where they were trying to make money for themselves.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, but the entrepreneur sometimes become successful business people, and then they want something else. Adobe was like that. It’s hard to balance this. At administration here, what we’re trying to do is to empower all the local cities, and townships, and counties to decide for themselves what kind of culture, what kind of this kind of promotion they want.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It used to be that Taiwan allocates all the budgets from the administration to the local cities. The local cities don’t really have their own tax sources to build sustainable projects, so...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You need to offer incentives to...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. They are not aligned. They’re mostly aligned just to please the administration’s planners, and the KMD, of course, loved this, for obvious reasons.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We are working on a new law that will change the administration, local level political responsibility, the financial reform act. It’s very controversial.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Because you’re taking, sort of, national party power away?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Decentralizing...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Decentralizing everything and making it much more powerful to be a mayor, for accounting, which explains why it’s kind of unpopular for the past 10 years.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Personally, I think it makes a lot of sense. Anyway, it’s...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Thank you. That’s a big picture approach to that, but maybe there’s a mayor out there who sees the light, and that wouldn’t be so expecting a windfall, wouldn’t be so greedy to put it in and to be very frank. They would see the advantage of having digital nomads coming in...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, but then they won’t need us then.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They what?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They won’t need us then.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I need you. I need somebody to say, or even private sector counterparts, who could say, &quot;Yeah, we think Yi-Lan.&quot; Yi-Lan Science Park, what’s going on with that? Not to change the subject, but I live next door to it, and it’s vacant. It’s gorgeous.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s supposed to be software, but...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s the artifact of the previous generation financial division law.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Meaning science park kind of thing?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Meaning that, because the administration at the national level wants science parks, all the different candidates...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Hsinchu was so successful...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. All the counties and all the cities proposed science parks, so we get an overflowing number of science parks, and of course, some of them are vacant.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Some of them failed.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, I wouldn’t say it’s completely failed, but in any case, they never reached the Hsinchu heights. That’s correct. That’s the artifact because it was proposed, not because Yi-Lan really needs it, but because the administration at the time wants it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>The tunnel’s been opened. There’s weekend traffic coming in to Taipei. It’s changing on that level. Tourism and traffic.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There is plenty of tourism.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There aren’t any jobs necessarily. It’s actually impoverished. It’s kind of weird. It’s like this island by itself.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, and the tourists, after the tourists go home, there’s no local industry left.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>When I first sent my link ‑‑ I don’t know if you saw it, but I had a link, Taiwan software development company concept to do VR, film stubs to bring my two worlds together. I haven’t really been able to get any...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There’s interest, but there is nobody saying, &quot;Yeah, we’ll help you develop, get some venture capital,&quot; or something like that. I’m a little bit stuck on that. I don’t know if you have any advice for me.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You’ve got a local company set up?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Not yet, because I don’t really have the funds yet.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I see.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m willing to do it myself, but I think it’s much more collaborative to do it with private sector.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Most of the investment funds from the National Development Council targets local startups.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You mean Taiwanese startups?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Taiwanese startups, exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What if I don’t have a Taiwanese partner?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Then that works. You can apply for one of the SBIR or something plans. That would help to further your goals. There’s some red tape involved. I’m not saying it’s completely...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>More than some, probably. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. I’m aware of this issue. We’re simplifying it. It’s not like we’re doing nothing. I understand it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I didn’t mean to imply you’re not doing anything. It takes time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s not just time. It’s also getting the current Korea public servants to shift from a subsidizing or reimbursing mentality to a collaboration or investment, angel‑level mentality. These two are actually very different.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, we set...We had our previous batch. It’s all reimbursement and subsidy. Now we’re switching to the second batch, and it’s zero dollars subsidy and reimbursement, all investment. You can take much more risk, and then you don’t have to do a lot of red tape and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Big change.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is a big change. Then we have to get Korea public servants on board for that to happen. There won’t be as much red tape happening, but you do need to fit into one of the so‑called investors themes for the NDC. All the relevant information is online.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There’s also a comparable sized fund for social enterprises, which is the one that I’m more familiar with. There’s less people applying though, because so‑called social enterprises is currently ‑‑ actually, a large part of it ‑‑ is done by MPOs and by people who are not companies, and therefore it doesn’t really want investments.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They really do want subsidies. We’re still balancing that. If you’re just doing entrepreneurship stuff, then the first fund that I mentioned has recently shifted to be investment.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>For Taiwanese only?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For Taiwanese only, I’m sorry.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What about private sector?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What about private sector?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Because that doesn’t have anything to do...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>My connection to the private sector is to the Silicon Valley private sector. It’s not to the Taiwan private sector.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s what you’re aiming, is to bring a bit of that cake here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure. Of course, you can talk with ASVDA. This is one of the possibilities. They do have this...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>That’s you, right? You’re advising.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, we’re at arm’s length. I do strategy. High‑level strategies are done. We review every three months or something, but the day‑to‑day operation is entirely in the hands of the C‑suite. That’s the CEO and the commission, and also the C‑suite people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We don’t actually interfere in any way with the very independently operating ASVDA agency, we just review its results quarterly or so.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Can you recommend? Can you suggest? Can you say, &quot;Hey, talk to this guy. Have a meeting with him.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m sure that they already have a telephone line or an email. Of course, you’re free to CC me or whatever. The other issue is, of course, we will have a public transcript. After you confirm with them, you can have a URL of your discussion with me, and then send as an attachment or something.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Sweet. What’s working the best in your mind, of the record? I know we’re on the record, but what’s really happening? I’m acting like a journalist now, but what’s the sweet spot?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In what?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>In all your activities now. Where you see the most progress.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In my activities?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There are challenges. You’ve got legacy government bureaucracy, red tape, etc., laws.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s fine. It’s all like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>The world is changing so fast, and Taiwan’s kind of behind the curve, isn’t it?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Depending on which curve you’re looking at.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What if you compare Berlin, compare London, compare Seattle.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, but you mention cities. Taiwan’s not really a city.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>For Asia.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The thing is that Berlin is Berlin. Everywhere around Berlin, the counties and so on, they’re not moving as fast as Berlin. What we’re seeing is the first tier of super‑connected super‑cities that are, as you said, moving very fast, and also free economic zones. The one in, for example, in Korea, is moving very fast, but kind of leaving its vicinities behind.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Would that be something possible to have here, where you could have the digital nomad land, and get to work?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You mean a free economic zone?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The previous administration tried that idea. It got shut down by the general populace, so no.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Why, though?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Why, though? Because the young people here, they want a free economic zone that could at the same time solve the inequality problem. That is to say social enterprise oriented.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>In salaries...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In salaries, social housing, everything. They don’t want something that would enable just one percent of the young populace who has the good English.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You mean the digital side?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The digital elite, basically.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You have to start somewhere, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s a left/right decision. In any case, I’m not taking sides for socialist or capitalists. I’m anarchist, by the way. My political agenda is just to get the civil society and the private sector to do as much work that currently the public sector is doing as possible, until there comes a day where we don’t need governments anymore. That’s my agenda.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>On the issue of left and right, I don’t really have a position.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m just talking about a new economic, capitalistic world, which is changing. It’s much more digital. I feel education is the answer to the young people who aren’t digitally inclined, or who don’t speak English.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Which part of the ASVDA plan aims to have this virtual academy and a very fast Internet connectivity, which by the way, Taiwan is in the top spot too, in the world for those last‑mile broadband readiness.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In theory, we can get all the people in all counties everywhere to use VR to study IoT, to study all kinds of hands‑on curriculum, and then become empowered. We’re doing that as well. That is much more welcome than an economic zone part of...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>The whole island would be one big economic zone.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s the idea, including remote islands.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You won’t be separating anybody.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>When do you think that utopia will happen. I’m an anarchist too.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s good. We’re proposing a special budget plan just for furthering that because our regular budget is multiyear. They don’t really contain sufficient funds for working toward that direction.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What is that like, five‑year plan or something?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s a four‑year plan for the digital part, but the total plan is 880 billions NT dollars. It’s some amount of money. You can locate the whole plan ‑‑ at infrastructure.ey.gov.tw. There’s this huge amount of pages and PDF files, but it’s in Chinese.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>In Chinese, yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Thank you, yes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>[laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think automatic translation would probably work pretty well for things like these, in any case. The digital part is just one part of it. There’s five parts in this special budget plan. We just sent it out to the legislation last week.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If they do approve it, we do hope to get this done in the next four years, which is about my term, anyway. If we don’t get this special budget, then we have to work with regular budgets, eight years at least, to do more or less the same thing. We see a special budget as a booster.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What are your plans after four years?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I don’t know.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You’re going to run politically or do anything?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m doing the same thing, whether as a digital minister or not. I’ll probably still do open government work and stuff, but whatever title, I don’t really care.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Thank you for your time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s a pleasure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m definitely going to be checking your site out. One comment on English here. There’s a simple, fairly inexpensive thing that Hong Kong did, basically because of their history and culture with the British.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They committed funds to have every government document and every transaction, everything, perfectly translated.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m aware of that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Right now, you get on the Chinese side, and there’s pages and pages online, and then there’s the sentence...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In our own website, PDIS.tw, we have a English website. We don’t have anything else. This is our team’s website. It’s completely in English. For the Chinese‑speaking people, we have Google Translate to translate it to Chinese, and leave it at that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Machine translation is actually getting...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Getting better.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...really, really good, especially for the Chinese‑English pair, so that we can get away with this.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>[laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re pretty unusual in that. For many other governmental websites, as you said, it’s like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You go English first.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you go Chinese first, what I’m saying is that machine translation is at a point where you can get OK English, it just don’t feel as good. We’ll continue making our website as planned and then see if other agencies start to catch up.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Is there any way that you can suggest as a minister to the legislature to say we’re going to make this legal binding thing, where we have a team of translators going 24/7 making sure every government within the whole world sees Taiwan? Right now, the world sees this much Taiwan. I’m all about imaging and messaging.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think it will need a lot of machine learning AI work. I do believe in getting better AI translators as a professional translator myself.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>This is an old‑school advocacy. When you face Singapore and Taiwan, Singapore and Hong Kong, and you get that perfectly official translation, legally accountable, it’s not the same thing as they got right now.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, it’s about three percent different. We’re working on that, but it’s getting really close. That’s because of a few breakthroughs that happened just a couple of months ago. We’re getting on that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The whole idea is of course you have to have professional proofreaders who are preferably native speakers, instead of just Taiwanese people who learn English. The professional proofreader is one thing. It’s another thing to have a good enough translation AI that could magically make all the websites.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re partnering with some private sector people to do that. That will be one of my priorities this year, is to automate the hell out of those manual stuff. I am working on that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Incredible. Good stuff. When can I see my transcript?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Like, I don’t know, 24 hours depending on how fast the AI works.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Great. [laughs] You think that the AI is still the answer, is the future answer?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s the first pass. It saves repetitive work.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You want to keep this?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure. Of course, we’ll still need humans to proofread it, in which case you are to proofread it for your own use. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s still a slight difference, even if it’s only three percent accuracy level, it’s not the official government...It’s not what Hong Kong does.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I know.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m an advocate for Taiwan. I think that’s something that...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The thing is that if we solve this through AI...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It wouldn’t cost that much money, though.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...we also solve that for...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You’re 80 percent there, but then you have to...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We also solve that for Philippines, Tagalog, and the other southbound languages. The whole idea is to make the government websites multilingual so that no matter which language you are, you see it in your native language.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>English is one way of doing this, but in our southbound strategy, many of our trading partners actually prefer their local language over English for many of trade related things. We do have to take that into consideration also.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>English being the lingua franca of the whole world so that...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For science and technology, of course.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I’m a little biased.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For business, we do a lot of business with the French office in Taiwan, and by necessity, we use English for a lot of documents, but they always prefer if we have French versions and so on. This is a political, it’s not a technical issue. We’ll do what we can do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Is it political? It seems a little bit like that is just an issue of about finance that it would have to be included in the budget. Here is the situation that I see today. You’re very optimistic, and I love your progressive view on things, but right now, there’s two kinds of businesses in Taipei.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>There’s local, and then there is something called international, which is where they still speak Chinese in the office, and yet a lot of business is done in English. There’s meetings, and news coming in.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>It’s totally not on the level of where I’ve worked in Singapore and in Hong Kong, where people were having small talk and such in English. We’re just not there yet.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think the machine translation’s pretty good now, seriously. We’re not Hong Kong or Singapore, that’s for sure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Not that you want to be, but that’s the one thing I think in Asia...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>At some point, the previous administration wanted to be.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Was it too expensive?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There are mayors who still look up to Singapore to say that this is the destination where we’re going to. After Sunflower Movement, 2014, I think the general populace just said, &quot;You know, it’s better to have equality first.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I was just talking about English.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I know, but equality among diverse linguistic groups, so that they would now insist not just we translate into Philippines or French, but also to Hakka, and Hoklo, and other Han ethnic groups in Taiwan. They’re language too.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>The script is always Chinese to Chinese.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it’s the Han script, but the words are different. It’s not entirely legible, and that’s not mentioning the aboriginal languages, of which there are many. We’re also working on machine translation for them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The point, when I talk about equality, it not just about economic equality, but cultural equality as well. There’s a fundamental difference in this particular cabinet of the attitudes around...The economic development is of course they’re very important, but it’s second place to fairness and cultural diversity.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>What? Really?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>People are hurting.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I know, but you see that in the campaign. The KMT was putting this economy first.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>They failed miserably. It was all about relations with China. That’s why they...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you see the economic development as the first priority goal, and China being this huge, growing market, of course you will want to find other trade agreements with China. It’s reasonable choice in any case.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I wasn’t trying to pick a fight. I agree with you. I just think that the Kuomintang was wrong into saying only relations with China was going to make the economy better here. Obviously, they failed.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They’re also developing ties with US and with many other countries. I think it’s mostly the economy first strategy and message in a sense that causes this tremendous election result, because this administration was elected on the principle of fairness and diversity.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>When we do economic development, we have a lot more things to consider, is what I’m saying. It’s not saying this is not important.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>OK, thank you for clarifying. Also, environmental concerns, so to speak. It’s pretty complicated.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah. Also, diversity with the ecosystem, and sustainability, and climate change, and everything.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>You have a lot of work to do. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, it’s interesting.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>I sure appreciate your time. I’ve learned a lot. Thank you so much, and I look forward to our transcript. I’ll definitely be looking at some of the websites you showed.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>OK.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Cheers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Philip Epps">
          <p>Bye‑bye.</p>
        </speech>
      </debateSection>
    </debateBody>
  </debate>
</akomaNtoso>