<akomaNtoso>
  <debate>
    <meta>
      <references>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Chung-Sheng Ko" id="Chung-Sheng Ko" showAs="Chung-Sheng Ko">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Clement Chen" id="Clement Chen" showAs="Clement Chen">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Dan Lejerskar" id="Dan Lejerskar" showAs="Dan Lejerskar">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/David Hall" id="David Hall" showAs="David Hall">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Fion Liao" id="Fion Liao" showAs="Fion Liao">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Narrator" id="Narrator" showAs="Narrator">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Pontus Appelqvist" id="Pontus Appelqvist" showAs="Pontus Appelqvist">
        </TLCPerson>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <debateBody>
      <debateSection>
        <heading>2017-08-31 EON Reality visit</heading>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I’ve been told that you’re very smart, and you understand things very easy, [laughs] so it’s going to be a pleasure to present...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>How can I help? Oh, yeah. We’ll be recording this. We’ll make a transcript, and we’ll send it to you for editing for 10 days before publishing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>OK.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Great.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I heard that you are very transparent.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Radically, actually.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Radically transparent.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>[laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I come from Sweden, and I don’t know if you’re probably familiar that Sweden has...It was very transparent. We have a personal number. All records are open. I don’t mind that. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Awesome.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Why are we here? To be honest, to get a little bit of advice. We have an idea of investing in Taiwan modeled after what we done in 30 other countries around the world. I understand that you are heading the digital aspects.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Or advising, but yes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s why we’d like to get some advice, because you’re familiar with how things work in California, or US. I understand that you have background there, and you’re also very familiar with Taiwan. What I’d like to do is, in interest of your time, to spend no more than 15 to 20 minutes quickly, to give you...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s fine. I don’t have anything else afterwards. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>15, 20 minutes to give you an orientation, and then to get your thoughts about this.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Without further ado, if you don’t mind, I’ll get started. Just a quick introduction, so you know who’s around the table.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Pontus Appelqvist">
          <p>I’m based in Singapore. I’m heading up our Asia market development, from Sweden originally, also, so it’s good to hear your colleague’s experience in Copenhagen.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Denmark, Sweden. We have the Scandinavian side here.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s great.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>That’s me.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Clement Chen">
          <p>I’m Clement Chen from USBCT, with David.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Fion Liao">
          <p>Fion Liao. Good to meet you again.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Nice meeting you again.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Chung-Sheng Ko">
          <p>Chung-Sheng Ko. I’m also the local partner with David.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>I’m David, USBCT. Good to see you again.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Very good to see you again.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>I hope you remember me.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Is that light OK for you, or would you like us to dim a little bit? Is that comfortable?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s fine for me.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Very quickly, about EON. We are essentially a company that we work in virtual reality for many years, and we focused on augmented and virtual reality for knowledge transfer.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We are a mission-driven company. I come from a country where I get my two master’s and almost my PhD. I didn’t ever took my PhD, but if I would, it would have been free also.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I believe that knowledge should be made available, accessible, and affordable. In fact, knowledge is a human right. This is a little bit of our purpose as a company.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We see there’s a big problem today -- I’m sure the most is familiar with this -- is there’s a reason we look at jobs and how jobs are created. I would summarize it in four elements. One has to do with education -- US have a little bit of a broken education -- longer life and mostly, globalization. Those things impact jobs.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The one job killer, the biggest job killer at the moment is technology disruption. Paradoxically, it’s technology disruption that also creates the new jobs. You can say lights go out here. Lights come up there. Unfortunately, not as many as they kill.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>It’s a little bit like lamps blinking. The problem is that this pace of change is accelerating. The current ways we have to transfer knowledge is not fast enough to cope with this change.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We see it manifesting itself in many ways. One is in the knowledge race. You have to teach more with less -- less time, less money. Knowledge is almost doubling every year versus every 25 years, 50 years ago. That’s one problem.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Plus, you have growing gap. How do you teach more with less time and less money? You also have a growing gap with jobs. These are smart jobs in US. You can see how the three and a half million new smart jobs, two million remain unfilled. Again, the gap is growing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We have a question that’s how do we fill these growing gaps? It’s a bit like &quot;Matrix&quot;. You have the positive and a green pill and the red pill. A positive scenario and a negative scenario. I believe in a positive scenario.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Let’s start with the negative first. The negative scenario would be to use more automation. Something like this. You have more and more humans that are displaced for more jobs. You’re increasing a society where a big portion of it are not employed. Perhaps not employable.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>In rich countries like US or Sweden, we have to worry what we do with these people. Many suggest a universal basic income. As you know, a job is more than a salary. It’s also a purpose, dignity, family. Personally, I don’t think that’s a good idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You don’t think social media is a dignified purpose within life?</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>No. You can do art. You can do anything. This reminds me a little bit of Matrix. The only think I’m missing is the fluids where you get your body, and you get your injections.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Perhaps we’re getting there. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s a possibility, right? I believe in something different. I believe in what I referred to as human 2.0. In fact, I’m not the only crazy person. 30 other governments have joined us, so far, around the world. Those are pretty important governments.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What is this all about? Metaphorically speaking, instead of being crushed by this AI tsunami, we can surf it. We can allow humans to live in a symbiotic relation with machine. We can take advantage of the machine, and we can empower humans to grow beyond their current human constraints.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s the theory of this. We think that the potential is to empower quite a lot of people. This is not a small thing. It’s 3.8 billion, to be precise.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Everybody.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>More or less everybody.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>[laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Why do I believe this will work? I’m a history buff. I like archaeology and history. If you look at what we’ve done the last 70,000 years, since we left Africa, and how humans are, we are curious.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I used to be a kid, put my finger in mud, and taste it. &quot;Oh, now I know how mud taste. It’s not chocolate.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We have that curiosity and thirst for knowledge. We are greedy also. Those two combination convince me that a big company, if some company in Taiwan can get a gentleman from Angola and make $300, and we can give him some way to empower him making like a Frankfurt worker that makes $65,000 euro, he will do it, because it’s financially viable.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s all theoretical, but let’s put it in practice. How do we do it? Today you may have...not you, you special person.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Let’s say normal person, like me, may have 40 percent of my cortex residing into this device. The problem is...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What is this?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>This is just a phone.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s a phone?</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Just a phone. Nothing special, but a lot of information that you have resides here, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The problem is that you are interacting with this device at the speed of thumb. It’s very slow. It’s like AOL back in the ’90s.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The question is how can we shorten the distance of the communication to device. Neural lace, 30, 50 years, that’s my bet. Elon Musk, I love him, but by the time he’s getting fixed machines, more or less, have taken a big chunk of what we’re supposed to do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I think the solution today is to use things like augmented virtual reality, today, fueled by artificial intelligence, IoT, big data, and so on. That’s our theory. Now how do you do that practically?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>There’s three components to this. One component has to do with the ability to, for example...I’ve been in this business for 26 years. I used to do aircraft simulator, and then became nuclear power plant simulators, that then became, now, simulators on the phone.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Here, this is the most banal example I can use. This is training someone how to replace a Frymaster at McDonald’s. I couldn’t find a more simple example.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>There’s 36,00 restaurant. You have two people in two different locations. A more simple example is this. This is a company called Aranco. They’re a pretty big company.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>This used to be, at one point, $1.8 million simulator. We’ll start it. This is for your benefit. The volume is on. It’ll come on in a second. It’s gaze controlled.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(background sounds)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I start the engine now. I have that on. All the functionalities of the physical environment works. I’m sure the Minister wants to try it?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>If you look left and right, actually move your head around.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I have to move my head?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You have to move your head.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not my eyeballs?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Well then it’s not really gaze-controlled.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>It’s like you are in reality. Look up. Look down. You are in that room, basically. It’s that instead of using a headset, or Vive...by the way, we do use HTC Vive and 32 other systems. Then the other one.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Pontus Appelqvist">
          <p>Which one?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Some type of AR environment. That’s what you saw there -- if you have the card -- that is a virtual reality environment, in a very simplistic way. You can also seamlessly do...sorry.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>She has seen the cardiac ECG already, last this time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Yeah, we’ll show that in a second.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>We looked at that last time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You saw that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>Yeah, cardiac ECG.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>No, I’ll show something more simple. This is the whole new car. I want the old car.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Pontus Appelqvist">
          <p>I don’t have that car here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>[laughs] You don’t have it? It’s in my bag. It’s in my bag, there.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s OK.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>No worries, we got it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We got a demo last time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You got a demo last time, so I’m not going to bore you with that. This is virtual training. You train in a facility on this, and then you take the snackable content with you at home, and recap it, but this is not going to solve the problem, the problem I was talking about.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The real problem there is how do you take knowledge injections when you need it, as you need it, in the context you need it? Let’s say you’re going to do, today, a step-by-step repair operation for an AR device.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s when we came up with this knowledge injection. Knowledge injection is all about, for example, Exxon...</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(background music)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>...BP are using this type of environment.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Environmental annotations.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Where you get guided solutions, where you can put the knowledge injection associated with a component, and then you can do different operations.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>This is not science fiction. I was just recording. This is an anchor point, creating a physical environment, and then not only provide you with the instructions, but actually showing which buttons to push and doing quality assurance that you’ve done, validating what you’ve done.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That becomes, now, suddenly, a little bit more powerful, because now you can connect this with AI, connect this with IoT.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then there’s a problem, still, that normal teachers in Taiwan, and anywhere in the world, 98 percent of them will never program a curriculum. Most of them, 90 percent, maybe more in Taiwan, knows how to use PowerPoint. [laughs] That’s the upper level.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What we did is to say how do we take that know-how, their single matter expertise -- they may be expert in biology, or chemistry, or whatever -- and allow them to create this content themselves?</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(background music)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s why we created something called Creator AVR. The idea is to take what we do 80 percent of the time, in terms of interaction creation.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Once we get the models in -- it can import from 120 formats, 55 native CAD -- we can then create the interaction on the spot, in a way that normal people can learn from it. In a second you’ll see.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s the expert. If you look at that device, of course you can switch between AR/VR seamlessly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Pontus Appelqvist">
          <p>This is your phone.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Thank you. You can switch for that. What you see there is the interaction environment. I know that one of your colleagues in Denmark has been dong interaction design.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We look at templates. What is it normally you do? You dissect. You identify. You can build all these environments, and then publish them seamlessly from a phone, all the way to high-end headsets, so 32 different publishing formats.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You could also use this virtual trainer. In this case we use 32 different devices, from HTC to Oculus. We are totally agnostic in this regard.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>HoloLens?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>HoloLens, of course. You’ll see the next example is HoloLens, because we use that for AR Assist.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We also built the world’s largest library for learning, because we have centers around the world, and all centers have a factory. That’s AR Assist. That’s, by the way, HoloLens, so the gentleman there is wearing a HoloLens.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>This is a typical knowledge injection. You have a robot, a man that works in symbiosis with the machine. The green arrows are generated automatically.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Once you create the VR experience, you can actually translate it to AR. You can kill two birds with one stone. We don’t see a big difference between one or the other.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Now you get the step-by-step instructions what to do, and you’ll get your quality assurance report by the time you’re done.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Why 3.8 billion people? Today, of the three billion workers that exist, there’s two and a half billion that don’t have any type of ICT in their daily work. It’s a huge opportunity. Now, with a billion of these devices, suddenly it’s possible to do it at the cost efficient rate. There’s about 1.3 billion students today that need fast knowledge.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We’ve been around for 18 years. I sometimes joke about it. I couldn’t go for vacation for the first 10 years. It’s all in the last four, five years that this is taking off. What we learned during the first 10 years is where’s the value. We started with 29 segments. We’re now down to six, where we know we have an enormous value versus the others.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then we developed the platform, then we created the global network. Now we have more than 42 million viewers. What’s the value for industry? Money. Service technician training, we took them from classical training to augmented reality.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>This is a mining equipment company. They successfully reduced the cost 92 percent, operator training 63 percent. When I started with university, originally it was the Carnegie Mellon, Cornell University. All these fancy, very expensive universities.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>With time, as the price lowered, we went to second-tier and vocational training, and now we’re down to K-12. Cheaper, better, faster equipment expand the usage.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What’s the value proposition? People learn faster, remember longer, made better decision, attention level goes up. You know all this. We also worked with governments. Why governments? Smart governments, like Singapore, or everywhere in the world, start to realize the value.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>One single example. This is an example of an ophthalmology application that’s currently used by hospitals and universities, everyone from Yale to Stanford. It does everything you would expect -- you can dissect the eye. You can look in the eye -- but it does something you may not have expected, which is injecting various dysfunctions.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You can change inject cranial nervous function. Then you have to analyze the patient, and the patient will behave as they had that pathology. The books, whether it costing some dollars, our application costs $20. It’s a cheap way to do it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The idea is you create that content once, then publish many times. You can have it in a room-sized environment. You can have it in desktop environment. You can have it on a phone, obviously. Create it once. Use it many times. Agnostic.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The workers -- let’s say, I know Taiwan used to very big on semiconductors, this is very big -- are using this knowledge injection to actually get the step-by-step instructions what to do. That’s how it...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Why is it blooming now? Why did it take so long time? You can argue many reasons, but one reason is that the hardware wasn’t affordable until recently.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Where’s the market? According to Goldman Sachs 85 percent comes from non-gaming sources, so education, health. According to Gartner, by 2020, 36 months from now, half of the top 50,000 companies would have implemented projects. By 2019, there will be a switch between consumer, today’s bigger usage. It will be the other way around.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Most people -- this you’re probably familiar with -- think about the top of the iceberg. They see the gadgets. That’s not so important. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>To do real implementation you have to be able to take existing data. You have to be able to support a lot of different systems. You have to be able to be compliant with all the new image recognition solutions and, at the same time, support various engines and be complaint with various AI, IoT devices. That’s what we’re doing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You have the layer with the product. You have the platform that agnostically supports all these things. You have the system that you have the freedom to choose, and different systems for different type of application or budget, then you put your application on top. That’s how we do it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Where is this going? I’m not going to take time with that today. In essence, we think we can go from 20-second bandwidth to, perhaps, two to three seconds over the next...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>It’s easy to predict three years. It’s difficult to predict 10 years. It’s impossible to predict more than that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We can create the future. We don’t have to predict it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Exactly, I love that. [laughs] That’s what we do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Why am I here in Taiwan? As we speak, there’s 136 cities that are visited by our troops from different locations. I happened to join the Asia team, because I think Asia is the future.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We are here because we want to co-invest in a center. The center consists of four elements. The most important element is to disseminate this into a country, reaching million of people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>To do that we have a center. This happens to be in France. This one is about 15,000 square feet to 20,000 square feet. It has about 28 trucks of equipment, in terms of various ways to publish that industry and education publishes today, all seamlessly adapted, from room-sized to pocket size.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s one element. The second element of this is the factory. That’s where the intellectual property encapsulation is happening.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s where, in this case, French students that we have trained become part-employed, in this environment, and develop French content for French people. Same thing in China. Chinese people, Chinese people, and so on. That’s the second element.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The factory, I have a 30-second video.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(video starts)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Narrator">
          <p>IDC’s addressing the VR and AR content by providing training for new content creators and building an app and content factory that acts as a regional distribution hub. EON Reality co-invests in IDCs with local governments and academic institutions around the world.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Narrator">
          <p>This investment includes a state of the art virtual reality and augmented reality center, content capacity building school, job creation, a sustainable revenue model, the world’s largest VR and AR library, a global distribution network, training curriculum, and more.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(video stops)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>To do this, where do we recruit the students? We start with a school, and typically the school has 100 students. In China, we started with 200.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What we do is four months theory. We train them on all aspects of virtual reality, and then eight months of project base learning. During that learning phase, they actually do real projects.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The best ones that want to work for us, we’d love to hire them. The ones that won’t work for us, they can work with the industry.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Last, but very important, is the sustainability aspect. All the centers are sustainable and a growth engine. 30 sites so far. Another 70 are on the way.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>How are the centers sustainable? Our philosophy is Human 2.0. Our delivery mechanism is the AVR platform. The vehicle to actually get it everywhere, boots on the ground, is the IDCs.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>With that we can focus on the key segments. Our key segments, number one is education. Energy, aerospace, medical, manufacturing, security. There’s another six that are secondary, but those are where the value is best.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>How does this work financially? When we said, for example, in Ethiopia we have a big...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Someone asked me, &quot;But Taiwan is a little bit behind. Will it be possible to do it?&quot; I said, &quot;If I’ve done it in South Africa, Ethiopia, and some places like that, I think we can do it in Taiwan.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Really?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I think so.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I’m joking.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It would be challenging.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Let me tell you, and you tell me why not. I’m happy to.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What we do is a worker, we have this platform. It costs, in US, $41 per month to take advantage of the platform. That’s your knowledge -- the pill.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Make money on that, we make money on the systems, and we make some money on the applications. Applications are owned locally, and so on. We have a hub, and then we do satellites in various cities, and then we get it out to the local environment.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>On the student side we charge $12 US, but in Ethiopia, for the same platform, we charge 27 cents. It’s not necessarily because we are egalitarian, which we are.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The idea is that there we need a contract with seven million students. They have a big population. They want to take the economy from $75 billion to $250 billion, and they have identified which barrier they want to address to make this leap. Very smart government, but the way.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I’ll skip a few slides. This is interesting. Here we’re working in France with Union of Metallurgical Industries, and they train 130,000 people per year. We started with a small pilot, and now we’re doing big rollouts.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>National rollouts, education, also France. I took that as an example. Then Minister of Economy Macron, now President supporting this. The pilot went very, very successfully. Now we’re rolling out.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I’ll skip a few. This is, by the way, our office in China, pretty big office. 3,000 square meters, main office. Ethiopia, that’s the Minister of Education. We signed an agreement to rollout. Romania, Mexico, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The model, in essence, is that we start with very few pilots with maybe 300 workers, and then we expand. We start with small education institution, and we have the KPIs, and we expand.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What do we need to make it happen? One, we need the physical space. We rent, normally, space. We pay for it. We don’t expect anything for free.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We put a showroom with the 20 trucks of equipment. We bring teachers from Silicon Valley and VR experts, the best ones, for five years to live in the country, transfer all the secrets, all the information to the teachers in Taiwan and the students.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We put the entrepreneurial school. We try to recruit 100 students. Normally not a problem. Then we put the platforms and five years’ maintenance, support, and upgrades. Then, once we’ve done that, it’s very simple. We inaugurate the center. We put the whole thing together.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I just completed an operation in Norway. We had the Prime Minister, all the top ministers, and then we had the CEOs of the top six industries. The CEO of biggest offshore company, the biggest shipping company, fishery, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We tried to focus on the industries that are relevant for the country. Once we do that, then we take small pilots. This is not spraying and praying. We focus on some areas, because obviously our most limited resource is not money. It’s people. It takes time, so you want to start top-down.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Space-wise, as I said, 1,500 square meters. In terms of education we tried to be agnostic. There, also, four months -- it used to be three months. Now it’s four months -- theory, eight months project base learning.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We develop a curriculum that’s quite advanced. That’s been accredited in many different countries around the world. It’s supposedly the best -- we’ve been receiving awards -- curriculum for begin not theoretical, but practical, actually applying this.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>People get a entry salary of $85,000. Even guys in South Africa.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Pontus Appelqvist">
          <p>We apply the same in China, for example, and Nanyang Technological University in Singapore.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then sometimes students don’t want to do a project. They are crazy. They want to have their own ideas. Instead of rejecting that, we embrace it. Say, &quot;OK, come with your idea. If it’s a good idea, we’ll introduce it to customers.&quot; Then you say, &quot;Recruit 10 students from the group and do a prototype, a map, a product, or even a company.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Here’s a crazy one. This guy came up with an idea to do a sports application, and then, two years later, he’s actually the CEO of EON Sports.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(video starts)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Narrator">
          <p>EON Sports and creators of SIIDEKIQ. SIDEKIQ is a virtual...</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(video stops)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>He became $25 million market cap. Alibaba wants to buy him out. He said no. Top three company in sports in the world, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>How do we fund this? We come in with $20.9 million, with co-investment 19.18 AVR systems, the platform, development lab. We pay five years for our teachers that we bring and live here and the project experts.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>76 percent of the investment. 24, the percent, is our local partner. What do we expect from the local partner? Three things. One is to help us recruit the students. Normally, not a problem.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Two, provide subject-matter experts. Let’s say we want to encapsulate knowledge around CNC machines. Then we need to talk with someone with someone that really understands that, that we then put together with us, then a co-investment in $6.6 million, which corresponds to 24 percent. That’s basically it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Locations, Manchester City. There we work with the local government, Sir Richard Leese, the mayor, and then with the universities.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Laval, same thing with the government. China, we work with China Merchants group, which is government owned, fourth largest company in the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Singapore, we work with the government, but they gave the money to a university, and then they continued. Pretoria, government. Melbourne, Deakin University, but also government.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>India, government folks in vocational training. I just was there for a week. We are doing 10 centers there, likewise in China. I’m going there tonight. Ethiopia, we talked about. Belgium, Greece, and so on and so forth.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I also, two weeks ago, fired myself. [laughs] I used to be the chairman. I’m still the largest shareholder in the company, but because I’m so passionate about this Human 2.0 I say I want to dedicate my next 20 years. By the time, I’m 55, so 75, god willing, if I have the health, we should do this Human 2.0 project.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I realize that our little company cannot do it alone, so I have to team up with governments, big corporations, but that’s the vision. Even if we do half, I’ll be very happy.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Today we are 42 million. [laughs] It’s a big long way to 3.8. Instead, our new chairman used to be the president of General Electric, ran 40,000 people. I’ve known him for 18 years. I’ve been on advisory board.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>David is our new CEO. He used to run British Airways, and also used to run an online company that he took to half a billion.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Very smart guys, and they will help us with the Nasdaq. Our company’s going on Nasdaq for market capital, approximately, of $2.3 billion.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s it. Summary, what’s the best? If we were to do this together, find a way to do it, it would be a state of the art center. I would say, by far, the largest in the region.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>There will be a school where we offer students to become experts in this area at no cost. We don’t charge for the school, but obviously we employ most of the students.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>It will be an entrepreneurial school that stimulates people coming up with their own idea, creating their own intellectual property outside our activity. The best one we’d love to invest in.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>It will be a bridge to employment, obviously. They will get access to the world’s largest library for learning, which grows every day, because it’s almost like crowdsourcing, and consistent content. We do it in a very qualitative way.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>There will be local IP development. I always joke about this, but at this point in my presentation I had Sir Richard Leese to say, &quot;Dan, thank you for your enthusiastic presentation, but I must say, sincerely, one thing.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I said, &quot;OK, what is it?&quot; &quot;Listen, we don’t want to develop content for you Americans.&quot; I said, &quot;First of all, I’m not American.&quot; [laughs] &quot;I’m Swedish.&quot; &quot;But what would like to do?&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>They said, &quot;Listen. I have four million people in my area. I have 43 four-year universities. I have Europe’s largest colleges, 300,000 students. What I like to do, I want to drink my own champagne first. What I mean is that if this technology can help us uplift, forget about making 12 times more money.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>&quot;Just say 40 percent better, faster knowledge transfer and can help uplift my people. For me, that’s valued 40 to 100 times more than making $50 million and outsourcing this because I want to take benefit of this before I get it to other people.&quot; I said, &quot;That makes sense.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We established the KPIs and then, we went from there. With that, I’ll stop there. Before I ask for your advice, maybe you have any questions?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, it all makes perfect sense. Do you have a neural lace lab?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I’m sorry?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Do you actually work with a neural lace lab?</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Neural lace lab? No. I know, it’s a joke. I got that part but seriously, I looked into it and it will get there. In fact, if you saw my slide, probably the next 20, 30, 40...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s exactly right because you are imagining 30-years of innovation.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>You see, 2037, we get neural lace. I’ve read everything about it. I’m a science fiction buff. The problem is, it’s becoming difficult by then to imagine what you cannot do. If you put this together, neural lace, and you put data roamers, and you put all this together, it becomes very complicated to see what humanity cannot do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Right now, I’m not worried about that. I’m just the bridge-maker. I’m the gap. I’m trying to get us from where we are today...AVR will be just an intermediary period, maybe 20, 30 years, allows us to leapfrog to neural lace because we can’t wait for neural lace. That’s not going to happen.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>One thing with your Human 2.0 vision, I think what your vision distinguishes between the Matrix-like scenario is that it enables humans to still feel useful in a society and focus people’s attention on each other instead of through some fake intermediaries, right? That was the main idea?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Then I do worry about the current generation of VR/AR devices because it requires a lot of extrapolation to the person in the environment for their brains to fill in because the device doesn’t really know where my eyes are looking and the device doesn’t really capture my minor expressions.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If we use that for communication, then it’s not actually represented in the other side. It’s mostly extrapolated...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s a poor version.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. At some point, in the office next door, they’ve got all the VR devices and there’s an uncanny valley, like a period where the VR/AR gets almost good enough but not quite. Then, it does create a jarring experience for people who spend extended time in it because it’s too...finding details on parts that’s not fine.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They shouldn’t be finding any details on the parts that my eyes are not looking but it’s not detailed enough in the parts that I actually look, which my eyes focused on and things like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I agree.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Also, to be honest with you, there’s many times I come in, I was, two weeks ago, in the biggest nuclear power plant in the US, in Palo Verde, and the first thing the guy came in and said, &quot;Oh, headset? I can’t take...I get headache.&quot;</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The discussion would have been over if that was our focus, headsets only. Then, I said, &quot;How about this room?&quot; Then, we had an IQ. Then, I said, &quot;OK, now you’re talking. More screens.&quot; First of all, the headsets -- we were just speculating about this -- it’s probably two, three years left.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Nobody’s going to go with a brick in front of their head. I think what we’re going towards is glasses and these glasses can use opacity and can transition easily from AR to VR but it’s going to take some time.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Meanwhile, I think this, what you have right there, there’s a billion of them. It’s actually a very good way to do AR knowledge injection. For the things we are doing, what you are talking about is there. Human communication, which requires a lot of aspects.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Like three or five years in the future.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Correct. We are now on the basic, how do I replace a fry master? [laughs] Basic but it’s useful. People are willing to pay for it and we help bit by bit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The contents are still going to be useful.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>The contents will be reusable. We have content that’s six or seven years old that still is very useful. It is exciting but the challenge here is, how do you create this PPP, private-public partnership? If you look at how we done it in other locations, and then, I’ll ask you for the device. This is the last slide.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>How we did it for other locations...70 percent of our centers...because we tried first to do it with private people. Private people, what happens is they look immediately to help close the center. [laughs] Meaning that, we met a company here and they said, &quot;Yes, you can do it but you cannot work with this company and this company.&quot; That’s not what we want to do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We want to do it in an open way. The way we done it, for example, in the UK, 70 percent of cases, we came in with 75 percent of the money. The local government, in this case, manages to provide us a grant but it’s not free money because we agreed on the KPIs. For example, uplift X amount of people. Deliver this based on these priorities.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Based on that, as long as we fulfill the KPI, it is a grant. If we don’t or don’t achieve the goals, they have the right to get some back. This is the way we did it in Manchester. We did the same in France. In Singapore, the money went to a university, so that’s 20 percent.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>When the government, don’t provide us the grant, they provide it to a university and we have to donate our 20.9. The university owns the center and we get access to it. For us, it’s no different. We can do either one or the other.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>US, we did it also through a university. Norway, we did it through a government. They set up a cluster. Belgium, they did it different. They have an investment arm, so they actually invested in the entity. Cape Town, they gave the money to a university and so on and so forth.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Czech Republic was through the EU. Greece was through government grant. Serbia, this minister became, actually, the prime minister, first female prime minister and so on. I would say, 70 percent is government grants. 20 percent is government investing in university and we, making a foreign investment in that university, or donation. Then, 10 percent, private.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Now, comes my question. Given your experience, what would you advise us, what do you think would be the most -- it’s assuming you find this interesting for Taiwan -- what would you recommend us would be the best path to make it happen?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In Taiwan, public universities are not companies, in the strict sense. They are more like units in the Ministry of Education.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you do want to work directly with universities, it will have either to be private universities, or you will have to find yourself a way into fulfilling some specific Ministry of Education goals, which I’m not aware of anything corresponding to your plan, at this moment.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For K-12, there are KPIs around digital and media literacy in K-12 curriculum but it’s not strictly vocational in the way that you displayed it. It’s more about...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>STEM?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We do it, for example, in Singapore, I didn’t say this much but the biggest market now is actually K-12, if you look at number of students because it’s like a pyramid.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then, we do develop courses. I would say, the value is everything physical, practical, whether it’s chemistry, physics, biology, more so than relativity theory because that’s more of a theoretical thing. It has to be something with interaction with a practical thing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It had to be designed in a social way, in the sense that five or six children interacting with a single object, settings like that. For K-12, I’m not aware of anything specific like the thing you offer here, in the K-12 curriculum that’s taking effect about a year and a half from now.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In addition to the K-12 curriculum, there are also experimental schools.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Taiwan does have a very vibrant alternate schooling system in the K-12 and private universities above K-12, so that is one venue. I’m not very well connected to that private university scene but it is a possibility.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The other possibility would be regional governments, where you mention that you’ve been approaching. I think, in our last meeting, you mentioned Taichung, Taoyuan, and Kaohsiung, something like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>We’ll be presenting there in two weeks. The Smart City exhibition, we’ll be presenting. We’re still talking to them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right. Even if the national government doesn’t have exactly a corresponding plan, perhaps the regional governments do. If the regional governments see that it is important, like the Kaohsiung city did, to have AVR industry as its local cluster, then it will have the sufficient land and planning in that region to develop this kind of ecosystem.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That would be business between the private sector and the city government. It wouldn’t be a national level investment. That’s two different levels.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We have had success regionally. I have a question, though. We were having a meeting here yesterday here, and I gave an example of what happened in Thailand. I was in Thailand last week. The government there set up something for the digital economy called Thailand 4.0.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>They create a new scheme, similar to what Italy has and almost every country has, where if there’s a foreign investment, and want to put 75 percent on investment and the local government can support 25 percent grant, assuming certain criteria and that is an impact to many.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>What we were told yesterday is that there is a similar scheme here in Taiwan. Are you aware of this scheme?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Mm-hmm.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>In that case, would you be interested or willing to help us to get to the right contacts to apply for such a scheme?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There are many such plans. I’m not sure which one you’re referring to.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Fion Liao">
          <p>MOE has a grant on global IT Innovation culture.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>In November, there’s going to be the private investment company.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, there is that. It is called Taiwania Capital Management. Which is, I think, AI and IoT-focused at this point but they may do some AVR as well.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There’s virtually one per ministry interested in it. There’s one for MOEA, actually two for MOEA, one for MOE, and one for MOST, but the MOST one works with the NDC.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think those are the four primary programs. I’m not directly in touch with any one of them. [laughs] I just read some bi-weekly reports.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I guess the question then, and we don’t have to answer them today, is that based on your understanding of what we would like to achieve, which would you recommend? A, would be the most suitable and B, the probability is reasonable to engage with that, if it is or not, I should say. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Honestly, I’m not involved in the case selection process or the review process of any of those four funds. I’m aware of their existence and what kind of companies that they produced, but I’m not involved in the process at all, so I have no idea about the criteria that they use to pick the investments.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>We have, normally, a 95 percent success rate but I’ve learned from the past, these two things. You have to do, what I call top-down, bottom-up. You have to get blessing, or at least general interest, from a minister level person or higher.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then, you do have to engage with the people that actually make the decisions, which is not the minister. The minister goes, this is interesting. If you do both, with this type of offer, our success has been high. We had a chance to meet the working people but we haven’t had a chance to get to the minister yet in each department.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I believe many trust your judgment in terms of what technology is feasible and what is not and you have a great amount of respect. If you could consider to give your recommendation to, for example, a minister to spend 30 minutes with us, worst case scenario, they learn a little bit more about what is happening in this sector.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I think that would be very helpful for us. Would you be open to do that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What I will do is that after each of our meetings, I will do a full transcript of what has been spoken here, and you can edit for brevity, making the message more powerful.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>OK, so we can use that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right. You can use that. Maybe not the neural lace part; other parts.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Feel free to use the transcript’s URL, which I relinquish all copyrights. Go ahead and use it in however way you want. Maybe we can do a short summary as a summary statement or whatever. I think that’s the extent that I can help.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s great.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I can certainly lend my URL, which is the PDIS site, the <a href="https://sayit.pdis.nat.gov.tw">https://sayit.pdis.nat.gov.tw</a> website that we use to capture all the transcripts that we have made in all our discussions that we had there. We have plenty of meetings with companies.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For example, there was a Bitcoin company here and talking about how they want taxation regulations to be changed to be considered a virtual currency instead of a virtual good, which was repeatedly taxed and so on. Then, that company used its transcript and forwarded it to the Minister of Finance, but the tax code did not change.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>I think that’s a bit more different than what we’re trying to do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly. It is, actually, very challenging to reclassify Bitcoin into any of those terms because when the terms were made, there was no Bitcoin, so it doesn’t really clearly fit into any of those slots for the central bank. That was that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Feel free to use the same model and communicate either with regional leadership or with other ministries.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>Audrey, you mentioned last time, correct me if I’m wrong, once an IDC like this, Taiwan needs it and is actually planning something like this, but it’s about four to five years out?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Well just today, that plan got the budget from the parliament.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>This is something you feel is needed now and it’s in the planning stages but it’s going to be four to five years if Taiwan is able to do it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I would encourage you to look at the detail plan. It’s at <a href="http://achievement.ey.gov.tw/cp.aspx?n=1E42BEB0F68720CB&amp;s=0E1FF5CBE8AF0056">http://achievement.ey.gov.tw/cp.aspx?n=1E42BEB0F68720CB&amp;s=0E1FF5CBE8AF0056</a> -- if you just go to the ey.gov.tw website, you can see the special budget. Then, if you click the special budget, it will lead you to a page where all the currently -- well, today -- approved special budget items are there. That’s the red square here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>This includes the DIGI⁺ program?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The one-time hardware part of DIGI⁺ are there. The recurrent parts, we can’t use the special budget. It’s all at DIGI⁺ webside, <a href="http://www.digi.ey.gov.tw/.">http://www.digi.ey.gov.tw/.</a> Here you will see this AVR science mark hub project.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Who’s heading that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The Kaohsiung city and the Ministry of Economic Affairs. The MOEA.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s the person we need to reach.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I would encourage you to read the KPIs there because it was done in a bottom-up fashion. Also, they consulted the existing AVR companies. There’s a lot of people doing special effects and things like that, around that area. They talked with them and so everybody felt that it’s reasonable in that region. Then, they proposed it to the national level for the special budget.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you are looking for alignment with KPI, I would highly encourage you to compare your KPIs in other governments with the KPI that’s outlined in this special budget item. That’s the most relevant part.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>All the others, I think, would require a lot of adaptation of your program to fit the Minister of Education’s K-12 or the Ministry of Science and Technology’s AI-based platform, in which AVR is still important but more like a facilitating tool.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Yeah, it’s a vehicle to inject AI.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>That’s right. Excellent. I really appreciate that advice. It was an honor and pleasure to meet you. Thank you for taking so much of your time. We’ll be back in Taiwan and this gentleman lives in the area, so...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>Yeah, Singapore.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>How far is it?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>It’s one half hour.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Nothing. I have to fly here. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s in a nearby time zone, we could meeting VR.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#David Hall">
          <p>Virtually.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Then, the last point is that if the minister travels to any of the locations, UK, France, I know that you are speaking sometimes in France.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Vous parlez Français?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>A little bit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>A little bit, OK. I just bought a house there because I enjoy France, not only enjoy France but we have a growing activity. As you know, France is hosting the La Valle, which is the number one place for research meetings. My house is just there. Our center is just there, also. I would love to host you when you come next time or if you go to California, likewise.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Dan Lejerskar">
          <p>Let’s keep that contact and we will do what you just suggested. We’ll take advantage of your offer. We will try to get to the ministers that have, as you suggested, the AVR projects first and see where they take us. Thank you so much. It was a pleasure. Thank you.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It was a pleasure. Thank you.</p>
        </speech>
      </debateSection>
    </debateBody>
  </debate>
</akomaNtoso>
