<akomaNtoso>
  <debate>
    <meta>
      <references>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/AP" id="AP" showAs="AP">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/KBS" id="KBS" showAs="KBS">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/MK" id="MK" showAs="MK">
        </TLCPerson>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <debateBody>
      <debateSection>
        <heading>2017‑04‑12 AP &amp; KBS Interview at Seoul</heading>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Can I just call you Audrey...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, of course.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>[laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Just Audrey.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>We’ll have another interview from KBS.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, I don’t know whether it will be simultaneous, or...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>No, I asked to...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Oh, you asked them to?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>...because I would actually use the time to have...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>I just want to run your profile briefly for fact checking purpose.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>You’re the youngest minister in Taiwan, is that correct?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>At the moment, but not historically. There was a Minister of Youth Affairs, 鄭麗君. When she went into the Cabinet a few years ago, she was 34.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Right now you’re the...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right now, I’m the youngest, at 35.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>You’re the first transgender minister in Taiwan?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In the world.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>You never went to college?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, I dropped out of junior high school when I was 14.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>When did you start your first company? At the age of...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>15.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>And your IQ is 180?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s just a rumor.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>That’s a rumor?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>My height is 180 cm. It often gets confused.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>[laughs] What’s your real IQ?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For adults the IQ test only gets to 160, above which the WAIS Test cannot reliably test. I am 160 or more but I don’t really know how much more. I’ve tested twice and there’s no way to know.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>...or more. I see. You started your Silicon Valley startup at the age of 19?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s correct.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>What happened to the company?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is still running. It was like an angel investment by a lot of Taiwan companies, and then we continued part of our operation in Mainland China and part of it in Taiwan. It’s still running (benqguru.com), but I’m no longer in charge of it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>You have actually a very impressive record.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>Minister, after meeting Dr. 張大煥, he was really interested in your philosophy. Habermas come up with democracy problems who have...I’m sure you know, because you mentioned the deliberation as a keyword. Habermas said deliberated democracy, which is the most important idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>You’re actually realizing that deliberative democratic system in Taiwan, so we are very intrigued about your progress.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The thing with the deliberation is that it’s magical, because when people enter into a high quality deliberation, everybody walks out changed. Then people respect each other and they will become immune to the rumors, to the propaganda, after deliberation.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The problem with deliberation is two. First, it’s messy. Meaning that every time you run it there’s no established way to get high quality deliberation. Second, it doesn’t scale. Meaning, if it’s 20 people, maybe you can get deliberation. If it’s 200 people, it’s impossible. If it’s 2,000 people, people just start shouting at each other.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Basically, listening, as the key to deliberation, does not scale. Meaning with more people it actually loose it’s magic. We use ICT, information communication technology, to scale the experience of listening. That’s our main contribution.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>In that process, do you actually allow the netizens into listening process?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>So about your program, your software. It has been developed in order to gather public opinion?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes, of course. There are these very important principle, in the idea that we use the Internet to deliberate people’s feelings, not their suggestions, not their decisions. Because if you jump into suggestions, people will not reveal the feeling they have behind the suggestion.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Even though five people say at least the same thing or they vote the same way, maybe they do it out of different subjective feelings. What we have outsourced before was people’s feelings, for example, around one concrete issue like you own a private car and you don’t have a professional driver’s license. Then you use this app, and then you get a stranger on your backseat and you drive them somewhere, and you charge them for it ‑‑ without mentioning any company name.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>[laughs] Yeah, exactly. Then, our software is an open source software. Basically, ask people one yes or no question, and based on their yes or no question, they get clustered. After you answer a question, whether you think insurance is important, whether you think it’s public safety, your avatar moves on the screen so you can cluster with people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This interface has two very important thing. First, it shows your Facebook and Twitter friends first, so you can see if people having very different idea than you, they are not anonymous enemies. They’re still your friends. It’s just you haven’t talk about this over dinner, so it’s not your enemy. That’s first.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The second thing is that in Internet forum it’s very easy for these to politicize, to dominate all the discussion, and these people are silent because they’d shout...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>They’re always polarizing.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes. The thing here is that you can press consensus and see there’s nevertheless 91 percent of everybody agrees the importance of checking of the driver’s credentials are protecting the passenger, so there can be consensus among disagreements.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>After you answer a few yes or no questions, you can also type in your own feeling, which then gets voted by other people. What we said before the deliberation was that if by the end of the process we have a set of agreements, more than 80 percent of people agree on something, then we agree to use this super majority consensus as our national agenda to negotiate with Uber and with other taxi.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>May I interrupt, Minister. How do you gather peoples’ own opinion? Like you said, you didn’t listen to their suggestions, you didn’t listen to their rational opinions. You just captured their feelings or their innate tendency to a specific policy, so how do you gather information?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No. We just ask people to start the sentence here with 我覺得, which is, &quot;I feel that...&quot; and then that’s it. We’re not passively monitoring. We’re actively asking people to write their authentic feelings, and then, this is an open‑ended survey, so people can feel anything.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>Within that process, people might really disguise or didn’t want to show their real feelings, so you might have to ask them twice or more times.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s right. You can change your positions anytime here, and then you can state a more nuanced feeling, because we only take as finding things that you managed to convince everybody. If it’s a disguised or if it’s a non‑authentic feeling, if people don’t share it, it doesn’t have any effect.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>People are basically competing to first convince people who think like them, and gradually to convince people who doesn’t think like them, and we only take the supermajority as the agenda.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>How do you call that system?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This system has a name called Pol.is, P‑O‑L‑.‑I‑S.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>You worked hard to develop. You say it really taken a lot of resources to develop...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is actually a community effort started by some Seattle hackers, but it is open source so everybody can contribute, so I also contributed to its development. It was contributed usually by people who participated in an Occupy or a protest movement before.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>After the Occupy Wellington, the New Zealand people would join, and after the Occupy Wall Street...Every time after an Occupy, people start thinking, &quot;OK. Democracy can take another form,&quot; and then these people will join this development.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#MK">
          <p>You’ve been a month before your team in Taiwan was in the 2014 Sunflower Movement.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s exactly right. We started this development before the Sunflower, but we were not many people, a hundred or so, but after the Sunflower it was just exploded in interest.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Just quickly, is this platform are you using for the Taiwanese government...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Are you using this platform for Taiwan’s government to gather public opinion?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s exactly right.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Can you give me just one example of the latest issue that you’ve got the idea from this from?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Mm‑hmm. The most high profile of course was the Uber case, but we also use the same for the Airbnb case, for Internet sales of alcoholic beverages, and so on. Just today, Uber announced that they will bind themselves to the consensus that’s made here, and they will change their business model starting tomorrow to play by the rules that were set in the deliberative fashion.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>How many people participated in the Uber survey?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In the Uber survey thousands of people participated, but only around one thousand or so logged in so that we can see their avatars, and they have answered more than nine questions so we can determine their position. It’s about, I would say, about one thousand active players, but about nine thousand or so are peripheral players.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Actually today I’m interested in two of the initiated from your department, and one of them is the eSport. I’ve heard that your department’s planning to replace the mandatory military service to playing computer games. Is that right? Can you tell also more about this and why you are doing this?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right. First, it’s not about computer games. eSport is a sport. It just happens so that the stadium they use is a virtual one, not a physical one, but the point here is the computational sport aspect.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>My favorite argument in this conversation is that I think Go (圍棋), the board game, is now a eSport, because most of the competition and training happens online, and also because machines now play better than human, [laughs] so this is mostly for two human beings to enjoy each other’s company and play for performance, and in this sense, it really has nothing different from other eSports.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>As for the alternative military service, it is true that it’s already the case for Go, for 圍棋 players in Taiwan. They can have alternative military service if they win some international or national competition awards. The same applies for any other sport as well as like symphony conductors and other cultural performers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>An e‑Sport athlete being a cultural performer, and which has international competition and so on, shouldn’t really be discriminated against. That was just the basic idea, so we’re not actively promoting in. We’re just saying this is like other sport.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The other thing that we used during the e‑Sport thing is that we have on our previous website a accountability trail where you can have this QR code that lists the entire decision making process for how exactly this policy was formed.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Starting from the public hearing, down to the classes, down to the military service, down the national tax breaks, and so on, we have all the ministries and all the decision makers in our internal meetings taken as a transcript ‑‑ was real time transcript ‑‑ and everybody, after editing it for 10 working days, agreed to publish it to the general public even before we have set our direction.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This is very important, because then everybody, that use for athletes or the stakeholders, look at our conversation and deliberation records and let us know over the Internet where we have missed, where there’s legal precedent for that, and so on, and so they were contributed, and I quote them on the next meeting and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Everybody knows that’s when all the three lights here goes from yellow, which means it’s in progress, to green, which means it’s resolved. We have resolved this policy case, and it’s one piece of the puzzle, it’s the military service, but there is also the educational aspect and also the industrial aspect. These are a complete picture, this is not just one isolated policy making.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>What are the two most popular e‑Sports game in Taiwan, and how far you have to perform in order to be replaced the mainstream military service?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>There are 10 spots with a firm criteria. Of course, if you win an Olympic level competition, that automatically qualifies, but even from a sport like LoL, there is actually no frequent Olympic level competitions.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The next thing of course is the alliances between the different countries. We’ve set a basic criteria that says it has to be regular, and it has to have at least this many people in its regional and this many people in its national level, and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you qualify for that ‑‑ there’s a few competitions for LoL that qualifies for that ‑‑ if you win the first three places or so, that also qualifies. Then, after that, it was about a national level competitions which still has to have some kind of structure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This is a three‑tier system, but still, only the professional players get to continue their work during this kind of alternate service, so we’re not rewarding video game players. We’re rewarding professional athletes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Another topic we are interested to know is that your country is starting to educate children about how to identify fake news at school starting next year. Can you tell us why you think it’s important to educate that?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think it’s important that we don’t use the words &quot;fake news,&quot; because I think it is a disservice to journalism. [laughs] There are rumors which are viral, which means people who spread it doesn’t bother to check, but it’s not necessarily false or fake. Some rumors turn out to be true.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The point here is that people need to learn to do basic source checking, fact checking, and balance of a diverse set of opinions and so on, basically critical thinking and independent thinking. In our curriculum, we call it information technology and media literacy.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This idea is not about spotting &quot;fake news,&quot; but about being able to make decisions and make opinions of oneself during a learning experience so that people don’t guess away one way or another based on rumors. That’s the basic idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The other thing of critical thinking is being able to listen and change one’s mind or opinion when new facts surface. Again, this is kind of against human nature, so we need to get started very early on and say, &quot;Standing to be corrected is actually a virtue. It is not about losing face or anything.&quot; This is the other aspect I think are very important.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Starting, what age would Taiwanese students...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The entire K‑12 system, that is to say starting from the first grade all the way through senior high school, because this is not a class. This is one of the literacy that need to be merged into all the classes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>All the classes, the teachers and the textbook makers and schools need to find some way to find media literacy and critical thinking into the way they are teaching, and not just taking it as a class, as a examination.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>I’ll have just one more. What was your reactions in your country when you were first appointed? Number one, you’re the hacker, so people may be worried that. &quot;How can a hacker be working for the government? Hacker can attack.&quot; A hacker is usually seen as somebody who attacks the government.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Like lawyers?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Yeah, or maybe lawyers...</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Number two, in South Korea, we had not a high government official to come out of closet, not to mention publicly transgender, it would instill huge outrage with the constituents. Do you have those outrage in Taiwan as well?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not at all, because first, I started working with public service in 2014, after the Sunflower Movement. For many career public servants, I’m already very well known as one of the people who helped them to communicate, to facilitate conversation with citizens.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In many cases, in people in administration, they call me kind of an understudy minister already. For a couple of years before I joined the cabinets working for the previous minister of cyberspace, Jaclyn Tsai.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What I’m saying is that if people had some outrage or whatever, it already happened 2014. It’s not waiting after I become a cabinet minister. That’s the first. The second thing about hackers. I think in Taiwan, because cyber security is very, very serious matter, people put a lot of understanding into it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They don’t really have this magical thinking that think hacker are somehow magicians. They understand this is just one kind of technology, and technology is just like any locksmiths or whatever, has their pride, has their professional code of conduct, and things like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Just like when people know a lot about law, maybe they exploit a loophole of law and become very bad lawyers, but they don’t have to be, right? They can become lawmakers that makes a better kind of law that is not going to be exploited.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think it’s much the same. I understand information technology, but it doesn’t mean that I will exploit its loopholes. It means that I will set up a system that doesn’t suffer from the same kind of loopholes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Since you’re at the hacking competition, is it getting more important these days for the government to foster more hackers like yourself?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, verily. The first thing I did after joining the cabinet was recompile the Linux kernel to add secure computing to our internal government information facilities, which is the system that we use every day.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We then invited penetration testers, which are security experts, who tried to attack the system and to find the loopholes, so that we can rest assured that when we are using the system, we configure it properly and so on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We take this very seriously, and we believe that active penetration testing and forensics, and all these tools, enables us to have a clear understanding of our information technology’s infrastructure and its limitations, so that we use it in a responsible manner.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Otherwise, all would be just voodoo and hearsay, which is pretty much the worst case, because then people will take some countermeasures that then cause side effects and so on. I think a clear understanding of the cyber security landscape is for everybody’s benefit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>What about the growing intergovernmental or allegedly intergovernmental cyber attacks? There is allegations of North Korea attacked South Korea, for example. There are allegation of cyber terrorism between China and the United States. Does that make this more important to have more hackers in the government?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, I think just like with any other terrorism, the impact itself is actually low. The thing that they hope for is to provoke some mysterious fear, and then have people overreact. The overreaction, actually, causes more damage than the initial attempt, that cyber terrorists are a real‑world terrorism.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s like a mosquito trying to get onto a bull, and then to break things into a store. The whole idea is to have a calm and clear understanding, and have cyber security experts explaining in a very clear, accessible manner what exactly is happening.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Then people would not panic, and they will not clamor for things that will actually cause more damage. I think literacy, again, is the most important thing here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>That connects with your education about the media literacy. Just one more about...I think there’s some Taiwanese people who believe that, the rumors are circulating in Taiwan, maybe behind that there is China.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Do you think that’s one reason that Taiwan should increase its education in media literacy? Because of China...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In Taiwan, there are many ideological camps. There’s pro‑unification. There’s pro‑independence. There are everything in between, and I think these camps are more than sufficient to generate credible rumors without being remote controlled by any other places or any other groups.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That said, I think it is important for people to get inoculated against this kind of virus of mind and deliberation, as you already mentioned, I think is the key for the inoculation, because any effect, fact‑checking, or whatever, after a rumor has already spread only has a containment effect.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If people have already considered carefully even the position of people they don’t agree with, they already have some kind of inoculation in their mind, so that they will not fall victim to rumors. I think really, this kind of early‑stage prevention is the key here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Just by getting people to listen to the ideas that they don’t like, basically, develops your immunology system.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>I think your view on this fake news ‑‑ I only use this term because that’s what my readers are familiar with ‑‑ it’s very refreshing. Could you comment on the US, US President Donald Trump, about how the way he communicates with the public?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Do you think the way he names some of the news media as a fake news outlet? What do you think about them?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>When Twitter first got invented, people used Twitter in the way that’s very direct, and make full use of the 140 characters. Taiwanese people used Twitter more like regular blogging, because in 140 Chinese characters, you can say a lot, [laughs] but in English, not so much.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think there’s a distinct style difference in the ways that we Twitter versus a English speaker use of Twitter. They had to be very brief, and basically just say even just one idea or half of an idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>As things developed, because I was in developing social media networks, we see a lot of very creative uses in Twitter, like multi‑part tweets, like the tweets that are complementing each other using hashtags and conversation communities, and so on. They built a community structure out of those very short forms of communication.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>@realDonaldTrump used Twitter the way when it was first invented, [laughs] used it as it meant to be, so it’s also very refreshing to me. I learned a lot.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>What do you learn from his way of using Twitter?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Basically, he had self‑contained messages.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Self‑contained...?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Contained messages that doesn’t rely on context.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Can you elaborate on...? [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Can I elaborate?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think that was pretty self‑contained. The idea is that if I have make a very long speech, where each sentence depend on the context of the sentence before and after, then when any one of those sentence gets taken out of context, it will be turned into something that I don’t already mean.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If I make all my messages self‑contained and short, then there’s no danger of being taken out of context. This is the basic thing that I learned, not necessarily from @realDonaldTrump, but it is the idea of Twitter at its beginning.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>I don’t want to take all your time, Minister.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>Some things in your career path is quite very impressive and somewhat special. I heard that you learned programming by yourself after dropping out of mid‑school. What would be the reason?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I learned programming when I was eight years old. That was seven years before I drop out of middle school.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Would you like to translate? Is English OK?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>No, you just speak in English, and I’m going to record it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s great. Yeah, I started very early on to take an interest in mathematics, and I started reading programming language books when I was eight. They described a way for people to very quickly get results with mathematics without having to do all the calculations by hand, and it’s much less error‑prone.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I got very interested. I didn’t have a computer, so I basically just took pencil and paper and drew keyboard and typed on paper, and then wrote what the computer would say and so one. Basically, I drew a paper computer.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This means that computational thinking is one way of thinking. It doesn’t depend on the machine, and if one structure oneself in some way, some part of the thought process can be automated.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For me, it is like learning a music instrument without having access to the piano or to the oboe instrument. The idea is just to learn the idea of melodies, and chords, and compositions, and so on, so that people can play this kind of music.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>After a few months, I started programming on a real personal computer, and then I found that those notes that I learned as programming languages actually makes melodies that are shaping spaces, around the spaces in which people can interact with each other.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The first programs that I wrote are computer games where people can play with each other, against each other, and so on, so that also characterized how people behave around each other by creating a space of people’s interaction.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This is a very special kind of instrument, I would say, while learning it is just like learning any other music instrument. The notes it creates is actually a new kind of space where people can interact.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>You’re a civic hacker since you are 33, right?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>What kind of activities did you focus on, and what were your goals at the time?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m always a civic hacker. I started working on Internet’s human ride and freedom of speech movement at least since 1996. That’s during the Blue Ribbon Campaign and so on, so yeah, I’m always a civic hacker I would say.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The primary thing, of course, is the sharing of the knowledge and making the process of sharing also a common knowledge. As early hackers, we all believe that the tools that we use to shape our lives is more and more taking over the role that was initially taken by laws.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>More and more we’re living in a case where algorithms, where computer code already determine what is possible and what is not possible even before the legal code kicks in. The problem being that computer code was not transparent.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>And people using the computer code doesn’t really know why it’s went to here and has no freedom to modify it or to distribute its modification. I would say that my core concern is still this kind of Internet freedom, with software freedom being one part of it, but also freedom of speech, of assembly, and of other human rights.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>Thank you. The last question would be why do think cyber security matters the most in the era of the fourth industrial revolution and if there’s any example you can give of this.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The security matters a lot, because if people are still using Internet for freedom of speech and of assembly, people must know for sure, not just blindly trusting that the speech they make on the Internet will not be used against them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If the Internet becomes a technology that oppresses people, then when people are going to have assemblies or have to express their freedom, they will go back to pen and paper or to face‑to‑face meeting, and the Internet will lose its original liberating promise of getting people who feel that they are alone and they don’t have people who think like them into communities.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Basically, if we don’t do our job right on security on the Internet, the Internet becomes a fragmenting force instead of a community force. If it becomes a fragmenting force, people will have a lot of small Intranets, like a balkanization of Internet, and each Intranet will have an exclusionary policy that excludes people who don’t think like them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You will not foster a cross‑community dialog and else will become a much more fragmented space where people live essentially in their own realities, and that is as undemocratic and as non‑humane as we can imagine if we extrapolate these trends further.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think the utmost importance is to get people to still see Internet as a secure place by having the literacy of telling insecure communication with secure communication, and keep to the secure communication methods so that people can still form communities where it still becomes possible to talk with strangers, to learn from strangers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>This is another question about security, because we have now self‑driving cars and AI‑level at so many things, and he would like to say to us some words why is it specifically more important security in AI and self‑driving cars.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Security, this word in English is very interesting, because it describes both a property of a system and also a state of mind. I feel secure versus a secured system.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In Mandarin Chinese, in the language that we use, we say 資安, the 安 meaning &quot;at ease,&quot; a calmness with information. This is important when I’m sitting in a self‑driving car, for example, because if the system is mathematically proven, it satisfies a lot of properties, all the engineers, everybody, vouch for it.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If their proof‑carrying code and all those advanced verification mechanisms cannot translate it to the language that everybody, common people, understands, they may achieve the mathematical definition of security, but there is no psychological or sociological definition of security, of feeling secure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>For me feeling secure is the goal, and this is just the mechanism, the instrumentation for it. On the other hand, there is a lot of what we call security theater, which means that not going through the rigorous mathematical proof, but just to enact on theater and trick people into believing, into feeling secure about something that’s actually not very secure.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>If you go to those security theaters for...this a lot like rumors. If you go to a lot of security theaters, people lose the ability to tell a rigorous system versus a non‑rigorous system. I think this is of utmost importance.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Because if people cannot tell a rigorous system versus some non‑rigorous system, people will not ask technology what they want to feel secure. People will just blindly accept whatever the vendors push to them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This creates a false sense of security, but then, when cyber terrorism or other attacks happen, people will panic because they did not know that their system, which they rely on, doesn’t have the property that they imagine that it have.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Again, as the AI and IoT technologies becomes part of not only our life but become part of ourselves, it is very important. Just like the medical knowledge enables us to know what is happening with my own body, my extended body also needs the same kind of self‑introspection and knowledge so that I can feel at ease with an extended part of my body. For many people, their phone or their smartwatch is already part of their body.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Do we have time to ask one more question?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>One more question about these answers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>Like you just mentioned, the autonomous car, the people...I mean the producers of the autonomous car will always say that this is a safe. It could be, like you mentioned, it’s a security theater, because we do not know that the autonomous cars will be safe or not.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>We cannot really tell. Technology is so complex. Artificial intelligence technology cannot really interpret it through people’s daily arrangements. Perhaps you could understand it...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#KBS">
          <p>So how can we assure that the autonomous vehicle is really safe?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>First we can do it through simulation. You can invent some simulation scenario, and try to put the algorithms in and see if it behaves the way you think it should behave. This is how actually we test real human testers.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Human testers describe the situation to human drivers, when they’re taking the drivers’ test and see whether they have the good...and this is essentially the same that we put the pilots also into in their cockpit simulations.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Basically, as the spirit of Turing Test, if AI can handle all the situations the human can imagine, and through at it, at a simulation, then we can judge it based on how it thinks and explains itself and their stimulation scenarios.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>At the moment, there’s still always somebody behind the wheel to take over when the machine fears that they don’t have the confidence to handle the situation. Another very important thing is the human machine hand‑off.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We need to have augmented reality system projected on the window of the car to have the driver know what the AI are thinking about the situation, and not just very low bandwidth SMS‑like messages, because then it will be too late.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s very important to have this co‑piloting mechanism between the AI pilot and the human driver for the foreseeable future before we can even think about going to fully autonomous driving.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Do you mind talking about some personal life?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>What was your family’s response to your decision to go through the transition from man to woman, could you tell us about your plans for your family, whether you have a plan to start a family?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>My family is really non‑rigid as far as gender stereotype goes. My mom was very expressive and was raised in a very androgynous manner, and so they don’t tell me what a man or a woman should or shouldn’t do.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Instead of transition, I would say that I’m just post-gender or post-genre, meaning that I don’t think there should be things that only one gender should do. I think anything that is declared is discrimination. I’m more against discrimination than against any kind of particular gender identity. That’s the first.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>When I developed this kind of thoughts, when I was an adolescent, I think they think in more philosophical stance rather than a psychological thing. I think they’re pretty friendly, and we keep dialoging.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Even when I decided to change my name, I made sure that my new name is OK by my father, [laughs] and that he also think it’s a good name before I changed my name into it. As for family, I already have a family. It’s just not human children. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I live with seven cats and two dogs, and have been living with them for 10 years now. It is a very large family, it’s just not human children, and I do plan to continue living with them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Two cats and...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Two dogs and seven cats.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Seven cats. Oh, wow. I have two cats. [laughs] I consider them my children as well. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah. Any final questions?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#AP">
          <p>Thank you for all the...very interesting.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Thank you. It was a pleasure for me as well.</p>
        </speech>
      </debateSection>
    </debateBody>
  </debate>
</akomaNtoso>