<akomaNtoso>
  <debate>
    <meta>
      <references>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang">
        </TLCPerson>
        <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Morley J. Weston" id="Morley J. Weston" showAs="Morley J. Weston">
        </TLCPerson>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <debateBody>
      <debateSection>
        <heading>2018-05-15 Interview with Morley J. Weston</heading>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>This story I’m writing, it’s largely about the use of Facebook, other social media in the upcoming campaign. Everybody wrote about it in 2014, but since then there hasn’t been much that people have said about it. Things have really changed since then. There’s been the Cambridge Analytica thing. Facebook has changed its privacy. There’s the GDPR things coming into effect.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>All of this together, I think it’s really going to change the environment between 2014, 2018, and 2020.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What about 2016?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Again, not much writing that went on.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No analyses?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Yeah, as far as I can tell. 2014 was the big watershed, especially Ko Wen-je’s campaign. There’s been endless academic literature about that. Something specifically with you I want to ask about is, the social media literacy campaign. I know you’ve been working on this quite a while.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That was in my previous role working with NAER.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>What’s going on with it now? Has it been implemented?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>As far as I know, the NAER, the National Academy for Education Research, has been working with the Media Watch Foundation on a five year plan to develop supplementary materials for the teachers, train the trainers, to have teachers know what media literacy is, how to integrate it into everyday education.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>How does it work across all the different fields and disciplines, instead of just one class for children learn? I think the Media Watch people will have the most up to date idea. The NCC also, I think, is working on its own media literacy education programs and applications, as well, but I don’t oversee them on a day to day basis. I was part of the committee, but no longer.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do think Taiwan’s well prepared, in general?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes, very much so.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>What do you think the state of media literacy in Taiwan is at the moment?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I was just talking with journalists from Global Views Monthly, the GVM. They are very interested in this topic, as well. I think people in Taiwan who are digital natives or people who learn to use Internet, it’s just part of their life. They don’t think real space/cyberspace. It’s already very integrated.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They get exposed to all kind of different materials, so source checking and so on, it’s already a instinct. It’s very difficult to infect people with a viral message and expect people not fact check. In that sense, I think Taiwan’s very healthy.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Of course, there are pockets of population who are educated in a more authoritarian era, before the martial law was lifted. They tend to look at messages printed in some form that were spoken with some authoritative voice or are credited to some authoritative figure and be more inclined to believe it. That is really a Taiwan specific issues.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In many other countries, the freedom of speech was taken for granted for all the generations. In Taiwan, there is a generational/educational gap. With the prevalence of social media and lying in particular, we see a lot of cross generational learning taking place, as well. Even the older generations are now catching on that not all what they see is real.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you think propaganda specifically coming from China is a big concern?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I don’t think so.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>You don’t think so? Why not?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>First of all, the virality of a message is just like a chain mail. Every time it spreads, the one that was mutated to be more trustworthy seeming [laughs] gets more people sharing it. The one doesn’t really hit something in people’s mind, they don’t get spread.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Even though maybe the original message originate from somewhere else than Taiwan, for it become really viral, it needs a lot of local contributions. For foreign actors, it’s much easier if you just sponsor a local team doing local originating content, instead of trying to supply your own message and try to spread it. The memes from foreign Internet culture doesn’t spread very well here.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>I think people can tell the difference, too, when something comes from Taiwan and when it doesn’t.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Right, exactly. It’s much easier to buy entire media companies than...</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...to try to play wu-mao.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Fair enough. The other half of this that I really want to get into is the use of...When the Cambridge Analytica story broke, everybody was talking about psychometrics and how they’d scraped all of this Facebook data. Do you think people’s private Facebook data is easily available for sale in Taiwan now? Or was it in the past?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It depends. For a while, Facebook was very lax in what kind of data is shared. Around the time which is also when Farmville and related Flash games, were very popular. It coincides with the initial round of mobile phone apps. I think people don’t really have a social norm back then. It’s very easy for a app to ask for all the permissions and have the user accept it.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Now of course with recent end to end iOS, it’s no long possible. The first time it asks you, you bet it has a really good idea because otherwise the user will not click to authorize a dozen of permissions, because it’s on an as needed basis now.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The design of the original, I would say, prototype, Android especially, mobile phone systems coupled with a more lax privacy policy created a much easier to access snapshot of people’s state back then. Of course, people grow. It’s been years now. It’s no longer very up to date. They’re irrelevant now, if you’re talking about evaluation of voting behavior, that is. People’s name, of course, may stay the same now.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>I’ve talked to a couple of people in Taiwan. When I’ve asked them for practical things the Taiwanese people can do to keep their data safe, they talk very heavily about anything coming from China. You should never put WeChat on your phone. You should never use a Chinese phone. Do you think these concerns are overblown?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No. Even if you use an iPhone, if you don’t use two factor authentication, or if you use a seemingly very useful, but actually there’s no privacy policy and so on, if you download the wrong app, even if you’re using an iPhone updated to the latest OS, it’s not guaranteed that, because, after all, at the end of the day, it is your personal data you enter there.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Part of our Digital Communication Act, which is now under debate in the legislation, and we expect it to pass soon, what we say is that it’s important, it’s mandatory even, for those platforms to publish their privacy policy in a user understandable way to be accountable for the choices they make and things like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What we ask is transparency. We’re not saying the government is rating the apps from five star to one star, but we’re asking as the bare minimum that they’d be responsive and accountable to the privacy policies and actions that they take. This is the same direction that’s taken by the European Union when it comes to their disinformation or misinformation principles.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It is up to each user to choose who they trust. It is also up to each user to choose reputable vendors that has a good privacy policy. I certainly wouldn’t say that the nationality is the only or even a major indicator. There’s many other indicators. The lack of a privacy policy, for me, is a huge red flag.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you think the act goes far enough?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m sorry?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you think the act goes far enough, the privacy act going through legislature right now?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s several acts the Digital Communication Act for one, the Cybersecurity Act for another. There’s also the very specific action acts like the Anti Harassment Act and things like that. Taken together, we try to strike a balance.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In Taiwan, freedom of speech is a core value. It’s not an instrumental value. Anything that we introduce, it can only empower the citizens instead of doing decisions for the citizens. The entire idea is working with the people instead of for the people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>With the people direction, I think we’re going pretty far. There’s still a lot of room, especially around education and media literacy, but Taiwan is definitely leading Asia in this particular regard. There are many other Asian countries going other directions, and they’re going very far.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Those are not the direction we’re going.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Especially Malaysia now. Who is collecting the most data from Taiwanese citizens?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>LINE and Facebook.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>The LINE and Facebook? True.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Nobody has been able to give me concrete numbers on this. I’ve talked to a lot of people who have said that many government agencies had their own Facebook social data scraping, Facebook and other.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Some of them, yes. They look for specific keywords. It’s not about private profiles. They just look at the public posts, and they watch specific keywords.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you have any idea how widespread this is?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>It’s pretty widespread.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>It’s pretty widespread.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>At least a dozen agencies or ministries are paying companies to do this kind of keyword monitoring for them.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Individual election campaigns, presumably, will have their own operations.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I have no idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>You have no idea?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’m not running.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>You’re not running?</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>I’m over that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Despite rumors to the contrary, I know.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That would be misinformation. [laughs]</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Cambridge Analytica themself, their parent company said on their website that they’d worked for some campaign in Taiwan somewhere around 2010 or before. Do you have any idea who this is, or do you know anybody who might know?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not at all. As I said, I’m not involved in election at all.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>You’re sure?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Not even in the previous campaigns. My only role is that of a voter.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>[laughs] Fair enough.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I really don’t have an idea.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you have any idea who would be overseeing this or who would know about this specifically?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The individual candidates, especially after 2014. Many of the candidates and the major parties, they all have specific departments related to Internet’s public relationship and things like that. If you’re talking about 2010, I don’t really know. I don’t really know, yeah.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>OK. What advice would you give to ordinary citizens looking to keep their data private?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Check for privacy policy and always use two factor authentication. If you’re using a messaging system, make sure it’s using end to end encryption. If you’re going to a website, look for the HTTPS lock sign. It’s just very, very rough cybersecurity advice is. Actually, not clicking past this is insecure website screens, I think is one of the habits.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>One of the thing that I did when I become Digital Minister is that we asked 25 interns last year, 35 interns this year, to check for the desktop and mobile versions, respectively, for all the government websites and services. We’re upgrading everything to secure HTTPS.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re making sure that as part of our service flow, regardless of which device you use, you see the same experience and not having to click through insecure warnings and things like that. If the government makes a habit for people to ignore those warnings, then when they encounter real, malicious cyber attack or phishing attacks, they get a wrong habit.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They get used to clicking through Java warnings as part of filing their tax system. That was the case last year for Mac and Linux users. That was a really bad thing to do. Today we have completely rewritten the Mac and Linux tax filing system on many other systems.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>What I’m saying is that the government should not ask its citizen to perform insecure actions. We tried to let citizens see that as red flags, instead of things that are just a nuisance for people to just click past.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>What else have you been working on lately?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Lately, I’ve been working on AI related policies. There’s an AI banking, fintech sandbox, that’s already passed by legislation. Just this week, we’re going to work on the AI mobility sandbox on crude vehicles like on ships, cars, and drones.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re going to have a what we call a regulatory co creation environment, where people can experiment of co-domestication of AI mobility agents to establish a social norm around safety and explainability together. It’s fascinating area of both social and technological innovation. We’re working with the legislation. Hopefully, we’ll send it this week.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Great.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’ll be updating our plans in AI Taiwan. That’s ai.taiwan.gov.tw. There’s many other web pages, smart.taiwain.gov.tw, bio.taiwain.gov.tw. That all ends in gov.tw. It’s using a more modern aesthetics. We’re very aware of that. We’re working on that, too.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Speaking of that, how would you rate Taiwan’s e-government right now?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think it’s pretty good at the service level, the responsive level, the way it works on mobile. The few cases where it’s not working, I said that 35 interns around Taiwan as we speak, are now doing service check to make sure that all the government websites and services are mobile friendly, accessibility friendly, and things like that.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>However, if the service is in English, it may not be as good. [laughs] It’s sometimes not updated in time. It could be very unfriendly. Or it lags behind. Or you can’t find things. Or even if it’s in English, it’s not phrased in a way that native English speakers would use. You have to guess what it actually means. Normally, it’s actually easier if you go to Chinese website and use Google Translate.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>It really depends on the government department, too, in very unexpected ways. The agriculture, the website’s perfect in English.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yeah, it’s very good.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>The National Police Agency, it’s godawful.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Well, which is why we’re working with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. This whole taiwan.gov.tw domain belongs to the MOFA. The MOFA did not work that closely with all the different agencies. Just as you said, the one that really has a sense and works very closely, but the one doesn’t. Doesn’t even know there is a resource that they can use.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re now working with all the different agencies to try to give the English presence on the web a more unified look. Also, a better updated way of getting the target audience something relevant to them, instead of pushing essentially just fliers [laughs] into the website. Yeah, I’m painfully aware of that.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>How important is English? Do you have any idea like when people access government websites what percentage is in Chinese? What percentage is in English?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Yes, we do. I think that one of the things is that we have to really strategically use Google Translate. We see more and more people if they use Chrome, they just automatically go into an English version because it’s machine translated</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think a more strategic use of auto translation, a more strategic use of accessibility guidelines, because if everything is in PowerPoint, or PDF, or just plain images, then there’s harder to translate for the current generation of machine translators, I can do to make it easier.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>The very simple thing of being things as text, things have a readable alternative text, and things like that, that massively helps not just blind people but people who rely on automated translation. We’re not saying that anything have to be painstakingly hand translated, but we’re making the whole website more amenable for Google Translate and other automated translations is what we’re saying.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Do you think you’ll stop with English?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No. If it’s Google Translated...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>If it’s Google Translated...</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...all English related languages.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Even if it’s Arabic or Klingon, if you’re using Microsoft Translator...</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>...as long as we have the right infrastructure, I think it would go very well.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Especially now with the New Southbound Policy, we now have that more of our people actually are working with the Minister of Economy and so on to make sure that we have a targeted portal for if you’re in India, if you’re in Indonesia, and so on, that the website doesn’t look too bad even if it’s translated into local languages.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Admittedly, it’s still a long way to go compared to English, but if we do it in a more universal, what we call internationalization, instead of just localized to English way, then it will pay off for all the different languages.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Back to social media literacy, it’s getting taught in schools, presumably, now. I had a journalist call up a couple of schools. They haven’t implemented it yet.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>No, because the new curriculum takes effect next year. All we have now is pilot classes.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Where are these pilot classes?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>You have to look up the National Academy of Educational Research. You can contact the NAER directly.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>That’s for younger people, but I feel like older people are the problem. What can be done to get older people more media literate, more tech literate in Taiwan?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>They can spend more time with younger people.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Fair enough.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Other than that, I think education is the lifelong thing. Recently, Minister of Education said that even if you’re already going through adulthood, you can easily get back to a college and apply for a up to 10 years program.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>University or college, including the normal universities, and also what we call experimental schools now up to university can apply to be experimental as well. Also, community colleges, they’re the three pillars of that, should and it’s already engaging with the public more. If you want to look into details, the key word here is University Social Responsibility or USR.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This year, we’re expanding the last year’s USR program into what we call 高教深耕, the deep cultivation of higher education so that they work as a community center, open up a lot of the literacy programs and other programs to people around their university as a community rather than just people who apply for their degree.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I think the USR program will also play some role in making sure that everybody has access to the latest thinking around media literacy.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Is there anything else you want to tell me about this subject? These are my questions.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Many of this is, in Taiwan, I would like to emphasize that, for people who are of an older generation. It’s not just digital transformation, because in other countries, when we talk about digital transformation, it’s mostly from paper, a non-interactive media to a screen, which is a very interactive media.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>In Taiwan, there’s also a change of thinking from an authority based political system and education system to a more communication based education and political system. That is unique in Taiwan. Spain went through something like that. Now some Asian countries are going through this.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>By and large, in Taiwan there is a very coinciding timeline where the Internet, personal computers, democracy, and lifting of martial law happened in the same year and created a very huge divide between the generations educated before that year and generations educated after that year. I’m caught in the middle.</p>
        </speech>
        <narrative>
          <p>
            <i>(laughter)</i>
          </p>
        </narrative>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>People younger than me don’t remember martial law, but I still do. It is our generation’s social duty to make sure that both generations understand each other, where they’re coming from, and then together face this new kind of media landscape.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>This work, if done correctly, it’s not just digital transformation, but it will be a transitional reconsolidation between the different generations’ take the role of authorities play in the society.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>That’s very good even from a transitional justice viewpoint. It’s very good because, frankly speaking, for the young people, many of them can’t understand why this reliance on authorities is so big for the older generations. For the older generations, that’s part of their natural education.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>I see. Great.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’re good?</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Those are my questions.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>I’ll send you a transcript.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Great. I’m going to publish on Friday.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
          <p>We’ll publish afterwards.</p>
        </speech>
        <speech by="#Morley J. Weston">
          <p>Awesome.</p>
        </speech>
      </debateSection>
    </debateBody>
  </debate>
</akomaNtoso>
