<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<akomaNtoso>
    <debate>
        <meta>
            <references>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Michael Connor" id="Michael Connor" showAs="Michael Connor"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Yngve Holen" id="Yngve Holen" showAs="Yngve Holen"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Ross Goodwin" id="Ross Goodwin" showAs="Ross Goodwin"/>
            </references>
        </meta>
        <debateBody>
            <debateSection>
                <heading>
                    2020-09-23 Conversation with Michael Connor and Yngve Holen and Ross Goodwin
                </heading>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Excellent. I’m glad you were able to join in. I know that the meeting schedule moved around a little at the last moment there. Time is a flat circle.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It’s raining outside, and I was just like, yeah, it was crazy.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s good, good.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Great. There’s two things…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Hey, here’s your headset. It doesn’t rain, the XR.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In XR, it never rains. Well, when it rains, it doesn’t get wet. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        So it’s been all of no wind.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Wow, that’s an art form in itself. A collage, a collage. We call it a collage.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        This is a sculpture. This is a sculpture.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right, Yngve sculpture. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        That’s amazing. Let’s go through the state of play about a few things before we get into VR or anything. The state of play is that we had originally thought that we could work towards a recorded presentation today, which at one point could even have been live.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        As the conversation progressed, it became clear we needed more time. We are still in a planning conversation today, of course. We’ve been recording the planning conversations throughout. We can hopefully use some clips that are interesting or relevant when we have final edit to make.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        The conversation so far has been revolving around a few different kinds of avenues. ETOPS was a starting point with Yngve’s magazine, which is the conversation-based magazine where there are conversations around a topic that are printed without authors being identified.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        The conversation began with the idea of extending that magazine into a format that was facilitated by machine learning, databases, or other things. That seemed to take it too far away from ETOPS as a very conversational, interpersonal project. That was part.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Through that conversation, we did come onto just wanting to experiment with machine learning in general. The update on that is that I have given a number of Minister Tang’s speeches to machine learning artist Ross Goodwin. Ross is available to jump on the call with us today to talk about some ideas for experiments around that, just to see if there’s anything of interest.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I want to say that Ross, he’s got a very fast-moving mind. He has a lot to say, so maybe that should be the last part of the call. I’m not sure maybe that we need to make an excuse to sign off at a certain point. I’m sorry, this is being recorded. I shouldn’t be so defensive.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m fine as long as Yngve is fine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Ross, he does really have a good, thorough knowledge of using text corpuses as creative material for AI projects. He will be able to give us some insight into what the possibilities are.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        The other part of the conversation that was quite fun was the XRSpace part, which we all know about – of course, Yngve’s had quite a process getting his headset – the idea being some sort of encounter in XRSpace.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        As part of that, we came upon the idea of the background of the 360-degree cinema being a possibility for a format that Yngve could explore that might align with some aspects of his work.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Those are all of the things that are on the table. It’s probably fair to say that none of them feel like a final project exactly necessarily at this point.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve and I had a conversation this week, Minister Tang, where we were talking about what our presentation will be like given that we’re coming to the close of our time altogether.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It seemed like it could be of interest to have the presentation happen in XRSpace as an experience, less than necessarily like a finished project. Within XRSpace, there could be a conversation around the topics that we have discussed, the two of you talking about your own practices.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Perhaps we can create some backdrops that would happen within that that we could use as prompts or just as [inaudible 5:10] material. That does leave open the possibility that, in the spring, the Kunsthall Stavanger show is still on the table.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        There is still the possibility that either the machine learning or 360-degree carpet aspects could be further developed by everyone collectively or by individuals within the collaboration into things that would be exhibited.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        There’s still the possibility of developing something further from this point, but it’s maybe good to start thinking in terms of just having an interesting presentation and less the final product. That said, we can see how today goes. Maybe we’ll get there.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Is that a fair summary of everything?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I want to add two things I thought about. I don’t even know how it looks like in XRSpace because I was on the outside. We have to find a way to record the inside in some way that looks…Maybe it’s also OK to be on the outside and look at it if we have a conversation on the inside and we have carpets and stuff, but I couldn’t see…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Oh, right. That’s great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I was outside. Now it’s like…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        That is a crucial problem in that. Anyway, keep going.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Maybe we could see what’s possible there. That’s why I’m excited to get into XRSpace, because I don’t how it feels like.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Second thing I’d like to…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        [inaudible 6:49] go through the motion of setting up your avatar and stuff?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I haven’t. I just got it [inaudible 6:56] .
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That will take a while though. That will take 10 minutes, 20.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        To make an avatar?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, to make an avatar, choose your likeness, and get acquainted with the controller or hand gestures. That would easily take you 15 to 20 minutes, just saying.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Probably two hours, if I know myself. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, it’s fine. It’s really easier than other VR pieces, but still there’s some learning curve.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I’m excited to see that. That’s why I wanted to ask. To the AI, the machine learning part, I was thinking yesterday the AI is now fed with a set of data from Audrey Tang. With the GPT…I always forget it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, GPT, that’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I didn’t know how to ask a question. It’s a hard thing to imagine how you can move with it or play with it. I was thinking maybe I also need a set of me in there, and we can have a conversation where they just bounce back and forth like a conversation forever. There could be a conversation from Kunsthall Stavanger, basically.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, that’s right. It takes forever to prepare for the show, and the show is just this forever preparation. I like the idea.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A dress rehearsal, a hash mark day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It also solves the problem of all of the time zone coordination that we’ve had to do. If you have synthetic beings that are able to carry out your conversation for you, it makes scheduling easier.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, that’s right, [laughs] exactly. Before you joined, Yngve, I was sharing with Michael a few digitally scanned assets from the Taiwan Digital Asset Library. For example, this is a famous temple, and there’s many temples like that in the Taiwan Digital Asset Library.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m showing you this temple only because it makes sense in the context of a very Taiwanese thing called lottery poetry. I don’t know whether you’ve heard of it. It’s basically a set of randomly generated fortune cookies writ large, larger than average fortune cookies.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You will come to the temple with a topic in mind, but you don’t necessarily have to say it loud. Then you draw one of those lottery poetry sticks, and it contains an auspicious message or something. It’s always in a cryptic form like a sphinx.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then you pay for the service for the temple scholar to interpret that lottery poetry for you. It’s a very Taiwanese thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        What’s the best thing about this is, of course, that it’s a pre-generated set of randomly generated poems, but it could be interpreted to mean anything. This interpretational part is like the assistive intelligence part that Michael was referring to, basically, treating me as a generator of lottery poetry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s a very apt metaphor that totally works in Taiwan, but probably doesn’t work in other places that doesn’t have this culture. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        We have star signs, right? There’s horoscopes every day. It’s not so far away when my partner wants to read me my future, [laughs] “Pardon me,” I’m like, “I’m a Taurus. I’m this star sign that’s least capable of believing in star signs.” Whenever I said, “It’s not my thing,” it’s that thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        This is very interesting. I also like the format of those papers. I also think it’s a nice way of…They almost look like bigger labels or something like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s exactly right. It’s in the form of hiccup poems. It’s interesting, and it’s very conversation, interpersonal. The parts where maybe having two avatars will work. One will basically generate a poem, and the other will then interpret.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then we will keep talking about the message generated by the prompt from the individual seeking, I don’t know, fortunetelling. Now we become fortunetellers. Anyway, that was just an idea I was introducing to Michael as he joined and just for context.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Also very printable. I could just imagine the printers somewhere just spitting out the…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        This is really interesting. I’ve heard of other randomness-based practices connected with Taoism and Buddhism, but I hadn’t heard of this before.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The most famous one is the national fortune lottery poetry. At the beginning of every year, this Grand Temple draws out what will happen to the country the next year. It’s a thing in Taiwan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Lottery poetry, it’s beautiful. It’s a nice…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It even rhymes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I’ve got a last subject, just collect a bunch of interviews that I have done in the past. I think she can turn them to, Michael, and maybe that’s something. I don’t know how that works, but maybe that’s something that can generate these two.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It’s definitely possible. We should get Ross on to talk through that in some more detail. There’s a lot of nuance to it but, yes, Yngve, if you create a corpus or we can create a corpus of your text, it’s absolutely possible for you to have an AI that replicates your voice in some strange way.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        If somebody needs to ask the questions or direct the poems in a way, I wonder if it would also be done in that way. If I post…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I wonder if we should make a decision because Kurt is available to record our XRSpace interaction. Are we deciding that I should tell him we’re going to postpone that? Or should we try and…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It depends whether Yngve already has an avatar now. From what I have heard, it’s not even set up yet, right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Should I try to do it on XR?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You’ll have to, for example, install an app called XRSpace, pair your phone with the XRSpace headset and all that. It takes time is what I’m saying.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I think we should say that’s not going to happen today. Maybe that’s a good moment before we get further into the lottery poetry/bot idea with Ross. Maybe we should just finalize our last schedule. We have scheduled in Sunday at 6:00 I believe.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Which is only a few days from now. Yngve has some conflicts coming up on his side, but I think there are a couple of other windows if we wanted to try and move that meeting a bit later to give, for example, Ross more time to prepare material.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I think you had another window or two, Yngve, that could work. Minister Tang, can we check with your schedule now, or do we need to have Zack on-hand for that?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I can speak for my schedule. If it’s not a Sunday, of course, it’s even better.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It’s better? OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s better. I never schedule Sunday. I made an exception for this.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Thank you. Yngve, you had some other possibilities?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I have to be in Berlin on the first of October. I have a plan with meetings then. After that, it’s hard. I don’t know how we can do it, but I’m down in Europe in different countries to try to do all my meetings by car. We’re like COVID times.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I will be in Berlin…It depends on how I drive down from Oslo to Berlin. I could be in Berlin the 29th, the 28th, and have full free days to do that recording. If you would do it on the 30th, it’s double as much time as we have now through Sunday. That’s two more working days, which are weekends. I don’t know. Some people don’t have weekends, some people do.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        30th, your time is the first of October my time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It would either be the 1st in the morning or the 30th in the evening, so whichever…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The first, in the morning, is easier for me because it’s a vacation day, and I don’t have anything. If we schedule for the 1st and in the morning, I can be up as early as 7:00, if that works. I can also do afternoons.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If you’re in Berlin, that would be 7:00 PM my time and noon your time. That will also work if it’s in the 1st of October.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That would be the 1st of October, that would be the 30th of September for me?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, it will either be 30th of September for you late in the night, or it could be also the 1st of October for you around noon.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Around noon. OK, let’s see. Better for me late at night, yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve, I think if it was 7:00 AM for Minister Tang, it would be 1:00 AM for you, which is quite late.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, it’s actually quite late.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        OK. Could we do…I have a meeting at 12 o’clock in Berlin. It’s a physical meeting, so I look at the architecture. I think I’m finished at two o’clock. Is that 7:00 in the morning to you, 2:00? That doesn’t work that way, right? Two is…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If it’s in the afternoon…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        That would be 8:00 PM.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …then it would be 8:00 PM for me. If it’s on the 1st, then it will work, but if it’s on the 30th, it will not. I have the entire day of 30th booked.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I could do on the 1st, I could do…OK, that’s a stretch. I think eight o’clock in the evening, right? That would be eight o’clock in the evening for you, OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s fine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        That would be 2:00 PM for you, which is a little close to your meeting. You can maybe have a slightly early start or so.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I can stay longer into the night too. I’m fine. If it’s on the 1st, I’m fine the entire day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        What about 3:00 PM for you, Yngve, on October 1st?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        And 9:00 for me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        3:00 PM is OK. I could do 2:00 PM. 3:00 PM would be perfect, yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK. Basically we meet at the same hour, like today, or an hour earlier?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Same as today, or earlier if you want.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Same as today. Maybe half an hour earlier if that works for you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK, so 8:30 PM for me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK, I can do that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. Do you want me, if I then could do even half an hour earlier to let you know, or should we just…It’s easier just to say 4:30. Then it’s safe.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Are we talking about 3:30, Berlin time?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        2:30.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        2:30.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I thought Yngve was saying that 3:30 would be easier for him, which is like today but half an hour earlier…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Oh, it’s so complicated. I never get this right. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If you can do 2:30, that’s actually preferable, and still that would be 8:30 for me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, I can do 2:30, no problem.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Very good.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK. I am sending you a calendar invite just to make sure that we all are on the same page. Which is probably a good thing to do in the beginning of this, but now that we are toward the end of this, it doesn’t hurt. I have sent both of you a calendar invite just to make sure that we are on the same page.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Thank you for doing that. That would have probably helped all along, for sure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Norway time. Great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (child speaks)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Nico, I’m on a phone call. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (off-mic speech)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        …where were we? I think I’m going to tell Kurt now actually that we’re not going to make it into XRSpace today.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background sounds only)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Oh, I just realized I muted myself. I’m interested in the question of whether things in XRSpace can be scriptable, because that might bring these two ideas together, if it’s possible to create a bot in XRSpace.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I have a feeling that bots create this potential for abuse and for bad language. That might be not ideal for XRSpace, because they can somehow absorb things in their training that might be not good for content purposes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Mm-hmm.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I’ll ask the question anyway.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background sounds only)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        There’s this just something completely different. There’s this one sculpture in Taipei, which is kind of like my favorite in the world.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Oh, yeah, the Meat-shaped Stone. We have a pretty good 3D scan of that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        You have pretty good 3D scan of that. Maybe that’s the one with me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Maybe we can look at that too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know why. [laughs] It’s a cool object, huh?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. It’s even in the Nintendo game, the “Animal Crossing.” They offer an Animal Crossing version of that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Oh.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I’m trying to find a good resolution version, but there is none. I’ll just paste a random photo here. Basically, the Animal Crossing community in Taiwan gets a free license from the National Palace Museum to basically carry those open data from the Palace Museum.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If you’re interested in the 3D scans that are Animal Crossing resolution, here’s the open data part, right? [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] OK, wow. It’s in the back there, right?.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, that’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Oh, yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        The one next to it, I saw the one next to it but I didn’t see the meat one when I was in Taipei. I’m so disappointed myself. How could I have missed that?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Now you can import it to XR and look at it all day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know what you do with it all day though, but it’s there for you to look at. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Very cool. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Cool. Should I see if we can get Ross on the line now?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I think it’s a good idea.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I think it’s time. OK, give me just a moment. Let me give him a quick call.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Mm-hmm.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background sounds only)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] He is muted there.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Kind of cool.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think he’ll join us through the Skype.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. Michael muted himself. That’s good.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Nice.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background sounds only)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        You know more how about these things work than me. I’m really new to this. We have understood from your mail that one part of the set was something that you actually used for what you call format, or structure, or how it’s going to look like, right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. There’s a content and there’s the style. It’s technically called a style transfer.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. That’s like four lines, five lines, or like…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Exactly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I see. Two columns, one column. That’s graphic design. It’s just column A…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. It’s the same thing. It’s the same thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We get to practice our lip reading, how I try to read Michael’s lips. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        How are you?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Ross to be on in just a moment.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve, you had sent a number of parameter of different topics you wanted the Virtual Minister to talk about, I think. I’d shared this with him. We had a chat last night about where he’s gotten up to. I think he was specking out different approaches to how to train something.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Maybe one of our big conversations is about a freelance, something that can respond to live, or if it’s something that can generate texts in a more synthetic way or something. I guess he’ll give us more information when he is on in a moment.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I like the idea of the two bots being in conversation as continuation of…I wonder if actually we could use the corpus of this conversation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I actually did that in my previous job, by the way. Like literally. There’s an Easter egg that I put in my previous job, and in all the customers that installed that piece of software, there’s a special point not advertised anywhere which it recreates. If you refresh, it generates randomly again.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The real conversation that we had when making the product together in the memory of Ken Pier when he passed away, my way to mourn him was just to get all the IRC chat logs and generate this virtual conversation. If you refresh sufficient number of times, you’ll probably see my name, which is Au in the chat room, but you will also see our project manager, Adina Levin, our fellow developer, Luke Closs, our fellow QA person, Matt Heusser, and so on.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s almost like we’re making the product over again. It’s in all the Socialtext instances all around the world…. This is the first time I said this on record.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Wow.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Was that repeating the exact scripted conversation or was it generated from…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Well, if you keep refreshing. That’s actually my first deep learning project using just character level RNN when it came out.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It’s actual stuff that’s been written to each other. It’s not developed. When you refresh, it takes you to different pages in the project. 2007 jumps to 2008.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. That’s not our actual conversation, but it could have been.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Oh, it’s generated.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s machine generated. It’s our avatars talking to one another.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I see. It’s based on what you all talked about, but then it’s just randomized like that. I see.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. There’s no trade secret to being divulged.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Exactly. It’s just a feeling or the…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The atmosphere of working.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That’s nice. [laughs] Can read it on for a long time. It’s cool. What is an Easter egg? I don’t know anything about programming. Is it…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        An Easter egg in the software is a function in the software that’s not part of its specification. When our customer bought the software for Socialtext, they buy something like Slack. It’s a productivity software. Nowhere in its menu or nowhere in its product description says you can actually generate some lottery poetry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s off menu. That’s what an Easter egg means. It’s also harmless because it doesn’t do anything bad to the product. It’s just unadvertised. One of the more interesting Easter eggs is that it used to be in the 1997 version of Microsoft Excel, you can actually open a flight simulator.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In Microsoft Word, you can open a pinball and so on. There’s games embedded in those productivity software that you can trigger if you know the right commands.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I see. It’s beautiful. I like it, the Socialtext Easter egg. Ken was the person who was passed away?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Ken Pier was the person who passed away. It’s my way to remember him.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (pause)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Minister Tang, I know that GPT-3 is considered a gold standard for machine learning right now and it’s the open AI version. When I spoke with Ross, one of the main topics of our conversation was that he had a number of other possible reference…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. It doesn’t have to be GPT-3. That was just this saying that if you want photo realism, something that is passable, like passing Turing test stuff, GPT-3 is where it’s at. For the chat log that you’re looking at right now, that’s just elementary software that anybody can run from a personal computer.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        A more simple approach could also yield good results for something like this.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s why lottery poetry, to me, makes more sense than, say, a five-page essay because for an essay to work, it has to be self-consistent. If it’s a short poetry, the consistency is in the readers’ minds.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Hello. Can you hear me?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes. Hello. Greetings. Good local time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I really can’t…Great. Hello.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Hi. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Sorry, it’s early here. It just got light. Can everybody hear me? I couldn’t hear you for a second there.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I can hear you just fine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I can hear you, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Mic is muted. Oh, no.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’m so sorry. I just woke up. How late am I? I hope you aren’t waiting for a long time, but I apologize if you were.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        We were talking about the matters, Ross.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Great. Nice to meet you all on a screen as we do everything in America these days, wherever you are.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        So glad you could join us, Ross. Let me give you a quick recap of where we’re up to with things, OK?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Please, yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve and Minister Tang are in the midst of their Seven on Seven collaboration, where we pair artists and technologists to make something new, as you know. Conversation has been a big theme of their collaboration and also poetry. Let’s say that those are two things that have been talked about a lot because they relate to both of their practice in different ways.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Along those lines, just to give you a bit of background, we have talked about a couple of interesting concepts that might relate to a project, ultimately. One is the idea of lottery poetry, which is a randomized poem that tells a fortune in Taiwan, or in a kind of Buddhist or Taoist tradition. That’s something that was maybe one point of inspiration.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        We’ve also been talking about trying to meet in virtual space through the XRSpace headset.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        There’s been some idea of virtualizing characters. It’s been a theme of the conversation so far.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        In relation to both those things, the idea of trying to synthesize one or more of us through text corpuses has become an idea we want to explore more. That’s where I reached out to you, and sent you some of Minister Tangs texts to start with.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        What we want to do with that is something we should discuss. Maybe at this point, we should weave to the side questions about the technical process that we would use to achieve difference. Maybe just talk a little about what we want to achieve with this and what you think some possibilities might be. You had yesterday really to get on board with understanding the corpora.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I have a pretty good sense of it now. Sorry, go ahead.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I guess we want to explore either generating texts in the style of this corpus or even potentially having conversational entities that you could interact with.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        There’s a lot of interesting possibilities in that arena. I guess now that I have a better idea of the media that the output’s going to exist in, can you be more specific about the XR’s headset thing that you mentioned?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That was mostly because of the corpus. Is it you’re using that as an example of something, a place this could go or…?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        It’s the example at this point, but it’s something that…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Got it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        We all have the XRSpace headset now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        What’s the venue and the intended audience for this? Is it just worldwide on the Internet? Is it a specific location?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        We’re going to be recording a conversation amongst the three of us. In the conversation, we will demonstrate some sketches or ideas potentially towards a larger project.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        This wouldn’t exist as a live piece of software for people to interact with online at this point. It might develop into that in the future as we talked about.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        What we’re interested in is something that we can use as a sketch or demo of an idea potentially, even if it’s like to say we tried this and it didn’t work out, we would just want to give an example through it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        You mentioned different entities. Is that the desired direction here, that it’s like we’re showing…I don’t know. I really like the idea of working with someone who’s alive in order to represent different voices that they might write with or different types of deconstructions of a person’s writing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        When you’re dealing with an individual, it’s quite different than dealing with a group of people, let’s say, who are all writing together or who are all writing separate work. Documents that are studied in the field I work in, I suppose, to the extent that it’s like a unified field.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        We don’t think about the fact that like Wikipedia, which is what GPT-3 is mostly trained on or the Internet as a whole is not an individually authored thing. When you reduce the number of authors, quantitatively, you end up with an interesting opportunity to…A lot is said about the way that crowds can speak and a lot of work focuses on crowds in different ways.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        There’s a lot of visual paradigms and text conversational design paradigms that have to do with speaking to an archive. If you flip that on its head in this case, which is probably the best way to go because you have relatively…Even Noam Chomsky who’s the most published author in English, you really can’t train a neural net with just his work.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Neural net as big as GPT-3 requires the work of millions of human beings. I guess the thing is that I would love to think about how to elevate.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Have you seen the movie “Inside Out,” or is that a popular movie where you are, with different voices inside their heads?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course. I refer to that movie all the time when I explain the humor over rumor strategy of disinformation fighting.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        This is just an example. I haven’t actually seen it. I’m just familiar with the overall concept of the film. I guess if the idea is to associate the individual with influences, that could be really interesting.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’ve been thinking a lot lately about the cognitive science of parallels of just the type of deep learning stuff that’s happening right now. It’s very interesting to consider the ways in which we as individuals, we’re certainly more complicated than GPT-3.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The question that I asked the folks I know at open AI is what about GPT-300? What about GPT-3000? At what point does it become an entity that you’re talking with on an equal footing?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The design that reaches toward that reverence of the model or the thing that’s speaking can be a little bit treacherous when we’re dealing with one person’s voice. What I would say is that there’s some interesting routes in terms of visualizing data that have to do with isolating influences and bodies of work.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Think about if GPT-3 in that style of model is like a tree and, at the top of the tree, you have all the work on Wikipedia and the Internet that filters down into GPT-3 or whatever. I’m using GPT-3 as an example. If you have one person’s work around them or this corpus, for example, of influences.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I would like to do something like clustering on it to identify labels within the subject, within the corpus, prior to doing topic-based generativity in a particular mold that’s in the spirit.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I guess the question is whether we could condense or expand this work. Are we trying to remix? Are we trying to create an alternate version of it? Or, are we trying to expand it?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The goal, obviously, isn’t just to create a walking, talking humanoid robot of any kind. It’s like what’s the design vision beyond…I’m sorry, it’s very early and I’m still brewing coffee.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Go ahead. Interject. Jump in.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        What you’re saying is synthesizing a textual entity through machine learning is limited because the entity is really being driven more by Wikipedia than by the fine-tuned data of, for example, Minister Tang. Is that what you’re saying?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Is that different when you do a…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I apologize for going too deep about it. I was trying to stay on the surface, but it’s hard.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Is it an advantage in that case?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Do you all mind I brew coffee while we’re talking? I really need some coffee.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Please. Go for it. We all want you to have coffee.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I hope you don’t mind. It’s going to leave me a lot more coherent.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Go ahead and brew while I ask questions. The problem is that when you use machine learning or GPT-3 or whatever, you’re bringing in all these other voices. They might be voices that are actually really inappropriate.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Exactly. It’s like if you’re using GPT-3, then you’re putting a big Elon Musk stamp on the project, essentially.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Is that problem less if you use something more simple? You mentioned Markov chains in our previous conversation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        It means much less empirically. I would say like LSTMs, BERT is associated with Google. The truth is that there’s versions of it on GitHub that are not…GPT-3 is brand name ones. It’s all marketing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        What you’re really looking for, part of what I was telling Michael is that part of the marketing of these models, these big models that are being sold to business interests is like, “Oh, we’re not really going to give you a name or technology, we just hope that our name becomes like the Kleenex.” It’s really annoying actually. That’s what’s happening.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Just before you joined, Ross, I was just sharing my first project with the character level RNN, and that was like five years ago, to mourn my coworker in my previous job, Socialtext. All I did is to put all the IRC logs of us working together.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        On the second link is an Easter egg that I put in the product. If you keep refreshing that endpoint, you will see an endless stream of IRC conversations modeled loosely after the actual IRC conversations we had with Ken.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I took all the IRC logs and then focused the character level RNN only on the parts of Ken’s speaking and the surroundings, the contexts that prompt Ken Pier to speak.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You see occasionally my handle at the other co-workers, but the focus is on Ken and also Mac Ken, which is the nickname Ken used when he used a Mac. It doesn’t have any knowledge of Wikipedia or anything like that because it’s a small corpus and it only has character level linkage.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Still, the timestamps and all generated is quite convincingly IRC. That’s the kind of self-sufficient model with five years old technology now that we can reliably get was just to stay at corpus.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I was just telling my Michael that if you don’t want to bring in GPT-3 or BERT, that’s entirely fine. We can use even our preparatory conversations as a small corpus and still generate quite coherent stuff.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s great. I love AI and working with AI interest in these tech companies. I have a lot of friends in tech now. It’s not that I have an antagonistic relationship with them in any sense. It’s more that I like actually working under the umbrella of computational creative writing more than I like working under the umbrella of artificial intelligence.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        When I can just call it computational creative writing and not AI, the audience doesn’t have expectations that are unrealistic for like, “It’s a walking, talking person and it serves you drinks” or whatever. That’s like the Boston Dynamics vision. Go ahead.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Go ahead, Yngve.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        The beginning of this conversation was that we were talking about the magazine I was doing which is called ETOPS, which is like a Q&#x26;A anonymized magazine on one topic. Audrey said something that we could just generate into magazine and very quickly fill out these pages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        My interest was in her job description. It’s so accurate and so distilled, and not a cumulative…which isn’t somehow also like what ETOPS is. It’s actually more going a place, meeting the person, having the conversation and just…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Got it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        …distilling it down so you get the essence, anonymizing only because certain interview objects that you will have will have been talking about…The last one was about neuroscience, and then you talk about a famous person at the Max Planck Institute in Germany. The interview you got would be the same interview that he would have 20 times already.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s an interesting idea for a XR thing we could try. Now that I have a better sense of this being a conversation-driven thing, primarily, as the concept, because that’s sort of what I was looking for, was “OK, we’re trying to represent a conversation.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I think what’s required here is more deconstruction, perhaps. That’s just an idea I have, sort of in the way you might present…I’m digressing too much, but what I guess I was going to say is that this…Do you watch the show “Rick and Morty”?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        They do a scene that could be represented interestingly…You know the unity episode, where Rick is walking down the street talking to everyone, and it’s all the same person?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        What if it was a group augmented reality experience where…And this is another idea. I really don’t like headsets when you don’t have to use them. I think that we’re overly reliant on screens, and especially during COVID. If the plan is to make this on the Internet, then obviously, it has to be on a screen.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        If the plan is to make this post-COVID in order to play so people can gather…I went to this beautiful skeleton of a performance once in Amsterdam that I think – it was a performance. It was just more music-based and dance-based than conversation-based. Everyone had these headphones that were all synced up.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’ve always wanted to do something with that media, and I think it could be done remotely or in person, where everyone wears headphones and there’s a synced set of conversations where they’re paired in spread algorithm.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        There’s a third person in each conversation that is the individual that we’re working with, his writing or his conversation. Basically, there could be a third voice in the conversation. Then I think how the voice works can be sort of opaque.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Really, the approach that I would use, I’ll talk about with Michael if you didn’t hear about it, something called Tf-IDF summarization scoring. I would literally use sentences verbatim, and insert them in smart ways into the conversations, but make the AI part of it for conversation pairings.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        We can do some generativity on top of that if there’s a desire to have poetry or something original that is said. But grounding it in quotes is going to be important to represent the individual well in this case.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        What I don’t want is for the AI to be kind of an expressive system that doesn’t represent the seriousness of the person behind the words initially. It’s not about necessarily that they’re serious words all the time. It’s more about the AI can misrepresent tone very easily.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I think what you said just now, Ross, is that it’s possible to do a slightly hybrid model where it’s largely remixed. But then maybe…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (child cries)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Oh, are you OK? Come here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Is this your child? Oh, my gosh.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background noises)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, so I think that a hybrid approach could be good. Maybe we have to make some decisions about the format that this would occupy from the side.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Maybe that’s a good point to let you go and make coffee, and get ready for your call with Germany. We can pick up the conversation with just a quick…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        There’s 10 minutes. We already had a prep for it yesterday, so I can keep talking for another five, just so I have little more direction here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Do we want to delve into this more, Ross, or do we want to quickly…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, I could also drop off if you want to settle the question of what the media is. The venue and the audience, I think is a really important question. This is physical versus virtual, it’s totally different.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m sure that XRSpace will be happy just make this a permanent exhibit because they will get more users. Of course, few people in the world currently owns a XRSpace headset, so it will a really privileged exhibition. We’re looking to present the primary exhibition as something that could be easily projected in places, that is to say probably as a film-ish thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s amazing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m telling what I heard from Yngve last time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        One idea I’ve been throwing around a lot is the idea of a movie that’s very long or possibly never-ending that anyone can be in if they just log onto a website and wait in line. It would be funny if you could do a version of that as a conversation with the minister.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Sorry, what were you going to say?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A 10 years’ conversations, like a movie that’s exactly 10 years long.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, some magical realist amount of time. I’ve wanted to do something like that for a long time. That’d be very cool.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I did like the idea that someone had a few minutes ago of it being this conversation replicated endlessly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. We just take 10 years to prepare for 7x7.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That’s a nice way of describing it. I like that. I also like the format of the lottery poetry because it’s like in blocks, right? You have these lines, it’s ready, the next one is ready, the next one is ready. It continues, it’s cumulative, but not in the…just open version it’s like…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It goes more into what you talked about, minting something in the digital realm. How do you fix something? Or, like a building block that you can’t take away. That’s what I like about the lottery ticket format, poetry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s stochastic.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. The way I talked about doing this from before, the tech is pretty simple. There was a question we reached. The first question is, “Is it in real time?” That adds complexity. The simplest way to do it is to have a system by which people are uploading clips, and then they construct it, but that’s less interesting. You lose some glitz by losing a real-time aspect. “Is it real time?” is one question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The next question is now much context does each speaker get? That was where I got stuck on this before. In the Web interface that everyone sees, which maybe is different for every individual person, which is pretty easy to do, there’s a bunch of unique URLs. That’s the simplest way to do it. You could have a actual Web app of some kind as well with a framework. That takes a little longer.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The main thing is that everyone gets their own version of the site, essentially, or everyone gets the same version. Then everyone gets the version, and then Oscar Sharp and I, when we discussed it, we’re like it sort of changes the dynamic, because then everyone can see the script in real time as it goes by.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        It’s just different if you only see your lines versus you see everyone’s lines, that’s what I’m saying, or something in between. Then the question also is how far into the future do you get? Are you getting the whole script in a window, are you getting the next page, are you getting the next few lines, the next few words?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        It’s a question of how much text to give to the person. It’s a pretty simple UX kind of…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Which person do you mean?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        …thing. The user, the person who’s going to be experience this installation or whomever, the audience.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Right, but it might be that the script is recited by some sort of entity. It might not be…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        It’s a performance?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Maybe a bot performance.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        If it’s a performance, then it’s a performance. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Back in the…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Or text-to-speech.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …Easter egg, I generated 20 to 30 lines of chat log at a time precisely because that seems like the right amount of closure for each random lottery. It’s around the right number of lines to fit something on the page too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I would be happy if, as a window in time, just like with the time stamps, that’s actually quite easy because it implicitly takes you back. We can also use the same technique, except it takes us forward to the future. You get to see a future version of Audrey-Yngve talking endlessly about possible topics to explore on 7x7 for the next 49 years or something like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Each time you roll the dice, you see a snippet into that window. You can, of course, also prime it with your own theme and so on. I would suggest it’s very limited. Just contribute one sentence into the conversation between me and Yngve, which we will treat as if you have introduced a conversation topic. Then we have some conversation around that slash poetry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That makes a lot of sense. If it’s performance-based, the vision is yours, essentially. I’m here to assist in whatever capacity. It’s hard to say.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’m running into roadblock in my own work, I have to be honest, at certain points these days, because the technology is moving so fast now with respect to language modeling that, as soon as one thing arrives, it’s almost like the next thing is already being talked about, well in advance of the first thing being available. That happens over and over again.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        We’re past peak AI in a way this time. That’s really kind of startling. I don’t know. These are interesting things to think about with respect to interface. I’m sorry if I’m getting too abstract here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve has something to say.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’ll stay calm. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I think we should get more abstract actually. I think we’re almost too much on the format at the moment. I come from a very classical perspective. I work with very, very slow medium. I work with glass and materials, high-tech stuff.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, very slow.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know if we’re even going to be on the panel, me and Audrey, talking about the project. I think it’s almost going to be a prerecorded thing. I also don’t think it needs to be a finished project. Just going back to the poem, what interests me with the poem that was the starting point from that is that it’s basically a job description as a poem.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It’s like a misuse of format in order to say something very precise but also keep it open, which is very special. This printed, it could exist…basically the alphabet together is the materiality. Whether it’s a performance or, in one year, a printer prints it out or somebody recites it, that’s up to time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        What I understand as format now or talking to Audrey is that in order to achieve a result, we have to decide a format in terms of how many lines or how big the thing is going to be. Is it a A4 page? Is it three lines or four lines, the structure of the things. Sorry if I use the wrong words here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        For me, at this point, it’s a question of where the boundaries are on this knowledge graph. The way to think about working with a language model is that you’re never just working with a language model. It’s always embedded in a system of some kind, even if it’s really simple.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        A chatbot, for example, that’s not just a language model. It’s also a UI. It’s got a visual element, probably, and literally just audio or whatever. If the deliverable is a document, that’s very simple if it’s a job description. My question as an artist is what’s the presentation for the job description in that case that you imagine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know yet. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        You don’t know yet. That’s what we’re discussing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Do you have a vision for that? Can you speak to that at all?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, I announced my job description as a tweet. It’s set in this Front Desk sans font. That’s the canonical presentation form for my job description.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        OK. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yngve, go ahead. What were you going to say?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I understand more and more now that different corporations creating AI, language tool, whatever you want to call it. What I don’t want to is we create something which is making Audrey Tang just scanning Wikipedia, which is super boring. It needs to be the most pure, crystal form of Audrey Tang. We need to have a conversation which is real, like the poem is real. It needs to come from a real place.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        What I would say is, if you wanted to be really faithful, then it’s a question of whether the ideas represent…Work involving artificial intelligence can say a lot of different things. By default, it always says something about artificial intelligence.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        My question is, is your vision here AI scary or is it AI good? I’m not making a value judgment. I’m asking you, by default, what’s the attitude about AI? Is it positive and playful or is it…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        My default attitude is assistive intelligence.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Assisted intelligence, OK. That makes sense.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In the sense that we’re all blind and deaf in some regards when it comes to understanding a holistic topic. AIs are assistive just as assistive technologies are. Basically, it restores us to a shared reality for collaborative learning about human experience, through a plurality, on the Internet of beings. That’s what I mean by assistive intelligence. It’s also in my job description.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I really like that ontology. That’s a nice way of encapsulating it that’s refreshing compared to what I hear usually. Engineers have a hard time encapsulating what they’re working on sometimes, even the smartest ones. I would agree with that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The other way I’ve heard it said or the buttress to that I’ve heard from people more inside the industry is every augmentation is also an amputation. That’s the caveat to that worldview. You’re going, “OK, if we’re going to go trans-human, then where do we stop cutting things off?” If it’s true that…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I see where you’re coming from. To me, assistive brings, with a default, like when you’re caring for someone with different disabilities. The idea is to restore human dignity, not to take away their agency from them.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The two important thing about AI, which is value alignment and accountability, goes with this assistive objective. That’s what you would expect to assistive person to a disabled person. They need to be value-aligned to them, to their agency. Also, there needs to be accountability for the decisions made on behalf of that person.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think assistive captures the twin aspects of accountability and value alignment, for me, when it comes to AI.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Absolutely. I always point to the example that the typewriter was originally invented as an assistive device. A lot of my work, camera stuff, has been called assistive in many ways because it’s assistive devices that are for everyone in a way.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s definitely a really cool worldview on technology. I think a lot of people are waking up to that worldview, at least most of the reality, if not the whole reality. Humans have always used tools. It’s a really old story.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Tool-making is what separates us from monkeys in a way, or whatever our primate ancestors. It’s a blurry line if you look at the science. My dad’s a paleontologist, so he knows a lot more about it than me. I think that technology’s always been embedded in our species.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        The more woke we are to that, at least the less likely we are to be harming each other with our technology and our pursuit of it. If we’re aware of what it is as a societal addiction to doing things better and better and better, in certain contexts like AI represent very dark, old urges in the aggregate.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        It’s like this idea that, “I want to be lazy. I want to have a robot do all my work for me.” Really, we have to be more collaborators with our tool systems in the end, no matter what.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Ross, can I say something here?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, go ahead. I have to go in second. I’ll let you all talk. If you have one more, if you have anything else, tell me. I’ve got to go in five minutes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        The question of condensation of a less corpus corpus seemed like a crucial issue. I know that in Yngve’s work, the accumulation is less important than the distilling of something. I think a lot of machine learning, because of this training aspect…I’m just drawing out this dynamic, but I can’t finish my thought for some reason.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        That’s all right. My coffee still is not finished. It took me five minutes to press the button.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        We have Taipei… I know in Taipei, but where are you again, Minister Tang – in Taiwan, I mean?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m in Taoyuan at the moment, at a social innovation summit, and, interestingly, using 5G connection at the moment because the WiFi in hotel, I don’t have the password, but that’s fine. 5G is as good as fiber optics.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I was going to say, if you’re on a data connection, that’s really crazy. Yeah, wow.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In Taiwan, we have unlimited data plans. Actually, anywhere in Taiwan, even on top of Taiwan 4,000 meters high almost, you have 10 megabits per second guaranteed as a human right for unlimited data, like US$16 a month. Otherwise, it’s my fault, personally.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’ve never been. My close friend from MIT, his mother is Taiwanese, and he goes a couple times a year to visit her family and his family there. I’ve never been. I’ve always wanted to go with him. One of our friends who has a little more money than me does go with him to Asia sometimes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        I’ve only been able to go a few times, but the trips I’ve gone on with him so far just to Korea. That’s it recently. I went to the Philippines a very long time ago. I’ve wanted to go, come back to somewhere on the continent. I’ve heard a lot of amazing things about Taiwan from my friend Dan, who is a close friend from college.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Ross, we’ll say good-bye and thank you. We’ll send some further notes. I’ll send a recap after we finish. Good day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Ross Goodwin">
                    <p>
                        Thank you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Good morning.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Bye. Live long and prosper.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Quickly to round up, [laughs] Yngve, why don’t you give us a debrief on where your head is at right now. We had an interesting concept with just continuing the Seven on Seven conversation as a synthetic entity. It seemed like we pulled back from that concept. Where are we now?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Where are we now?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        You’ve too much to think about, but…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (pause)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It sounds difficult to use those. It sounds easy and it sounds difficult. It has to be very clear.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I’m very afraid when I hear Wikipedia, and it’s just searching the Web to randomly take content. It doesn’t sound like the right thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Of course, I always get very alert when people start talking about formats, performances, and equipment in the exhibition spaces because it’s a very little…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        To be clear, we’re looking for a format for some experiments or one experiment that we can discuss and assess in a sense. It’s like a public experiment, not a finished work at this stage. I wanted to clarify. Ross, he’s obviously obsessed with the really deep structure of artificial intelligence.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        If you create a character using GPT-3, it’s not that you say things directly from Wikipedia. It’s more like a style that comes across.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (child yelling)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Nico, I don’t have sausage sweetie. I have cucumber. I have sweet potato, I have smoothie.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (child yelling)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        She wants sausage.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I would love to be able to give Ross some kind of instruction to do some experiment. Then we can see what it’s like.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, we can do that. If I could add something, I really like the format of the lottery poetry. I just don’t know. I like it. I like even how it looks.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s very self-contained. I really like how portable it is.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I like that you could also potentially print it out and give it somebody. I even like the fact that you have pay for the interpretation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] A consultation, right. The first one is free.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] I could go in that direction. When I looked at it, I also liked that some had two lines and some had four lines, some had five lines, but that’s just a graphical thing which I liked, that they’re bigger and smaller and say more, say less, but it has a max or something like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I think that’s something. I don’t know what it should be, if it’s you speaking or we asking a question and there’s a question-answer type thing and a thing like that. The question-answer doesn’t make sense, and maybe that’s the poetry in that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It’s hard, but I would like the sort of thing that writes these things to be trained on Audrey’s writing and not being an intelligence that then gets a question and just swipes through Wikipedia to tell you what time it is or something like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We can limit the answer from my current transcript corpus, which already have more than 50k, 45k-ish speeches. That’s more than what we need. If you read through all that I sent Ross, then there’s more than enough. We don’t have to consult any other external sources.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        In some way, it could be like, “Oh, there’s so much. I don’t even know how to read through it.” That was first feeling when I got that link. It’s so much, I just jump in here. I remember I spoke to my studio manager, and I said, “It’s just so confusing. It’s so much information.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I tried to send her something that she should read, but then she was reading something completely different. We talked about half an hour, reading different stuff, talking about different stuff. Maybe there’s a way to for me ask you questions.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Then again I wouldn’t want my questions or the simple questions that I wrote in May, which was just to kick start something, to go somewhere. At the moment, I wouldn’t want that to be defining the whole programming. Then it’s programmed, and a bit like, “Oh, I don’t know enough, if that’s the right way to…”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I have a lot of topics, not so many, 10, 20, something like that. I could feed them into something.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That will work. For example, if you have a input, through very simple math like the Tf-IDF Ross was just describing, we somehow decide a lottery is the main topic of your input. Then it can very simply just run a search. Then if you click the link I just pasted to you, you will list exactly this many times that I mention lottery in my public speech.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then each of them can be seen as a kind of lottery poetry. If the machine draws one by chance, then it may or may not have anything to do with the actual topic that you’re talking about, but at least it solves the voice problem because it actually came from one of my conversations.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        But it would be a copy-pasted thing. It wouldn’t be a new combination of things.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        What I’m trying to say is that all the different times that I talk about lottery are not, of course, the same topic. In the link, I first talk about a receipt lottery, which is electronic. I talk about sandbox application which is like a lottery in reverse. If you run just a search result and combine them into a poem-ish thing, then it actually takes a index life on its own.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The challenge is how to make sure that it fits actually the poetry lottery format. The idea is that each word or each short sentence, if you click on it, actually takes you back to a word that I actually said. The link would be at word level, not at copy-paste level.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I say this with some experience because when I was 20 years old or so, I would log into the Perl chat room on a IRC on the chat space, and I wrote a bot. Whenever it sees me type river run, it would just pull randomly from Finnegans Wake a certain paragraph and to insert into the conversation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s almost like poetry lottery because Joyce always has something relevant to say. It just pull random sentence out of Finnegans Wake. The corpus that you see here is roughly at the length of Finnegans Wake, actually longer. If I can do that to Joyce, I’m sure that other people can do that to me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Sometimes in my work, topics are really banal. Topic is about the experience of flying economy class. If I could ask, could I get something out of it…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course. That’s the whole idea.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That would be super cool. [laughs] That would be very fun, actually.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        How do we…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (background sounds only)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Guys, do you still hear me?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I still hear you. I’m just…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        With no formatting whatsoever, if you just said flying economic class, and then I just do say a search for the three words, because we were saying word level links, that the raw result will be like this, which I can read out. I can say I fly out Saturday early morning, something like that, in the free economic pilot zone. Exactly. Now, it’s just 15 or 20 per class, and that’s much easier.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s not quite an answer to your question about flying economic class, but it’s really random sentences that somehow combines just in a freestyle way that talks about flying in the economic and the class. This kind of software, I’m sure that Ross can very easily write.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I guess the first, I fly out Saturday early morning, something like that, is copy-pasted as a whole or it’s just put together…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Currently, it’s copy-pasted as a whole. We can also decompose it so that it’s not a whole copy-paste, but rather a sentence level thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        In some way, the project could be asking topics and using all of the writing of yours to then generate a certain point.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Just for the record, here are the three links where the three lines came from.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I see. Now I understand.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s just for the record.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It’s good just for me to understand it. I never spend time programming. I understand structure in different ways. [laughs] This is interesting. Cool.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Could we link this in some way to the XRSpace? Is this something that…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, we can read it out in XRSpace.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        If it’s in the cinema, we could just watch…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. We can watch with a backdrop of pretty much anything. I can perform some of my answers, I guess, with my digital avatar. You can also recreate, say in your avatar, “What’s it like to fly economic class,” and that will feel quite natural like me and you having a conversation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That could be cool. That’d be nice to have, because we are pre-recorded and then we have something that’s we have a conversation in space. It’s already visual because we recorded in XRSpace. That takes up how it looks like. We don’t have to think so much about that, except how we look like as avatars, right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s exactly right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Mike Connor will present the project as a project in creation. We just have to see how we tweak it now so it feels right, feels good, and performs what we want to. Maybe it would look like the lottery poetry on that screen. Maybe it’s pass-along.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We can definitely model that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It doesn’t need to have an engine font like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        It could be simpler. Cool. Is Michael still here or he left?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Michael is still here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Hi.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Hi.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Hi.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Are you good?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I caught just the last few couple minutes. I was just carrying around my laptop but it wasn’t plugged in so the battery died. It sounds like you have a way forward.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        I guess at the moment, it’s just this one idea that because there’s so much writing poetry that the way of interweaving, it needs to happen by some artificial intelligence. The way that needs to be something…You can probably explain it better than me.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        We just went through something where if I asked the question, if would ask something, how it is to fly economy class, then there’s probably ways to use a word…What do you call it? The word prompt, the word…?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The prompt. The three words as individual prompts.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        That’s going through the database. Putting it together, we’d get three sentences out of it. We probably have to work in it so it looks differently because there’s just three copy-paste happening here, taking the three words together. Every word makes a sentence, I guess.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Is this going to be us doing something or no?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Is it going to give us something? I don’t know. I was thinking maybe it’s possible to be in XRSpace and just look at random poetry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course, because there’s a browser in XRSpace where people can browse Web pages together. If we put it together as a Web page or as a video, we can watch it together.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Just searching for a way where we could access something like this online and already use just the XRSpace as the place where we are with our avatars. That’s the visual thing that’s pre-recorded for. If it’s a project yet, I don’t know but it’s a conversation that happens. It has somehow…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Some parameters to get somewhere at that’s…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        I’m just trying to make sure I understand what I need to do but I can probably watch back your conversation up to this point and get my instruction from it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. That’s the beauty of recording.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Maybe we’ll let you finally get to sleep, Minister Tang.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sleep sounds like a good idea. [laughs] We can put it like that. We really do have something here that’s very doable and also fun as well, which is always the most important part.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It can be a very simple random numbers of pictures that we just watch together in XR, which is like that three lines formatted like a lottery poetry paper. That will be something. Generating that sort of thing from the corpus is well within Ross’ capabilities.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        If we were, for some reason, to find backdrops or images to illustrate it, then I would have no problem searching the Internet with AI images, but the writing should be pure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Should be pure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Cool.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Are we good?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Do you want to meet me, Michael, to meet in that space at some point? I know you’re busy right now but we could do it like…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Michael Connor">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I’m available most of the day today. Just a little bit distracted right now, but then I’ll be OK again for a while.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I will go to sleep. We have something red — that’s not herrings — for once. Thank you for the collaboration.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’ll sign out here. Cheers. Bye.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Yngve Holen">
                    <p>
                        Take care. Bye.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Bye.
                    </p>
                </speech>
            </debateSection>
        </debateBody>
    </debate>
</akomaNtoso>