<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<akomaNtoso>
    <debate>
        <meta>
            <references>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Brian Tseng" id="Brian Tseng" showAs="Brian Tseng"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Old K" id="Old K" showAs="Old K"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Slido Comment" id="Slido Comment" showAs="Slido Comment"/>
            </references>
        </meta>
        <debateBody>
            <debateSection>
                <heading>
                    2020-01-18 Conversation with Brian Tseng
                </heading>
                <narrative><p><!--
                                <script type="text/javascript" src='https://amara.org/embedder-iframe'></script>
                                <div class="amara-embed" data-show-subtitles-default="true" data-initial-language="en" data-show-transcript-default="true" data-url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CrO8MROMhpQ" data-team="null"></div>

                --></p></narrative>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Welcome back to the Night Night Show. Dear viewers, our next guest is truly special. Solved simultaneous equations at the age of 8, started a company at 16, retired at 33, and is the youngest minister without portfolio in Taiwan’s history. Let us applaud for Audrey Tang.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Minister Audrey Tang, welcome to our show. You are the first bring-your-own-device guest here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        I was very worried that today you would only send a robot out, and then you would not arrive in person.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If you want that, we can arrange another recording.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Right, I remember I asked if the robot could come.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sure thing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh really, okay, next time… uh, no next time, this is the last episode… I just realized that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        This interview, I want it to be different from the past. We used to take care of the audience following, their mood, and whether they laughed or not.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        I don’t want to do this at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        What do you mean?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        I just want to chat with Audrey, Okay?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The host sets himself free.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, I don’t care at all, because I don’t have another episode, I don’t care.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No problem.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You have watched our show before. I have openly shown my love for you. Have you seen that?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Did you say super like?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, super like.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I have seen that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Everyone wondered what that was about. No, I just wanted to express my love for you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Thank you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Why… a bit reserved. So… you have watched our show. Why would you like to be on our show?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Because I support a new political party: Can’t Stop This Party. Since you are a party member, and because I support the party, I should also support the party members’ programs.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        In other words, if I hadn’t joined the party, you wouldn’t have come?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, so guessing that game was important then.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Wow, it was so close. Fortunately, that game, I didn’t…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …win.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        It was definitely not set intentionally. So, we actually have a lot today… I myself have a lot of questions to ask.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Can you really control other people’s brain waves? Before you answer… (puts on a foil cap)
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I read an article like that in the 2016 Journal of Current Biology, which said, “Intraspinal Sensory Neurons Provide Powerful Inhibition to Motor Circuits Ensuring Postural Control during Locomotion.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You see, brain control, brain, control. One of the co-authors of this article is our Brian here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh my gosh, you dug out my master’s thesis… I won’t be affected by your remarks!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Whose brain did you control at that time?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        It was zebrafish.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Zebrafish larvae, right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Uh… larvae… Yes, because they are called larvae, larva, anyway, the little zebrafish share the same word as larvae.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK. So even when zebrafish were little, you kept controlling them through cerebrospinal fluid?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, not little, but before they were born, we messed up with their nervous systems.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Before birth. You implemented brain control in the fetus.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Wait a minute. For this whole part, you really didn’t care about the audience at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        No care at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        You were just chatting away.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Are you saying that I am the one who controls the brain waves?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, in fact, Brian is the capable one.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Then you don’t control other people’s brain waves?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, in front of Brian, I dare not say that I could control others’ brain waves, because you have actually done it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh my gosh, I already started to believe it!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        (Removes the foil cap) OK, no, no more nonsense.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But indeed for many… you know that many old people have the impression that you are like an all-seeing eye, all the time… you monitor everyone’s iPhone, right? Is this true?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course not. My name is TANG Feng.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        A homoFENGnic joke came straight out.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Do you have other rumors to crack? Because there are many legends about you. Do you know that you are much like the Chuck Norris of Taiwan? That is, Audrey Tang is so clever… that… “Audrey Tang realized the truth before God wrote it down,” things like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, I think the most important thing is that my name has now become a verb.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, really, someone like that?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A transitive verb.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Meaning?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It means that something has been removed and taken down. For example, if someone asks me a question on Slido and finds that question is gone, then that is the so-called “being Tang-Fenged.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, being Tang-Fenged.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        When a noun becomes a verb, it means that it is beyond my control and has become a concept that everyone can use.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Just like we don’t say “you go to the search engine to find it,” instead, we all say “you Google it.” This is called “verbing” a noun.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        How do we know that this is not part of your plot?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Alas, this is a very good question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If this were part of my conspiracy, we wouldn’t be talking about it here at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh yes, because you brought it up. But how do I know that, a level deeper, this is not part of your bigger conspiracy to let us find out?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, we know that the title of Brian’s thesis is “Sensory Neurons Provide Powerful Inhibition.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This means that when we talk about it here, no one will think about anything else! This is Brian’s conspiracy.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You really know how to… that is… make nonsense…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Do you feel like you’re turning into a zebrafish?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yeah… I’ve started to… doubt everything I did before.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Talking about… because we just talked about something beyond your control, and you are passionate about AI or that kind of technology, right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I was. Before entering the cabinet.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Like Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla, he worries that AI will dominate the world eventually. Don’t you have this worry?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It should not be so. Because our AI at this stage, I usually call it Assistive Intelligence, like an assistant.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The most important thing is this: it’s like a secretary who helps you decide all kinds of itineraries, but when you ask them why, if they never tells you, then you will actually fire them.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This means that the current situation of our human society is that AI can only do auxiliary tasks, and we don’t actually put it in a position where auxiliary becomes judgment and a boss.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So as long as we keep to this bottom line of privacy and accountability, i.e., to protect one’s privacy, and to be accountable, just like an assistant. Thus, it is impossible to dominate the world.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But now the way AI learns by itself, similar to the neural circuit of the human brain to learn. What if…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Suppose we hard-code the idea of privacy in their hardware. But it transcends it because it learns that, “I can surpass human beings, and I want to override this instruction.” Wouldn’t there be such a day?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That is a very good question. It’s like “how to contain the Genie in the magic lamp.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So the simplest is that you don’t want this magic lamp to have an opening at all. It’s like when you are driving, sometimes you look at the navigation. If you don’t connect the navigation to your steering wheel, that’ll do.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In simple terms, do not connect the cerebrospinal fluid to the motor circuit…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Don’t go back to my paper any more! Enough, Enough, there is no such meaning at all!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But seriously, if one day humans go to war with robots, whose side will you stand on? Because I will absolutely choose robots.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course I’m on the side of modern Homo sapiens… Well, we split up right away.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Really? No way!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        No, I think that if humans… like cyborg, if we put some machines on our bodies, we can definitely break through the ceiling.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Right, so the most important thing here is that if Assistive Intelligence develops into so-called Augmented Intelligence, then we actually feel every day, like, the cell phone seems to have become a part of our body.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A situation like that would be augmenting our existing social norm. Just like we wouldn’t say simply because I wear glasses to correct myopia, that somehow makes me a non-human cyborg.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In the future, when everyone can have the same augmented intelligence, human society will become better as a whole. The focus is still the same: We cannot leave some people behind, while only a few people becoming the kind of cyborg you just described.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So in an imaginary future, because that boundary will become more and more blurred, if say, later, that we can repair the organ by implanting some machines, and then there will be a degree of transition from human to robot.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You mean, in the future, everyone will be in the middle. Let’s not keep dividing…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, there is no need to wait for the future. It is happening now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        People in places with broadband access, for example through 4G signals, are not the same as those in places completely disconnected from the net.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In the first case, we can use livestreaming and real-time collective intelligence tools to make decisions together, etc.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        But in the other case, you can only communicate by shouting. If no one is close to you, no one will hear you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Therefore, the concept of “broadband as a human right” means that if broadband is not available anywhere in the whole society, the people there would be excluded from the democratic society. This is why “broadband as a human right” is one of the most important policies of our government.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Wow, connecting to the policy. This is really great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        An advertorial opportunity.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, I have no idea how many people got that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But I think… first off, we broke the premise of many sci-fi movies, that is, humans will go to war with robots, we said that we would be in the middle. However, another issue rises, the system. In places without broadband access, some people may fail to catch up. Is broadband a human right?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Broadband is a human right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        It is in the future, then…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Right now, it is a human right in Taiwan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Even on the northern peak of Yushan about 4,000 meters high, you can still get 10 megabits per second with unlimited 4G for 15 euros per month, and you can still livestream, maybe faster, because fewer people use it there.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Makes sense. Wow, this can, by the way, solve the problem of urbanization and rural depopulation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Exactly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Awesome. This reminds me that we did talk about 5G here. The question we asked was that, if most of the technology is concentrated in big companies, like the United States, of course, there are firms like Qualcomm, but Huawei still accounts for a large part.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We also have Mediatek, which makes SOC (System-on-chip) here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So we are capable of developing 5G capabilities independent of oversea manufacturers.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, of course, because now we look at the situation of the bidding for 5G, we can already see that this year it will enter our lives.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In that, I think the most important thing is that 4G is fast already now. 5G will be faster, but not very, very much, it will be a bit faster.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The sub-6 band, which would be the first one to start with, is about 10-20 times faster, though it has an important advantage: Low latency. It’s like that if we are now chatting through video, from the point you nod to the point I see you’re nodding, it’s called micro expression. In fact, the brain only takes about 1/60th of a second to complete the process.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        But if there is a delay in the process, I would feel like talking to a virtual person. This is why most of the time we say “meeting in person builds 30% of trust,” but video meetings only builds 20%.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So when 5G reduces the delay to less than 1/60 second, meeting through 5G also builds 30% of trust.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Understood. We have just covered quite a few key points. Don’t you think 10 to 20 times faster is a big improvement? You think it’s a small…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s all right, it’s OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know if we need to be modest or something. But you can look forward to Taiwan in the future. Do you think it will step into 5G within a few years… Because there is still a problem with the base station. Is it because of frequency? It requires very dense base stations. Will there be no problem with land use?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This is actually fine, because after the passage of the Telecommunications Management Act, we have actually adopted the so-called co-construction method, especially in non-metropolitan areas.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The so-called co-network and co-construction mean that one base station can serve several different base providers. A lot of technical characteristics of 5G allows us to deploy the base stations in a test field, and we don’t need to fill them all at once. For example, the Shālún science city…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …everything is over there…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …it’s now a self-driving test ground…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …right. I just visited the Taiwan CAR Lab there.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, exactly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So we have to cover the self-driving tracks first, because the vehicle-to-vehicle communication cannot tolerate a 1/60 second gap.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        But when you get out of the car, it’s okay. Why not wait for 1/60 second?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        When we talked about self-driving cars, I really wanted to ask another question. This is a question on tech ethics.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Self-driving cars may run into the trolley problem. If the car can’t stop itself, should it kill the driver or…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …just don’t drive so fast.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh! Makes sense. Just set a top speed, then self-driving cars won’t encounter that kind of problem.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK, but we can only say that it minimizes the chance, and we can’t say that it will completely prevent this from happening.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, because there were these self-driving vehicles around my office, the Social Innovation Lab, at #99 Section 3 Ren’ai Road…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …you don’t need to spell it out, OK?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        …tell it all…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …you don’t have to run open government to such an extent…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …well we actually tore down the wall there so you can walk in directly from the roadside, it’s really quite open. Anyway…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …not interested, really…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …this office you are not interested in, there were all these alien-looking things roaming around all day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        These are actually self-driving vehicles, and they are tricycles. Thanks to our contributors, the tricycles gradually became this attractive, two-eyed, capable to read human expressions…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Very cute.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …cute like this.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Although tricycles in nursery rhymes run fast, in reality they are slower than a jogger. So it’s not about lowering the probability, it’s that nothing will happen even if you really run into it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes. Just now, I don’t know how many viewers got it. Audrey actually jammed a few things in those words, without even caring if anyone got the reference. How did you achieve this equanimity?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Equanimity? Very simple. Like a good novel, you always have to read it a second, third, and fourth time before you see the deep meaning.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Every time we go back to it, “Ah, I found another one.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, it is like a game. If you cracks it at the first try, you won’t play it any more. For higher replay value, put lots of easter eggs.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, but the most admirable thing is that you put them in so invisibly. We put them deliberately, and even then the audience may not buy it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Like in an interview with “Deutsche Welle,” you said, oh I remember Taiwan’s breakaway…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Neolithic Age.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …was at the Neolithic Age. Was that one you had thought about before and was ready to put there?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, not at all. I just responded casually, and then answered his real question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Don’t you just feel that other people are dumb?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Not at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Because when I’m talking to you now, I have a kind of inferiority complex. I am afraid to ask some questions, afraid that you would look down on me…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, this is because we are meeting for the first time. This is quite normal.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        I am touched.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Your words are really heart-warming. Old K wants to say something?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Once you have meet each other a few times, you will get used to it. You will know that you really are dumb.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Old K has been hanging out with me for two, three years now. My reaction is really quite slow, isn’t it?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        During that segment, I was just thinking about what we should eat in a little while…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        I’ve decided that when I go home I will play this segment at 0.75x speed on YouTube and watch it slowly…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …yes, everyone can do it, really, including this segment…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …YouTube can play it at 0.25x speed.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        By the fifth replay, I’ll get the jokes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, and then write a response saying, oh I know, I got the joke now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Audrey, rumor has it that your IQ is… 160? 170? 180?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That 180 is in centimeter only.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        180 in centimeter only? Okay, brilliant.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s the appropriate unit of measure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Because IQ is meaningless in adults and anything above 160 cannot be measured anyway, I just don’t talk about it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Is it really true that you can’t measure an IQ above 160?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, in WAIS…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale. It doesn’t continue after 4 standard deviations?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Indeed, it doesn’t go up after that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        How strange, okay. So, how relevant is IQ in the future? Should we be concerned about this matter, or is it not…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think by now, especially now, IQ is completely meaningless. Because for most of the things tested in WAIS-III, you only need to have a mobile phone. It doesn’t even need to be online. Even in places without Internet access, you only need to have installed 5 apps. Memorization forwards and backwards, turning 90 degrees, and so on, your phone can solve them all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        To put it simply, as long as anyone has a mobile phone in hand, their IQ is already above 160, and so cannot be measured. With this in mind, IQ is the least useful thing now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So really, technology can dismantle many previous concepts.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        We have just talked about policy. I don’t know if it’s a topic your staff would like you to talk about, but let’s talk about the future. After the election, what can we expect our country to look like in the future?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You have taken part developing the 108 curriculum, which is being rolled out now. What about the 108 curriculum? Currently, many people are very hesitant. They are worried and have no idea what this idea of “sùyǎng” is about.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Is is right to call it “sùyǎng?” What does it mean?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, the word “sùyǎng” is a part of a translated term. The original term is “competence,” from “core competence”.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Why not just translate that as core “nénglì”?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Right. Because we needed to overcorrect something.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Why overcorrection? Because for more than ten years, people in Taiwan translated the word “competence” in “core competence” as “jìngzhēnglì.” However, that word actually means something else: “competitiveness.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Competitiveness is only meaningful if you go to run a race, and when someone wins, there is a first, second, and third place.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Competence, on the other hand, is about applying what we’ve learned in everyday context. Like teaming up for a common purpose. Everyone in a team contributes their knowledge and skills. Each person has a different set of competences.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So competence is about cooperation, whereas competitiveness is about competition. Because we used to translate both as “jìngzhēnglì,” schools focused too much on competition between individuals, which is quite meaningless once you graduate and form a team, except when played for laughs in a certain show.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, the audience gets it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Audrey did it again, you see.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But the premise of this is that once you graduate, it is not a zero-sum game. It is a team competition… well not competition…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        …team cooperation…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …but why…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Teams are competitive with one another.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        True.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        But within a team, it is mostly cooperative.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So as a teacher, you need to show how to cooperate within a team, and how teams compete with each other.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Understood. The other thing that everyone questions is the so-called urban-rural gap. I think this is relevant to the 108 curriculum… because…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Let me talk about the premise. We really wanted to make an “Èi!” episode for the 108 curriculum, but I think it’s still too early. Let’s wait until this batch of high school students take their first exam, just before they face the exam, the real problems will be highlighted. Moreover, there are very few videos at the moment…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        My key point is that people worry about the gap between urban and rural areas. They feel that there are many self-study courses. Teachers who teach these courses are concentrated in the cities, and none is in the rural areas. How do we solve this problem?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think there are two aspects to this. On the one hand, the net can replace the road, with co-teaching across schools. We have a teacher in one place. This teacher, while not necessarily a domain expert, is very capable at understanding students’ learning motivation. Over the net, maybe through a wall-sized projection, they may be connected to an expert teacher in another city.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, just upstairs from my office at #99 Section 3 Ren’ai Road, people are learning indigenous languages. In the morning, children can choose to learn the culture or language of any indigenous people. Yet, of course, it is not possible to send such teachers, e.g. from the Sakizaya people, to all of the dozens of schools in Taiwan. That’s why they have a green screen, and the culture of various indigenous peoples is continuously projected in the back. All the children can then form a learning community with the indigenous peoples through this dual-teacher projection. This technology is quite mature now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Secondly, it is not necessary to use knowledge-based teaching. Students can also go into a local area and work with people in the local community, community colleges, community development associations, etc. as school-based courses. Even in class time, what in the past could only be done in the community or the eighth class can now be taken outside the campus and directly brought into these fields for practical experience.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        There is an advantage to this. The local culture can be passed onto these children. When they grow up, and if they want to study a specialty, such as monument restoration, they would learn skills that are useful to their own local people. If they haven’t learned such skills in twelve years, then after going to university they probably won’t return to their hometown, because what they study are of less relevance to their hometown.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, you have mentioned two points just now. I think the first point is that if technology can really bridge the gap between urban and rural areas, in terms of hardware, doesn’t it mean that our government should ensure that everyone in the countryside has the hardware to connect to the Internet before they can accomplish the things that you mentioned?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This is exactly one of the goals in our Forward-looking Digital Infrastructure program, and its implementation rate has reached 100%.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Brilliant. Brilliant. Yes, my question has been answered.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        The second question, though, is that if each urban and rural area has its own characteristics, wouldn’t that impede the mobility? Because what you learn in one place is what you can use in that one place. If I want to move to the city, I…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …can just move to the city for further development.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        But I can’t learn it, or did you say that you can learn it online? OK. Alright.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s why when we talk about regional revitalization, we used to talk about community building, and it often took a lot of young people, maybe eight or ten, to build an ecosystem in that community. Yet, nowadays, sometimes one or two people go back, and through the net, they can connect everything about design, copywriting, and marketing to the online community. That’s why it only takes one or two people to go back…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You’ve just said connecting to…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Online communities. Now it only needs one or two people to bootstrap a regional revitalization plan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK. Let me ask one last thing: Disinformation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Our show has discussed how to respond to disinformation before, and our solution is to knock everyone out. When you can’t tell the truth from the false anymore, you won’t be impacted by disinformation. Of course, I am standing by what we’ve said previously. I believe this is a great way.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In other words: No appendix, no appendicitis.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. This interpretation totally makes sense. However, I know you, Audrey, have provided a solution to counter disinformation by responding with memes?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, memes are a little bit like knocking others out. Yet, first things first, they don’t cause irreversible damages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Seems fair. Clever.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        When your party just formed, I sent a flower basket. The flower basket was full of catnip.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course, a part of me did that to avoid the cilantro conflict, but the important thing is that catnip has the same effect as memes. When cats approach…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        …they temporarily get unconscious…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …so when a cat’s restless, angry, full of outrage, out on an expedition, the only thing you have to do is to offer some catnip, which will knock out the cat for a second.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        After the effect wears off, the cat actually becomes quite reasonable. Thus, we can keep on talking about the topic nicely.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        However, in order to use memes to reply to the disinformation, or as a the premise to make this work, the memes always have to…always have to be more hilarious.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Because…for instance, if disinformation is spread through more hilarious memes, then aren’t we kind of having a competition to be the funniest message to grab everyone’s attention?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s actually not like that. Because when we think of something humorous, our brain circuit is like this: When I perceive a social controversy, I often feel helpless. The helplessness may lead to uncomfortable and angry feelings, and when one feel angry, one often press the “share” button immediately because it can lift anger into outrage.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        However, the circuit of outrage is contradicted with that of humor. That is to say, if you see something humorous when you feel angry, no matter it’s true or not, as long as you laugh and think it’s hilarious, you will then generate a sense of “Hmmm…I’ve laughed and had fun already,” and the feeling of “I must vent my anger at someone” disappears.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Therefore, memes don’t really have to be true or false; in science, there are lots of different hypotheses. These diverse ideas can then lead to real debates and deliberations.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Alright. Yet, I don’t agree with you because the circuit of emotions doesn’t have to contradict each other. For instance, when writing scripts for the show, I often tell my writers, “we have to pick an emotion.” I believe sadness and happiness have the most contradictions. As for anger, you know, our show satirizes many things, such as the Mining Laws and factories on farmlands. These are all approaches to channel anger to…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, that’s the most effective… We totally agree.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In other words, if you want a funny punchline, you should start with anger because it’s the easiest way. Nevertheless, when anger turns into outrage, as in going on an expedition to attack someone, it becomes hardly funny at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Its outcome is different. Good.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Let’s talk about the last topic. I believe everyone in the audience can see that I really just want to chat with Audrey and don’t really care about you guys at all.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, I noticed that you seldom turn your head.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, seriously… I really don’t care.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You know, the producer keeps saying, “Okay, okay, you should end the conversation now,” on the side. Yet, it’s my last episode, I just don’t care.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Audrey, I don’t know it’s before or after when you became a Minister, but when someone said that you’re a proponent of anarchy, you seemed to explain that anarchism doesn’t equal to having no government at all?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I’m a conservative anarchist, or “chíshǒu de ānnàqí.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So it’s not the “bǎoshǒu” kind of conservative. What’s the difference between your definition and the usual one?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I define conservative as respecting the diverse cultures in Taiwan. Currently, we have about 20 national languages, and each of them is a different culture. When one particularly strong culture dominates other cultures, looking from that culture’s side, people may consider it as progressive, as in making progress. Yet, when you take the view from the other cultures, it simply means that we didn’t conserve them well.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Thus, my main idea here is transculturalism. In other words, you may be under the influence of one culture when you were born and growing up, but you can get in touch with another culture, usually through learning a new language, when you’re in your teens or twenties. The more you can understand your hometown from the perspective of other cultures, the more unique your thinking becomes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        With a transcultural citizenry, everyone can offer a unique perspective, which makes for a most diverse democracy. This is my fundamental idea.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Wow! There are so many things that I want to talk about.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Let’s talk about anarchism. In your opinion, what’s the difference between “anarchism” and “anarchy”?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In anarchism, there can be governing mechanisms. It’s just the government would not have the power to coerce, command, and force people.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK, good. Also, because I majored in foreign languages, I wanted to talk about languages that we’ve mentioned earlier. We learn languages, and languages are the denotations of the conceptual world. We express our thoughts through languages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You’ve just said learning another language can help you understand another culture, but my question is this. Since a language cannot include all concepts, so do you have other methods to…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …then you probably have to learn more languages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK, good, more languages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Alright, alright, I have restrained my urge. I know that just now the audience is sending questions to Minister Audrey Tang through a website. I don’t know if we have explained to everyone that we want really irreverent questions.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Hold on, hold on, the second question is… it’s completely irrelevant…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Now someone, someone…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I see the “(seriously)” in brackets, indicating that this is not irreverent.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Great, they must be worried that no one knew this was just kidding.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “Minister Tang, how do you maintain your hairstyle? (seriously)”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, my favorite hair studio is Superbcut, a social enterprise.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Hey, really, I know it, it’s that shop on Dunhua South Road…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, they also helped with your party’s founding party.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        As for their hair stylist, every time I visit there, I say “Please help me cut a hairstyle that does not require any maintenance.” That’s why I don’t maintain my hair.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, so you don’t maintain your hair?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The only way to maintain one’s hair is to have enough sleep, eight hours a day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Do you wash your hair every day?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        About every one or two days.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, so you are really saying something. I’ve found that you really know how to chat. How come you can speak about anything?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I have probably been asked these questions more than five times already.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Not creative, that’s what you mean.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s cached, it’s all in my head. Actually, this is because their vote number is so high. The ones with low vote number often have never been asked.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Got it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “Can you find @shasha77 in the vast crowd?”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        What is this…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This is an eyesight test, not an intelligence test.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        He is also one of the party founders.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        @shasha77… where is…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        He is dressed like Wally today.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In the second row…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Too accurate…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In the back… I saw the shadow of a figure just now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I give up, I give up.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK, we can’t find it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “What advice will Audrey Tang give the newly re-elected President Tsai Ing-wen and the new Legislative Yuan?”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, from the perspective of the executive branch, we are the subject of congressional oversight. That’s why we won’t do anything like advising the Parliament. But a few…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        On this informal occasion…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …yes, so I can speak a little wildly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A few legislators from the south often told me that they have to run local trips for their constituency. Even if we have the high-speed rails, their service may be far from high-speed rail stations. They will rush, then, to the parliamentary inquiry and then rush to go back. In fact, they’d spend almost an entire day on this.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        You’re going to say something about robots and Skype?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I would suggest that, in every administrative area, we can place this kind of devices for tele-inquiries.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Because in fact, during the parliamentary inquiries, what matters is the optics, and tele-inquiries can also offer that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Also we should use a kind of projected virtual characters…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        The videos are split-screen anyway…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Anyway, we can…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Pack a bunch of white balls at home…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …create 3D models of legislators.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think this must be very effective. And then after every inquiry, the legislator can fly up. Wouldn’t that be great?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Brilliant. Okay, next question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “How do we achieve anti-infiltration with information.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, this question is linked to the half-question that I have not answered yet.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        On my suggestion to President Tsai Ing-wen, because I am also in charge of youth engagement, I think when we are making policies, we often think about the state helping young people, helping them with schooling, employment, entrepreneurship, housing, etc.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        But in fact, some of the most interesting youth policies we see are often proposed by young people. For example, the suggestion that WorldSkills medalists should go to the National Day parade. After the parade, they could go to the elementary and middle school to help students renovate their school buildings. This is to let everyone know that technical high school is about learn things that you can help your school with rather than things that you only learn when you can’t enter an academic high school.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This idea was put forward by Huang Wei-hsiang, a youth advisor to the cabinet. He was 29 years old when he joined the Youth Advisory Committee, about the same age as you. Under such circumstances, I think that the more youth policies are led and decided by youth, the better.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In fact, this is also the best method for anti-infiltration in terms of information. Because if you think that the top-down policy affects you and you have no right to decide, then it is very easy for you to become misinformed.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        However, if this policy is something that you have taken part in, say, if it had been proposed via Let’s Talk, a petition through the Join platform or other methods, it means this policy had been originally written by you, or at least parts of it had been written by you, then of course you will not be subject to infiltration.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Hang on, there are two questions. What is the definition of youth?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        According to the definition of the Youth Development Administration, or our Youth Advisory Council, it is 18 to 35 years old.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        OK, OK. Which definition do you not want to follow?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course, everyone has been a young person once, anyone over 35 years old.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Like a certain young boy.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I asked my friends from the Youth Development Administration today. They said that these high school students on the stage…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This is because the 18-year-olds are not the most frequently petitioners of proposals; rather, it’s the 15-year-olds. Because an 18-year-old can at least go to vote in a referendum, whereas a 15-year-old can do nothing, so when we have a petition platform, the petition such as banning plastic straws are all proposed by 15-year-olds.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So I asked the Youth Development Administration whether they are considered youths? My colleagues said that they are “youths-in-training.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Do you think they are so enthusiastic because they can’t do so much? Because once you can do it, you won’t cherish it as much.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sounds reasonable. That’s why we should cherish this period of traineeship.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Or we can start taking away the rights of what people can do… no, no, just kidding.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “Recent Views on Hong Kong (Influence on Information Dissemination)”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I see another bracket here. Well I think for Hong Kong, with the resurgence of a so-called waterless movement… Er, let’s do another take.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        As for the “leaderless” and “be water” movements in Hong Kong, I think the most important thing is that in our previous imagination, large-scale events must have organizers. Many people would say, what happens if there is no organization? It would become a riot.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Therefore, the approach in Hong Kong is not that there is no organizer; rather, it is that everyone can be an organizer. Everyone can think clearly about what I am going to do here and that I am willing to share it, so that very soon there are more than 2,000 organizers.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        So, with a co-creation like “Glory to Hong Kong”, we can see that in each creative process, there is an organizer facilitating the co-creation. After each creation, they share it in an open and transparent way, so that other creators can see it and say, for example, that it only resonates with certain people and not the others. Then someone else can remix it so that it resonates with other people as well.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We can already see this kind of creative method on LIHKG. I think this is really a method that any social movement in the future must learn.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        That’s great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “In an ever changing era of AI, is there any advice you want to give to someone who is on this path?”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Actually, I think in the era of AI, any time you are feeling machine-like while doing your work, these are the times when AI can help you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So it can eliminate some negative emotions because there is no such work for you in the future?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes, so you can focus on the creative work.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Oh, but can you call this an advice for people who are on this path?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Certainly. In other words, one of the most needed skills right now is experience design. Or if you have a social work background, it is called job/process redesign. With this competence, you can go and find out what is repetitive in your work flow; which tasks has a simple input structure and a simple output structure; where there is only a difference in speed and you find it really boring.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Previously, people had to endure this part of work, because only humans could do it. But now, even if nobody wants to do it, and you can’t find a trainee, you can go and train a machine apprentice to do it. After it has observed your work, it can do it for you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        And then you can do the part that requires getting along with people, that is, the competence around communication and interaction, and develop common values, the competence around social participation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Redesigning your own work is “Taking the Initiative.” Using different skills to connect with each other is “Engaging the Public.” Achieving a shared purpose is “Seeking the Common Good.” These three are precisely the Core Competences of the 108 curriculum.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        So we come back to that again. It’s great. OK, alright. Last question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Slido Comment">
                    <p>
                        “Can you shout “Better than Brian” to Brian Tseng.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        I think this is very suitable for Audrey to shout out.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Surely not?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        It would be very convincing.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Fine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Old K">
                    <p>
                        Unlike a certain someone.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Alright, alright, alright.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You’re good with that?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Yes, of course.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Better than Brian!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Without a doubt!
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Brian Tseng">
                    <p>
                        Audience members, please put your hands together once again for Audrey Tang.
                    </p>
                </speech>
            </debateSection>
        </debateBody>
    </debate>
</akomaNtoso>
