<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<akomaNtoso>
    <debate>
        <meta>
            <references>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Clara Gillispie" id="Clara Gillispie" showAs="Clara Gillispie"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang"/>
            </references>
        </meta>
        <debateBody>
            <debateSection>
                <heading>
                    2020-12-18 Clara Gillispie visits
                </heading>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know makes some people nervous, and it’s just not a good…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I know. Even when we introduced social distancing, I say, “Keep two meters or wear a mask.” people keep two meters 
                        <em>
                            and
                        </em>
                         wear a mask.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] Which, if you can do it, is great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Which is really, really good. Let’s get started.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know you have quite a busy schedule, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, it’s fine. We’ve got an hour to ourselves.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Excellent. I have some questions that are a little bit all over the map, based on my interests and research. Maybe just a little bit of background about me, my original academic focus has been technology policy, but over the last decade at NBR, I’ve moved into looking at energy, public health, and sustainable development policymaking.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        This year has been an attempt to bring the two more clearly together.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        For Taiwan, that’s involved looking at a couple areas, which, depending on the amount of questions, I might only get to the first one versus three.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sure. Also, I’m told that it would get really loud 50 minutes from now, because there’s a festival thing going on. You’ve probably seen…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I saw. It’s nice.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We have 50 minutes of quiet time, hopefully.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The bulk of my questions and interests are first focused around how Taiwan as a democracy deals with misinformation, specifically, about COVID, then some on the ways that it’s responded to COVID more broadly, including the biosurveillance mechanisms.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Then, because that’s not enough area, I have a lot of early questions bouncing around in my mind about smart cities. Maybe…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know much about smart cities. If you ask about smart citizens though, I have lots of stories.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’d love to hear.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        My initial question for thinking about the misinformation challenge is I see so many people who will say, “Oh, misinformation about public health is really easy to address, because it’s all…”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, we just have a cute dog.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, or I mean, “Oh, it’s just very clear what the answer should be, so no one should fall for misinformation.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, just cute dog.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I was going to say, I’m normally not a dog person, but following the social media, it’s very cute.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I know. The Shiba Inu is not just any dog. It’s a super cute dog. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I was going to ask, why the Shiba Inu in particular? Is it because it’s so popular in Taiwan?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, literally, the participation officer of the Ministry of Health and Welfare lives with this dog.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I didn’t know that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They live just a block or so away from the Ministry of Health and Welfare. Every time the CECC has a press conference, they just walk back home, take new pictures, and upload to the Internet. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Oh, my gosh. I’m going to have to tell a couple of my friends that, because they had the same question, if you have that kind of dog, and they thought it was…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, it’s an actual dog, and we thank her for her service.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Yeah.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Thinking about the initial landscape, one of the questions that I always wonder about, when a pandemic is starting, it’s not always clear what is fact versus fiction, because sometimes, the scientific studies might be a little bit lagging.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’m thinking where the WHO and others, the US, threw a little bit of question mark onto the mask situation, even the…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sorry to interrupt, but this dog was saying, and in no uncertain terms, “Wear a mask to protect your own face against your own hand.” That is never in question.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s a good point.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We’re not saying anything else.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s a very fair point. In situations, though, where it might be unclear…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then we simply don’t have the dog say that. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        How do you think, then, about if you see online people approaching the questions or citizens are tackling it? What do you see as the role, “of government” is not the right word.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of the spokesdog, yes, of the Zǒngchái. The Zǒngchái role is very simple. There is, broadly speaking, two ways that a message go viral, and both start from outrage. It’s discussed at length by Manuel Castells in his books.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        One is the system that is, I refer to as antisocial media, which goes from rage to fear and then to disgust or apathy, which is extreme disgust. That leads to polarization, and of course, all that. Also, there is another path that turns this outrage, instead of going to revenge or discrimination, which is all based on fear, it can turn it into worrying.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Like, we worry together how people could prevent this kind of injustice from happening again. Once we worry together, eventually, we deliver something new. That’s the joy, the joy of co-creation. The movie “Inside Out” captured the five emotions pretty perfectly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I love that movie.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The point of what I call humor over rumor is to make this rage, worrying, joy path, the prosocial path, more viral, have a higher R-value than the outrage, fear, and then disgust path.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        This is a very basic question, because my knowledge is limited here. I’ve heard you mentioned before, what exactly is an R value? Is it just the measure of how…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        On average, how many people do each recipient share to. It’s like a virus. The R value of a virus, if it’s above one, then it will cause an epidemic. If the value is under one, it means each person, before they recover, infect less than one person, then it will not go viral. These kind of disinformation, we don’t have to do anything.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s incredibly helpful, thank you. That actually relates to another question I had. I think looking at something Doublethink Lab wrote, they’ve mentioned that in terms of the virality while there’s been a lot of misinformation posts of the, “Can I drink garlic water?” type things, that’s been less viral or less of a concern than…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. Only a few, a handful went truly viral.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Most of those that went truly viral related to political issues or maybe societal questions, like how do we…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        There’s a truly viral one. “Hong Kong rioter’s compensation exposed, killer police earn 20 million,” with a scary-looking person, and says, “This 13-years-old bought iPhones by killing police.” This is an actual “Reuters” photo, by the way, but it said nothing about iPhones.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course, this is a doctored message by the weibo account of the central political and law unit, part of the PRC Beijing Regime.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Am I correct in thinking, one of the challenges that I’ve heard is, even if you get out that correction that says, “Oh, this image was doctored.” if it takes too long, people who’ve seen it might say, “Oh, sure this…”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        This is literally attached to each and every share, say, on Facebook. You can still share it on Facebook, but you can’t escape from Facebook showing a public notice saying, “This is probably…” maybe not probably “…sponsored by the PRC.” [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That, I thought, has been one of the most encouraging moves this year, to be more transparent on who is this account, or who has been sharing this?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’ve heard the theory, if it’s not caught, and one of the reasons why it’s so important to think preventatively about how you diagnose and identify, there’s the risk that people might say, “Oh, yes, I saw this a few weeks back, and it didn’t have the label. Now that you’re telling me…”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Basically, it has to happen in the same day, because once people sleep on it, it forms long-term memory. There’s no escaping from that. That’s why there’s the triple-two point by Kolas Yotaka when she was our spokesperson, saying that, within two hours of detection of a disinformation with R value above one, we need to roll out two different mode.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        One picture and one video or whatever, to counter points, each less than 200 characters long, meaning that it fits on the screen. If you get there in two hours, and especially when the detection works on the early stage, when it has not gone this exponential, it was still at this stage…This is just like fighting coronavirus.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then the quarantining would work, and then you can vaccinate with the humor, sufficient number of people, so that on average, when people see the message of outrage, they already laugh about it, so wouldn’t share. This is what we call – what I call – nerd immunity.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        It’s a good way of thinking about it. I really like the inoculation message, too, because I think it helps on a couple of friends. The two hours, I’ve always been curious, is that just because it’s quick, it’s very easy to set, or is there a specific reason for two hours versus, say, four?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s a length of a news cycle. Like morning news, noon news, evening news. If you get within two hours, the next news cycle can do a balanced reporting, but if you miss that, then the noon news may spread the disinformation, and you have to wait until evening news.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        At that point, there are more people who’ve heard it, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The two modes, is that in a single post, or is it like make sure you release a text post, but also…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, like a meme is an image, but also a press release, for the people who are investigative journalists who want to know more, or a video and a picture, that happen, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Most of this, I’ve always been intrigued. I’ve seen a couple of times the wiggling butt. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, but he has a front side, too. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Are these mostly posted on the websites that’s closest to whatever the issue is, so Ministry of Health and Welfare?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s also just featured on Line today, on the most popular instant message system. Basically, it’s in the commons. Anyone can remix and post it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’ve been a big fan of the Ministry of Health and Welfare. It’s both the Twitter account and then the Facebook one. Even beyond the misinformation, I’ve found it very clear in communicating correct information.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I would say, especially as someone whose language skills are limited, it’s very visually representative of, “This is the case numbers, and here’s how you can link to more text. Maybe you can translate it.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The Ministry of Health and Welfare, especially around the Food and Drug Administration, they have the most exposure to disinformation, even though pretty nonpolitical most of the times. Still, if you look at the trending misinformation for the pandemic, it’s still about health.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        “If you eat this and that, it will cause cancer. If you eat this and that, it will kill cancer.” [laughs] They have the most experience countering this.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        One thing that I’ve heard, and I welcome your reaction on, is that, especially compared to the United States, there’s much less anti-vaccine or vaccine disinformation.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Oh, yeah, the flu vaccine, I think, is historical high in adoption rate, so that they would have to throttle it a little bit. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’ve noticed the very clear, “Here is the cycle of when you can go.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Line today, I’ve seen some of the messaging on Instagram, Twitter, Facebook. Is there anything I’m missing relating to WhatsApp?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        PPT.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        PPT, yeah. Is there anything that’s being, either like a bot or accounts on WhatsApp?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        There are Line at-bots. I think a few ministries and politicians have Telegram accounts, as well. Especially, Line started charging too much. Some of them switched to Telegram first. I don’t know about WhatsApp. WhatsApp is not the most popular messaging app here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know. I was very big on WhatsApp, because earlier in the year, I was in India. Then the United States is popular, too. When I got here, everyone immediately said, “You need to be on Line. This is where…”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. When people say they are online, sometimes they just mean they are on Line.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        On Line…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’d love to hear more about the process of moving from identification to dissemination. Something I was less clear on was how many people are we talking about who are involved in this process, or hours per week, and are we talking about people…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It differs from ministry to ministry. It’s very hard to cite. The Ministry of Health and Welfare, the Council of Agriculture, maybe the Ministry of Interior, these people-facing ministries, and Ministry of Economic Affairs, of course, with their “Toy Story” based campaigns.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I will say the Ministry of Education, and also, for some reason, the coastal guards, they have some of the best response systems. It’s really hard to gauge, because it also depends on whether they face a controversial issue.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        When there’s a controversial issue, they will work with more professional comedians. Sometimes, like YouTubers also volunteer their time. There’s a very successful campaign with the Ministry of Education about school bullying.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Most of the people who contributed, I think pro bono or something, because they care about that particular issue. It’s variable.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Taiwan FactCheck Center, involved in that as well?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        No, not really. What we call this humor over rumor, it may be a rapid response to something, but we don’t call ourselves fact-checkers, because that’s journalists’ job, the journalists, they of course already fact-check within their own institution.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Some of the professional journalists also formed the fact-checker to fact-check the fact-checkers, like very meta. That’s actually part of the International Fact-Checking Network. At that point, I think there’s the TFCC, there’s MyGoPen.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        These two are part of the IFCN. There’s all grassroots ones, like Cofacts, which then evolved into more what we call forks, derivatives, such as the Dr. Message Bot – again, a cute dog – from Trend Micro, our antivirus company.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        There’s also the Meiyuyi, or the Aunt Meiyu, which is now part of the WhosCall, which is another startup focusing on fraud detection on phone calls and things like that. There’s an ecosystem, but this ecosystem, unless they get the IFCN certificates, they don’t quite call themselves journalistic fact-checkers.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That makes some sense. Also, some of the ecosystem helps to amplify or reinforce or check work, but also, it sounds like, for some of the efforts combatting, not recreating the work or taking away from.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, exactly. The Line ecosystem is pretty good, because it’s shows a real dashboard of which partnering organization which offer which fact-checking, and also the trending ones. Many people can just look at this analysis as well the Cofacts one, because this is all just public information, to detect to those disinformation with an R value above one, but before they actually reach a lot of people.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know, I was looking at some of the Cofacts database, and I was incredibly impressed by just how much data was out there, of not even, just broad data. Not even trying to do a message, but allow researchers to check.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’d love to hear a little bit more about ways in which you’re trying to reach difficult-to-reach communities. There are two that I have in mind in particular. One is, of course, the elderly or those who are less digital native are often cited as the most likely to spread…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Then the other one is foreign communities, whose first language might not include Taiwanese Mandarin or another Chinese dialect. It might be English or Southeast Asian languages.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        According to the TWIGF report on the broadband utilization and Internet use and so on – of course, it’s all online, I’m not going to cite the entire report – I think it’s rather a stereotype that elderly people use less. It’s not like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        A lot of elderly people spend a lot of time on Line, and they’re very happy with QR code. I think this is really not a generational issue. What really is an issue, however, is linguistic and cultural. If we only use, as you mentioned, Taiwanese Mandarin to spread those messages, there are the elderly people who are more fluent in Taiwanese Daiyi or Hakka or indigenous languages and so on.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We do need to work the cross-cultural translation, not just linguistic, but also cultural translations as well, working with lifelong learning endeavors, such as community colleges. They’re very helpful there, and also long-term healthcare facilities.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The elderly people also want to help their family chat groups to fact-check their children and grandchildren. They also want to contribute. It’s just they have to know how. The mLearn portal, for example, emphasize that although it’s Ministry of Education, this is lifelong education.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We do work with, as I mentioned, those reaching out ways. Working with people who don’t speak any of the 20 national languages has been challenging.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The MOHW did really well there, working with English and most of new immigrant languages, but it’s true. You need to make the picture cards in a very deliberative fashion, actually consulting those different culture groups.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Also, just paying attention, for example, making sure that the text doesn’t overlap the picture, so that when you want to translate this into Vietnamese or something, it doesn’t hurt the dog’s cuteness.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] Or change the meaning, part of it is lost.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Or change the meaning, exactly right. I would suggest you talking to maybe MOHW, because they’re, I think, the most advanced working on this cross-cultural thing. For example, the Coastal Guard, I don’t think they work on this that much.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        It may be in some ways less relevant to their work day-to-day.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In Taiwan, we say the Coastal Guard as 住海邊, meaning that everything is their business.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They have a very broad reach.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        You’ve spoken to this a little bit already, but I’d love to hear more about how you of measuring success in some of these efforts. The challenge that seems to come up inevitably is how do you define success of a disinformation campaign that never…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Oh, very easily. This says, “Wear a mask and wash your hands.” so we can use this SCADA system of the Taiwan Water Company to measure whether people wash their hands more. Not individual people, but in aggregate, do the fountains and faucets turn on for a longer time, and whether that’s just in the municipality or rural areas, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We can also work with the community pharmacists to know how many fraction of people do have access to masks in the rationing system. Not vis-à-vis disinformation, but on the success of the call-to-action.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s really helpful, because the action seems to be also where you want to drive, even regardless, if you have a campaign that doesn’t respond to the public health concern…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It really needs to stand alone. This is not just counter-disinformation, there is also sharing scientific fact.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I think I know the answer to this one, but I want to ask directly to make sure I…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know the World Health Organization over the summer and fall has been doing some efforts to try to think about their own metrics for success in combatting the infodemic. Has there been any invitation, extension, inclusion of Taiwanese participation?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We do have limited scientific contact so that, through the WHO system, we can reach other scientists and get their contact. Some of the scientists even cited Taiwan as performing really well. There’s scientists who cite these conversations.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course, we have MOFA people here, so I’m obliged to say having scientific access is not the same as having ministerial access, unless you are in a country where the top epidemiologist expert is also vice president, like in Taiwan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Talking to the top scientists doesn’t necessarily translate to ministerial action, but the point is ministerial action. Having the ministerial access is still very important. End of obligatory information. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Especially, too, in some of the breaking news and understanding where it’s not just historical review, but it urgently needs action now, and getting that high-level attention to it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Digital literacy as a broad effort, I know there’s been this conversation, and I’ve read a little bit online, about trying to embed it in high school curricula.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We call it competence, we don’t call it literacy.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        If I can ask, what’s the difference between…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Literacy is when other people produce media, and you consume it. Competence is when you produce the media. Competence builds on literacy, of course. If you’re illiterate, probably you’re not very competent.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Being literate is not enough, because with broadband as human right, many primary schoolers maybe have more Instagram followers than I do, in which case, they are media. They need to learn about the journalistic part of media, like checking the sources, balancing the…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …ethics and things like that. Without which, they’re going to fill in their media content, anyway, and probably from conspiracy theories.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know some of that’s been ongoing. Has that officially been launched in high schools?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, of course. That’s what I refer to by the mLearn portal. It’s mlearn.moe.gov.tw. It’s been there for quite a while now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        OK, fantastic, thank you. Then this has been incredibly helpful, too. Thank you. This transitions between a few of my questions, the transparency focus.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The case study that I’ve been previously more familiar with on thinking about government response to pandemic or crisis is South Korea, where during MERS, the administration was not transparent enough by a number of measures led to changes in laws.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The challenge being that, with COVID-19, some human rights groups argued that they’d actually gone too far in saying…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        To the other direction. We believe in making the state transparent to the people, but if you make people transparent to the state… [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        There can be some groups that question, “Oh, we want to know where the cases are clustered,” but then you get to the question…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        We don’t do that, not to a level where you can reidentify the person.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Following the Ministry of Health and Welfare, it’s very broad on the case, so you can understand maybe the country of origin and a little bit about what the next steps were taken to ensure management of local spread.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Has there been any discussion more or less information requested, or?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. There was a case, I think, in April when a hostess in a professional hostess bar was diagnosed with COVID. Of course, in host and hostess bars in nightlife district, they were already stigmatized to begin with.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        When we learned that the first day, she said, “Well, I’m just staying at home. I don’t have many friends. I don’t hang out with people. I don’t know why they heard it.” Then the next day, she says, “Yeah, well, I want to protect the anonymity of my patrons.” which is very legit, but there’s a large backlash.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Not only people want to 肉搜, so how do I translate it? D-O-X-X, doxx her but not successfully, though. They also are basically putting pressure on the CECC to fine the business to put the owner to jail, or to do other criminal code stuff.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Like the US Prohibition, exactly the US Prohibition. You know what I’m talking about. They have the moral high ground, because after all, the hostess did lie to the contact tracers to the first day. The CECC refused and resisted that pressure. I was in the meeting, because we were originally going to talk about masks.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then we didn’t talk about masks that day. Minister Chen Shih-chung eventually said, “What we are going to do is a 行政指導…” — an administrative recommendation — “…that the nightlife district, specifically the dancing clubs and host bars and hostess bars, need to remain closed until they can figure out how to make the real contact system work.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s it. He didn’t put anyone in jail. Didn’t actually fine anyone, even.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Very neutral to the person as well.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Very neutral to the person. Then it’s almost like a challenge to the social innovators. After three weeks or so, some business invented such a way that the patrons who visit can leave a prepaid SIM card or a throwaway email address that doesn’t identify themselves.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They can use a pseudonym, and then they enter the host or hostess bar. Then, if there is a local transmission, then within 14 days, they will be notified by that handle, but the data is never sent to the CECC, or indeed, to any government. It is in the business.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Then after four weeks, it’s shredded – like, literally shredded – at which time the patron can throw away that SIM card or throwaway email address. It does the job of real contact without any new data collection in the government side. This is what some academic people called participatory self-surveillance.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’ve been wondering about that, because I’ve gone to a couple of museums and different places where they’ll say, “Oh, we need your phone number or email.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, but we will shred that four weeks afterward.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        It’s only if they’re specifically approached by the CECC saying, “We have a person that we’ve interviewed who says they’ve come to your facility within this period of time. You might want to notify everyone.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Exactly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Fantastic. It’s hard, because Taiwan has just done so overwhelmingly well.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, it’s half a year since the last local transmission.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I was going to ask how you think about measuring success on that, when you’re like, “Well, it’s harder to miss cases.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I know, I don’t know.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Maybe you measure against Taiwan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I know. Every time I try to do a study or comparison and talk to anywhere else in the region or the US, my family still can’t believe. They’re like, “Wait, you went somewhere, and you didn’t wear a mask necessarily?” I was like, “Well, after December 1, I’m wearing my mask.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, I think measuring against Taiwan, I think we are second only to Antarctica, maybe… [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        …and the International Space Station.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I’d love to hear a little bit more about how wire surveillance has worked in general. I’ve been very interested, having gone through the quarantine process myself.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, get SMS every eight hours.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Yeah. I got a couple times where it told me that I had left. I got very anxious, and I had to text back. I was like, “No, I’m still here.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        As soon as you text back, that’s fine.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s what I was told, too, like, “Make sure you leave your phone on, because sometimes, it can get drained.”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s right. If it runs out of battery, then they report as if you’ve left.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Others have been clear to characterize the report-in system online as not being an app, but being a service. I’d be curious to hear about how that…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s a telecom-side software. The software has always been there already. It’s been used to do geographically-targeted earthquake warnings. Maybe a few days ago, you got one, saying that, “There’s imminent earthquake.” also, flood and evacuation warnings as well.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The capacity is already there. It’s not a new data collection point, not, unlike the tokens that the Singaporeans wear. This is not a new device, and you don’t have to turn on GPS, Bluetooth, WiFi, or whatever, because it only measure the signal strength and nothing else, which is why it’s a little bit imprecise.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Which may be a good thing, because then we don’t know which room you are in. We just know which block you are in. Then we know that the telecoms do the processing themselves. They cannot outsource this to other people.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s not like you get random advertisements because of your quarantine. Then also, unfortunately, they’re also subject to the shred it after four weeks data retention rule. I think it’s proportional, but that’s because we’ve been exposed to SARS, and I remember SARS.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I understand standards may be different in other jurisdictions.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I got to use a lot in quarantine the daily report-in your symptoms app. I’d love to hear more about the decision process of deciding what goes into that or not, because in some ways, you could think of it having mission creep.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        It’s also a good opportunity, thinking about foreigners as being difficult to reach, of directly saying…It occurred to me when I was using the app, I tried to message back and someone, like, “Can I cure COVID with garlic?”
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The app said, “No.” Well, “You need to call this, because we can’t understand.” I’ll be curious to hear more about how you think about…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s not a real call center thing. No, it’s not a call center. The mission is very clear, the symptom, the temperature, your suggestion to improve the experience. These are chosen precisely because that’s what authorized by the act for communicable diseases.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Because we’ve never declared a state of emergency, so we are bound by whatever is in the act. Anything else we want to do, we need preapproval from the parliament, the legislature. This is why I mentioned the heuristic of not setting up new data collection points that wasn’t there before the pandemic. That would require parliamentary authorization.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (pause)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Are there any methods or mechanisms or processes set in place to review and audit these systems? I’m thinking like the question I’ve had a couple times in the US context is how do you know that your information is being deleted after the 14 days, or how do you…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        28 days, and how do you audit the nightlife district, that they’ve not sold it to advertisers?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Exactly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <narrative>
                    <p>
                        <i>
                            (laughter)
                        </i>
                    </p>
                </narrative>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        In Taiwan, there is no single answer to this question, because we don’t have a single data protection authority. According to our current privacy act, the nightlife district, for example, will probably rely on the Ministry of Economic Affairs.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        On the other hand, if this is like a job search board or something, the Ministry of Labor would be the data protection authority. All in all, I think there’s 14 different data protection authorities. The problem here, of course, as rightly pointed by the drafters of GDPR, is that the standards will necessarily differ.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Even if, for example, the Ministry of Health and Welfare can give a full account of how your data has been, the retention, deletion, and so on, but if they have worked with, for example, the convenience store, which doesn’t report to MOHA for DPA purposes – it reports to MOEA – you have to ask MOEA, too.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If your, for example, immigration report is part of the MOI, then you have to ask the MOI, and actually also MOFA, maybe, because that’s where it is issued. The decentralized architecture of the data protection authority indeed makes the law — which is very clearly written — like you can get a copy of your reports and requesting for update and deletion when the purpose is gone, and things like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s fine, but it’s extremely time-consuming, and you can’t really, like just looking at this table, saying that these trades are the MOEA, these are the Ministry of Finance, Council of Finance, this is the NCC, Ministry of Transportation, Education, Interior, Labor, MOHW, Finance, or GEC, the Gender Equality Committee, or FTC, the Fair Trade Commission. They are in charge for 多層次傳銷, how do you say that? Multi-level marketers. If you are subject to a privacy breach of a multi-level marketing enterprise, then you have to report to the FTC.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Look, this is news even to me. Not many people can really memorize this table. That makes the DPA act difficult to enforce, and of course, many people don’t bother to ask all those different ministries. They ask one or two and get maybe satisfied, or they can live with it, and then that’s that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Sometimes, there might be a response, but there’s a lot going on. It’ll take time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You have to write a formal letter to the CECC. They don’t do phone call, because they don’t know you it’s you. If you are not you, then you’re essentially requesting other people’s data.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Exactly. Can I ask, where does this table live?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        If you look at PIPA.ndc.gov.tw, which I think is in the GDPR office of the National Development Council, because they are in charge of negotiating with the EU on the GDPR adequacy. The lack of a single DPA is, I think, the only blocking issue now.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They have this comparison of GDPR and Taiwan’s current status. Now, NDC being, of course, the initiator of the Bilingual Nation Initiative, with luck, they probably have an English page, which will probably help you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        [laughs] Google Translate has been amazing, but sometimes not so.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yeah, it has been amazing. I’ve found DeepL to be more amazing, but OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        My favorite error has been Facebook Translate sometimes translates MOFA as the Ministry of Magic, and that’s just adorable.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They are. They are a magical ministry. Yeah, there is the English version. The Personal Data Protection Office, the PDPO of the National Development Council. They are the prototype of the single DPA.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Everything is there, but the enforcement is currently limited. I think the PDPO, the office, and yours truly both would really prefer if we have true GDPR adequacy, and you have a single place, preferably, to just press a key and download everything related to your data being used.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        There’s a National Development Council website called MyData for that, but I don’t think there’s an English version just yet, at mydata.nat.gov.tw.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Would any of that, either in terms of the enforcement question or the single-agency DPA, be changed or enacted by the idea of this new digital ministry?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Yes.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Would that include a specific single agency under the digital ministry or…?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The dependent agencies are not under ministries, but, of course, because of the digital ministerial council, there will be an opportunity to talk about setting up new offices to satisfy the GDPR. It will be related, but the minister of the digital ministry will not have the appointing of the personal data protection office. Otherwise, it’s not independent.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        From looking at India over the last year, it’s been quite the challenge. [laughs] I think you’ve hit upon all of my questions. This has been so incredible. The thing I always ask everyone at the end is, based on the questions you’ve heard me ask or topics I’ve touched on, are there any bad assumptions that you think I have or things that I haven’t touched on that you’d encourage me to think about?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The first part, no. I think these are excellently-framed and very balanced questions. Also, I think it’s worth highlighting the, what I call, people-public-private partnership, because much too often, foreign correspondents report the Taiwan all-of-society approach as public-private-people partnership or public-private partnership, but that’s wrong.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The people set the norm, and like the mask availability map, that’s set by the social sector, not my idea. They essentially pressure government, like reverse procurement. We become the vendors. [laughs] Then we…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        And solve a genuine problem.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Right, exactly. Then we take that to pressure the private sector or convenience stores. It’s people-public-private partnership. That’s the only thing I would like to bring up.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s fantastic. Thank you so much. This has been really great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Thank you, awesome.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        The noise did not get too bad, either.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s quietly getting louder now. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Will you get to enjoy the holidays at all, or is it continuing to be a very busy, I know already, 2020 for everyone?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I think I’m going to enjoy the holidays, definitely.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        That’s good. This is really my first time in Taiwan, so I’m trying to decide both what I might do for Christmas, and I’ll…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Excellent.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Thank you.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        The magician here, the MOFA colleague, can maybe make some suggestions. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs is truly a magical place. [laughs]
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        I got to use going to g0v Conference as my excuse to go see Tainan…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Tainan has better weather, and better food.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        It was so nice. I love Taipei, but it’s good to travel a little bit.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Very much so. OK, cheers.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Clara Gillispie">
                    <p>
                        Thank you so much, cheers.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Bye.
                    </p>
                </speech>
            </debateSection>
        </debateBody>
    </debate>
</akomaNtoso>