<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<akomaNtoso>
    <debate>
        <meta>
            <references>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Benjamin Finn" id="Benjamin Finn" showAs="Benjamin Finn"/>
                <TLCPerson href="/ontology/person/::/Audrey Tang" id="Audrey Tang" showAs="Audrey Tang"/>
            </references>
        </meta>
        <debateBody>
            <debateSection>
                <heading>
                    2021-02-17 Benjamin Finn visits
                </heading>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Thank you for having me, Minister.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sure.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Sorry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        How do you spell your project?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        ——–.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        OK.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        You won’t find the Facebook page, sorry.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        You won’t find the web page because we took it offline out of concern.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I saw it on Twitter.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Great. We work on what’s called the —– Project. We’re currently deploying it around the world to fight hate speech, misinformation, and calls to violence. We use a system and an AI. We’re very close to getting the AI to work and be better, and be able to automatically flag hate speech and send it directly.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        We work with Facebook, Twitter. We’re close to getting Audacious funding, if you’re familiar with Audacious. Then the coup happened. We think that all of our people are in danger. Eventually, once the military takes full control, they’re going to turn their attention to anyone who annoys them. Taking their lies offline is going to annoy them.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        What we’re hoping is, something quite audacious, to bring as much of the company out of —– as possible. I don’t know how to do this, because I’m just an IT guy who just happens to be in —–.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You were based in…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        I spent two years there. I just happened to be here when the coup happened. I was planning to go back, but now I don’t think I can ever…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I see, so you came here for a visit?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        I came here for business reasons. I run my own company, but it’s not in human rights thing, so it’s…We want to bring as many of the people out of the country as we can. We think Taiwan is one of the best fits. Of course, we’re getting a lot of funding to save, because human rights defenders do have channels for funding.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        The problem is visas. When I heard about you, I thought, “Well, there’s someone who cares a lot about social impact and might be able to help our cause.” Is there anything…?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        You’re saying there’s a list of people, because we don’t have a refugee act here. You would be going nowhere without a local sponsor for their visa. While, of course, we have, for example, the Gold Card, but it takes time.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        They wouldn’t…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        They wouldn’t?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        I don’t know.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Our 
                        <a href="https://goldcard.nat.gov.tw/en/">
                            Gold Card
                        </a>
                         is available to anyone who has the potential to contribute to science and technology.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Oh, OK, that would be great.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s how many people who just discovered 
                        <a href="https://taiwangoldcard.com/">
                            TaiwanGoldCard.com
                        </a>
                         can get their Gold Card, specifically the Ministry of Science and Technology one. Because you’ve done a AI system, then you have the potential to contribute to science and technology in Taiwan.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Yes, we do.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s not like you have to earn a high percentage in salary or anything like that. Long as you have the potential to contribute, then you are eligible. You can get a Gold Card from overseas. Once you have that ID, it’s as good as a residential certificate. Then you can stay here.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        This would be a lot of people though.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Sure. We need to see these are actually the people that work on the project and things like that.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Of course. What would you recommend I do for the next steps?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Check out TaiwanGoldCard.com, which is not a government website. It’s done by the people who have get Gold Card themselves. There’s a active community here, and they can probably help you of getting the right messages across, because they can share how exactly they got a Gold Card.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        If we needed this to move fast, is that possible?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        When you say a lot of people, how many are you talking about in the team?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Right now, let’s say, about 35 people have passports. Our entire company is almost a hundred people, but I don’t know if we’d be able to bring over that many.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I understand the situation. On average, in normal times, it’s 30 days is the usual processing time for a Taiwan Gold Card, but I can’t promise that it could be fast tracked.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Of course. You recommend the Gold Card is the next step?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s one possible step.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Of course. Like I said, we work with human rights defenders all over the world.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I understand.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        The company itself will..
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        I presume that, since you’ve worked with Twitter and Facebook, they’ll be willing to attest to these people’s mission?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        I’m sure they would. They’re willing to even sponsor money. They’ve donated in the past.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        That’s awesome. In that case, our Ministry of Science and Technology would be the ministry to talk to. There’s contact numbers and all that on the website.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Minister of Science and Technology.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Minister Tang, thank you so much. Thank you for your time. I really appreciate it.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Glad to help.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        I’m sorry, to intrude on your…
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        It’s fine. Please give your email to ST and we’ll work out the privacy-preserving part of our transcript to be published.
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Benjamin Finn">
                    <p>
                        Absolutely, of course. If it could be everything except maybe the name of the company?
                    </p>
                </speech>
                <speech by="#Audrey Tang">
                    <p>
                        Of course.
                    </p>
                </speech>
            </debateSection>
        </debateBody>
    </debate>
</akomaNtoso>